<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>9.0.x on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/9.0.x/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 9.0.x on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/9.0.x/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0 RC1 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-rc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-rc1/</guid>
      <description>The first Release Candidate of PrestaShop 9.0 is now available for testing. This is a significant milestone in the development cycle, and we encourage all users to test it thoroughly.
PrestaShop 9.0 Release Candidate 1 This version marks the final stage before the stable release. It includes all planned features, improvements, and changes introduced since the alpha and beta phases — including the new Hummingbird theme, Admin API, PHP 8.4 and Symfony 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0 beta is now available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The first beta version of PrestaShop 9.0 is now available for testing. This version includes many new features and improvements, a new Hummingbird theme, a new Admin API, PHP 8.4 and Symfony 6.4 support, many bug fixes, and a significant codebase cleanup. Read on to learn more about the new features and improvements.
PrestaShop 9.0 beta 1 In June, when we released the alpha 1 version, we also published the first overview of new features and improvements that PrestaShop 9 will bring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9 minimum PHP version will be PHP8.1</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-9-min-php-version-will-be-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-9-min-php-version-will-be-81/</guid>
      <description>The develop branch contains the source code that will give birth to PrestaShop 9. This is the future of PrestaShop: it will be released either at the end of the year 2023 or at the beginning of the year 2024 and must carry on the ambition of the project for 2024. This major version must also embrace the change in the PHP ecosystem, and consequently, it must drop the support of obsolete PHP versions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
