<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>quentinau on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/quentinau/</link>
    <description>Recent content in quentinau on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 09:10:11 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/quentinau/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop &#43; Azure: meet the team behind it all!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/PrestaShop-Azure-Technical-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/PrestaShop-Azure-Technical-event/</guid>
      <description>Our core team worked closely in the past few months with the Microsoft Azure Team to build 4 ready-to-use PrestaShop cloud hosting plans. You’re invited to discover an exclusive preview of it in Paris next week!
From standalone virtual machines to multi-VMs solutions, these 4 offers have been built to help you be more adaptable and scalable. They include powerful tools and services, such as high availability, SQL clusters and load balancers with auto-scaling web servers just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 alpha 3 now!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-alpha-3-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 02:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-alpha-3-is-here/</guid>
      <description>Here it is. After two internal alpha versions, we’re happy to present to you this public alpha release of PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 &amp;ndash; the first in a series of public alpha/beta/RC versions that we intend to release over several weeks, in order to gather feedback and make sure that the final and stable version is the best it can be!
Here is your chance to dive into what’s coming in 1.7:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the team building PrestaShop 1.7</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/meet-prestashop-team-prestashop-1-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/meet-prestashop-team-prestashop-1-7/</guid>
      <description>These days, the product &amp;amp; dev open-space is quiet but the minds are working like crazy! We’re starting 2016 by giving a huge push on PrestaShop 1.7 and as you’ve read here, that includes a lot of important projects.
We wanted to sum up all this so you can have in one place, an introduction to what’s coming in version 1.7. So, here is a series of videos with the men &amp;amp; women building PrestaShop everyday!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
