<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>forge on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/forge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in forge on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/forge/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Native modules and smart menu</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/native-modules-and-smart-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/native-modules-and-smart-menu/</guid>
      <description>As an open source project, PrestaShop is continuously being enriched by the company teams, external contributors, developers, etc. Thanks to all the community, it keeps growing in the right direction. The PrestaShop Team is proud and honored to read everybody&amp;rsquo;s feedback, ideas, translations and pull requests, it helps improving the PrestaShop project and making it better for everyone!
It is the strength of this community that renders each version of the software more powerful, with new features and contributions added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are moving Issues to GitHub</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/moving-issues-to-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 11:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/moving-issues-to-github/</guid>
      <description>Next week, we will enable issues on PrestaShop project’s GitHub repository. This is going to be the new way to report bugs and to open feature requests. This way, the roadmap, issues, pull requests and source code will all be in the same platform.
Introducing issues There will be two templates for creating issues: one for bug reports, and one for feature requests. Of course, please search if your issue has already been reported, before opening a new one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A year into 1.6 maintenance: the way forward</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/a-year-into-1-6-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/a-year-into-1-6-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>A year ago, we released PrestaShop 1.7.0.0, and put version 1.6 in maintenance mode. The plan is to maintain it for two years, with regular patch releases. Approaching the one-year mark, time for a review!
So, first things first: we are of course as committed as ever to support version 1.6 until October 2018. As you know, we are keeping our promise: A dedicated team of developers has been assigned to process 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create the best bug reports</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/misc/how-to-create-bug-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/misc/how-to-create-bug-report/</guid>
      <description>Every morning, the Product and QA team gather around a big screen, and review the new Forge tickets that were created since the day before. At the end of the meeting, all new tickets must be asserted, and if need be, placed into the hand of a team member.
Reviewing Forge ticket can be very brain-consuming: sometimes, report incompleteness can make for a need to ask for more info, thus slowing down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look back on the PrestaShop project in 2016</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-project-github-forge-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-project-github-forge-2016/</guid>
      <description>Following up on both last Friday&amp;rsquo;s HNY post and last Monday&amp;rsquo;s lookback on the translation project, here&amp;rsquo;s an infographic presenting a few stats on the PrestaShop project, from GitHub and the Forge!
This visual look back on the PrestaShop GitHub project and the 1.7 Project on our Forge bugtracker is a way to present the contribution from the community to the improvement of this e-commerce solution. In comparison to the HNY numbers, we added a couple of Forge tidbits.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
