<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SamuelPires on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/SamuelPires/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SamuelPires on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 16:30:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/SamuelPires/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A new place to contribute to the PrestaShop project and share your feedback on the next features</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/productboard-portal-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/productboard-portal-launch/</guid>
      <description>As announced here, the Core product team recently adopted a new working tool to gather feedback and prioritize features: Productboard. No more teasing, it is now time to have a look at how it will look and how we will all be able to handle it!
Productboard makes two things possible for the team:
On the one hand, having a dedicated internal interface to centralize all feedback, group them into topics, define features, and prioritize them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product development at PrestaShop</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/product-features-methodology-at-prestashop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/product-features-methodology-at-prestashop/</guid>
      <description>In March 2020, the Core product team at PrestaShop, in charge of building and prioritizing new features, decided to work with a new tool: Productboard.
The team thought it was the right occasion to talk more about the product development at PrestaShop, the steps, the roles and responsibilities and what happens behind the scenes before a new feature is added to PrestaShop.
PrestaShop’s product development cycle Core product team In the PrestaShop company, a cross-functional team is dedicated to maintaining the PrestaShop open source project: the Core team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
