<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>localization on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/localization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in localization on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 09:10:11 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/localization/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An update on the 1.7 RTL project</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/PrestaShop-RTL-project-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/PrestaShop-RTL-project-update/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago we announced the launch of a project to better adapt PrestaShop to right-to-left (RTL) languages. We already have a small community overviewing what is going on (thank you!). To make sure everybody shares the same level of information, here is where we stand so far.
Choosing a method: RTL script We had to figure out which method to use to adapt PrestaShop to RTL languages. Here are the many methods that have been reviewed, and why we’ve chosen to go for a script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making PrestaShop RTL-compliant together with you</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/PrestaShop-RTL-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/PrestaShop-RTL-project/</guid>
      <description>As an editor of a free software translated in many languages, our wish has always been that merchants from anywhere around the world could be able to sell easily thanks to PrestaShop.
This strong focus on internationalization implies more than “just” having the software translated. It also means supporting more formats and behaviours. As a first step towards a full internationalization, we’d like to make sure that PrestaShop 1.7 version is compliant with right-to-left languages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
