<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
  <language>en-us</language>
      <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>PrestaShop 9.1 Beta is open for feedback!</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/prestashop-9-1-beta1/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/prestashop-9-1-beta1/</guid>
          <description>PrestaShop 9.1 Beta is here, and it includes several major improvements that you can already start exploring and sharing feedback on. Your input is valuable for the final release of PrestaShop 9.1.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Improved Discounts System in PrestaShop 9.1</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/improved-discounts-system/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/improved-discounts-system/</guid>
          <description>Discounts are a pivotal element in ecommerce, driving sales and customer loyalty. As shops grow, the complexity of managing these promotions increases, often highlighting limitations in flexibility and performance. Recognizing these challenges, we embarked on a mission to revamp the discounts system in PrestaShop, aiming for a solution that is both powerful and easy to use.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Introducing Shipments in PrestaShop: finally solving the Multicarrier problem</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/introducing-shipments/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/introducing-shipments/</guid>
          <description>We are introducing a fundamental paradigm shift in PrestaShop’s core: moving the order management center of gravity from the Carrier to the Shipment.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference 2025 - Filmed Morning Sessions and Q&amp;A Now Available</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/prestashop-developer-conference-2025-keynote-sessions/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/prestashop-developer-conference-2025-keynote-sessions/</guid>
          <description>The PrestaShop Developer Conference happened a few weeks ago, and this year’s edition brought together our vibrant community for a day packed with technical insights, product announcements, and open discussions about the future of PrestaShop.
Over the coming weeks, we’ll be publishing a series of blog posts, similar to this one, diving into the event’s sessions, giving you insights and takeaways. Each post will spotlight different talks and themes from the conference.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>PrestaShop 2025: Year in Review</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-year-in-review-2025/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-year-in-review-2025/</guid>
          <description>As 2025 comes to a close, it’s time to reflect on an incredible year for the PrestaShop project. From the highly anticipated release of PrestaShop 9 to the vibrant gatherings at FOP Days and the Developer Conference, this year has been defined by innovation, collaboration, and the unwavering dedication of our community.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>From Good Intentions to Measurable Impact: PrestaShop&#39;s Call for Contributions at Open Source Experience</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-open-source-experience/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-open-source-experience/</guid>
          <description>This month of December, Paule Morizot and Fabien Moreau of PrestaShop spoke at Open Source Experience about the project’s Call for Contributions. What a great place to give an update on this topic and to show an experienced crowd what we are currently doing at PrestaShop.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>PrestaShop 9.0.2-2.1: what happened and why the version looks different</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-2-2-1-patch-version/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-2-2-1-patch-version/</guid>
          <description>Some of you hit an unexpected issue when installing PrestaShop 9.0.2 from prestashop.com, and some also noticed a slightly unusual version number: 9.0.2-2.1, which has been used since the start of PrestaShop 9 but hadn’t been explicitly explained until now.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>PrestaShop 9.1 is in feature freeze</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-1-feature-freeze/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-1-feature-freeze/</guid>
          <description>As of December 12th, 2025, PrestaShop version 9.1 has entered the feature freeze phase. Learn more about the feature freeze, the next steps, and what’s coming in PrestaShop 9.1.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>PrestaShop 9.0.2 is available</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-2-maintenance-release/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
          <description>PrestaShop 9.0.2 is now available! This second patch version represents yet another step in making PrestaShop 9 more reliable. It focuses on fixing some reported issues to provide a more stable and seamless experience for merchants and developers.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>A Fresh Start for PrestaShop Issues: Bringing Clarity to Chaos</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/reorganization-of-prestashop-issue-management/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/reorganization-of-prestashop-issue-management/</guid>
          <description>2,300 issues. One number. One challenge. Imagine searching for a needle in a haystack of 2,300 straws. That’s exactly what PrestaShop contributors experience today when trying to check if their bug has already been reported. It’s also the daily challenge for our QA teams navigating this ocean of issues, some dating back to 2018.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference 2025 - Event Recap</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-developer-conference-2025-event-recap/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-developer-conference-2025-event-recap/</guid>
          <description>On November 19, 2025, the PrestaShop developer community convened in Paris, and online via a global livestream, for the third PrestaShop Developer Conference. The program featured hands-on sessions, live demonstrations, and expert talks, alongside a major announcement. Attendees deepened their understanding of the PrestaShop ecosystem, gained project information, and explored practical advancements they can apply in their daily work.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Hummingbird v2.0.0 Beta Is Available</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/hummingbird-v2-beta/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/hummingbird-v2-beta/</guid>
          <description>We are thrilled to announce the release of Hummingbird v2.0.0 Beta. This milestone is the result of a monumental effort, representing more than 320 commits, 500 file changes, 50,000 additions, and 30,000 deletions. The goal is to deliver a developer-first, lightweight, and modular theme that establishes a new standard for the PrestaShop ecosystem.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Sunsetting the PrestaShop cron service</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/sunsetting-the-prestashop-cron-service/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/sunsetting-the-prestashop-cron-service/</guid>
          <description>The PrestaShop cron service will be officially shut down in December 2025, marking the end of a legacy component that once helped stores without full server access automate scheduled tasks.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Call for contributions: Admin API - great start!</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-admin-api-progress/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-admin-api-progress/</guid>
          <description>Two months ago, we launched our second Call for Contributions initiative, this time focusing on the Admin API. We’re excited to share the progress that’s been made!</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - October 2025</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-10-01-2025-10-31/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-10-01-2025-10-31/</guid>
          <description>October has been an exceptional month for the PrestaShop project! We released the first maintenance version of PrestaShop 9, opened registration for our biggest community event of the year, and watched the Admin API contribution initiative gain incredible momentum. Let’s dive into what made this month so special.</description>
        </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
