<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kpodemski on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/kpodemski/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kpodemski on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/kpodemski/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - October 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-10-01-2025-10-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-10-01-2025-10-31/</guid>
      <description>October has been an exceptional month for the PrestaShop project! We released the first maintenance version of PrestaShop 9, opened registration for our biggest community event of the year, and watched the Admin API contribution initiative gain incredible momentum. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into what made this month so special.
October was truly a milestone month for PrestaShop. The energy and enthusiasm from both PrestaShop SA and our community contributors have been remarkable, resulting in impressive progress across multiple fronts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - September 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-09-01-2025-09-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-09-01-2025-09-30/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the September edition of the Core Monthly! This month was buzzing with activity around PrestaShop 9, with the team working on its first patch release and the community stepping up to expand the new Admin API. We also saw some fantastic new tools and improvements, all thanks to dedicated contributors.
PrestaShop 9: patch in progress and Admin API Call for Contributions September has been a busy month for the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - August 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-08-01-2025-08-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-08-01-2025-08-31/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the August edition of Core Monthly. This month brought an important security patch for 8.2, a new community feature in the back office, and a fresh call for contributions to expand the Admin API in PrestaShop 9.
Security: PrestaShop 8.2.3 A security-driven patch release for PrestaShop 8.2 is out. Version 8.2.3 fixes an email enumeration vulnerability on the back office password reset page. While PrestaShop 9 is not affected, we strongly recommend updating if you are on the 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the PrestaShop Wall of Fame</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/meet-prestashop-wall-of-fame/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/meet-prestashop-wall-of-fame/</guid>
      <description>From its very first release, PrestaShop has been built and improved thanks to the dedication of its open source community. Today, we&amp;rsquo;re introducing a new way to celebrate that dedication - directly in your back office.
The Wall of Fame is a new tab in the back office available through the ps_distributionapiclient (version 1.2.0) module that showcases the top companies and individuals contributing to PrestaShop. Merchants can now see, right where they manage their store, the vibrant community making the software better every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for contributions: Admin API</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-admin-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-admin-api/</guid>
      <description>After the success of our first Call for Contributions focused on hooks, it&amp;rsquo;s time to launch a new round. This time, we&amp;rsquo;re inviting the community to contribute to one of the most significant changes in PrestaShop 9: the new Admin API.
Why the Admin API? During FoP Days, we asked attendees to vote on future contribution topics. Three stood out: Hooks, Admin API, and Web Accessibility (EAA). We started with Hooks, work on the EAA subject will be part of Hummingbird 2, led by PrestaShop S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - July 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-07-01-2025-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-07-01-2025-07-31/</guid>
      <description>We are back with the July edition of the PrestaShop Core Monthly! 🌞
Dear community,
July has been an exciting month for the PrestaShop project, filled with significant releases, upcoming feature announcements, and continued community engagement. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into what made this summer month particularly productive for our project.
PrestaShop 8.2.2 maintenance release We released PrestaShop 8.2.2 on July 28th, bringing a comprehensive set of bug fixes and improvements to the 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - July 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-july-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-july-2025/</guid>
      <description>On July 30th, 2025, we hosted another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project, highlighting the announcement of the upcoming One Page Checkout (OPC) feature in PrestaShop 9.1. We also covered the current state of the project, recent releases, and ongoing contribution initiatives, including the Admin API.
PrestaShop Live Update - July 2025 The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows: 00:00 Beginning of the session: introduction 02:21 Project news: PrestaShop 9.0 is available 10:23 Project news: PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update July 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-july-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-july-2025/</guid>
      <description>Yet another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2025 will be hosted on Wednesday, July 30th, 2025, at 4 PM (Paris time) on YouTube!
Join us for the upcoming Live Update, where we will share exciting news about the PrestaShop Project!
We will provide a summary of the Call for Contributions: Hooks Initiative, highlighting the community&amp;rsquo;s efforts and achievements.
But that&amp;rsquo;s not all! One of the highlights of this session will be an exclusive presentation on the highly anticipated One Page Checkout feature, coming in PrestaShop 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - June 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-06-01-2025-06-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-06-01-2025-06-30/</guid>
      <description>We are back with yet another edition of the PrestaShop Core Monthly, your monthly digest of the PrestaShop codebase&amp;rsquo;s latest changes and news from the PrestaShop project.
PrestaShop 9.0.0 is out! 🎉 June marks the completion of one month since the PrestaShop 9.0.0 release, which is now available for download!
This release is a major milestone for the PrestaShop project, as it brings a lot of new features and improvements. We hope you will enjoy it as much as we do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for contributions: hooks - initiative summary</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-hooks-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-hooks-summary/</guid>
      <description>During this year’s FoP Days, we launched a new community initiative focused on improving a specific part of the PrestaShop project: hooks. Rather than casting a wide net, we deliberately concentrated on a single topic. The goal was to make it easier and faster for contributors to submit changes, and for project members to validate them.
Why hooks? Hooks are essential for extending and customizing PrestaShop without overriding core files. They empower developers to build features in a clean, future-proof way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - April 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-april-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-april-2025/</guid>
      <description>On April 23rd, 2025, we hosted another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project. This time we focused on two subjects, the Update Assistant release and the Targeted Contributions initiative.
PrestaShop Live Update - April 2025 In this session, I presented the latest news about the PrestaShop Project, including the Targeted Contributions initiative. This initiative is a great opportunity for contributors to work on projects that matter to them and the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update April 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-april-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-april-2025/</guid>
      <description>The upcoming PrestaShop Project Live Update will take place on Wednesday, April 23rd, 2025 at 4pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
This edition will focus on the latest developments in PrestaShop 8.2.2 and PrestaShop 9. We’ll discuss recent improvements, new features, and what these changes mean for the community and merchants.
A special highlight of this Live Update: we will be joined by PrestaShop SA Core Extensions team members responsible for the Update Assistant module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - March 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-03-01-2025-03-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-03-01-2025-03-31/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s new in the project? We&amp;rsquo;re ending the quarter strong! Project members with the help of the community have been working hard to prepare the next major release of PrestaShop. Release of the completely new version of the Auto Upgrade Update Assistant module, and that&amp;rsquo;s only a glimpse of the work done in March. Read on to learn more about the latest changes in the PrestaShop project.
Stay up to date with the latest developments in the PrestaShop project by reading the Core Monthly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - March 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-march-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-march-2025/</guid>
      <description>On March 5th, 2025, we hosted another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project where we shared more information about PrestaShop 9 Beta 1. We also took a sneak peek at what&amp;rsquo;s coming to PrestaShop 9.1 thanks to a special guest from PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s product team.
PrestaShop Live Update - March 2025 In this session, we focused on PrestaShop 9 Beta 1, stressing the need for developers to prepare for potential breaking changes and major updates within the PrestaShop ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update March 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-march-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-march-2025/</guid>
      <description>The second Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2025 will be hosted on Wednesday, March 5th, 2025 at 4pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
Join us for the upcoming Live Update where we will provide an in-depth walkthrough of the changes under the hood introduced in PrestaShop 9 Beta 1. This session will be particularly valuable for those looking to adapt their PrestaShop solutions or solutions integrating with PrestaShop to the new version.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
