<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kpodemski on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/kpodemski/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kpodemski on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/kpodemski/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - November</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-11-01-2023-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-11-01-2023-11-30/</guid>
      <description>November was marked by the first PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris.
PrestaShop Developer Conference On November 30th, PrestaShop organized its first developer conference in Paris. The event was a great success, with around 150 attendees, over 25 speakers, and almost 20 talks. It was a great opportunity to discuss best practices for working with PrestaShop software, exchange experiences between developers and discuss PrestaShop development.
The great turnout proved to everyone we need more events of that type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - October</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-10-01-2023-10-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-10-01-2023-10-31/</guid>
      <description>In this Core Monthly, check out what we&amp;rsquo;ve been up to in October with PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s core and modules. Also, get a sneak peek at the agenda and speakers for the upcoming PrestaShop Developer Conference.
PrestaShop Developer Conference A few weeks ago we closed the call for papers for the conference, and it&amp;rsquo;s time to share with you the agenda as well as speakers for the event. We received a lot of great submissions, and we&amp;rsquo;re excited to share the agenda with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - October 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-9-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-9-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the ninth time this year and streamed live on October 11th, 2023.
PrestaShop Live Update - October 2023 It was a special Live Update where we said goodbye to the project leader, Pablo Borowicz, who, after over six years, is leaving the PrestaShop company. On behalf of everyone in the project, I would like to thank him for all the work he has done for the project and wish him all the best in his future endeavors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing October PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-9-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-9-2023/</guid>
      <description>The ninth Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, October 11th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
We will go over the latest project updates, take a look at recent changes in the software, changes made in the developer documentation and at the end of the session we will make a very special announcement.
Join us on YouTube! Remember that at the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - September</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-09-01-2023-09-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-09-01-2023-09-30/</guid>
      <description>In this article, delve into September&amp;rsquo;s updates and news from the project. As well as Hacktoberfest 2023&amp;rsquo;s kick off, offering a month-long celebration of open-source contributions. Keep reading for more information.
PrestaShop 8.1.2 In September, the project saw the release of PrestaShop 8.1.2. This second patch for the 8.1 series brings two security fixes and addresses over 30 bugs. The release also includes minor enhancements, particularly to the new product page and the multi-format image generation system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - September 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-8-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-8-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the eighth time this year and streamed live on September 13th, 2023.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows: 00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 02:30 Project news: PrestaShop Developer Conference 04:28 Project news: PrestaShop 8.1.1, 8.0.5 and 1.7.8.10 08:56 Demo: changes in the developer documentation by @thomasnares 43:00 Q&amp;amp;A session You can use the timestamps to jump directly to the parts you want to watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - August</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-08-01-2023-08-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-08-01-2023-08-31/</guid>
      <description>A little later than usual, discover the latest happenings in the PrestaShop Project for August 2023. We had a productive month, successfully merging more than 240 pull requests and releasing PrestaShop 8.1.1 and some security patches. Read on to find out more!
PrestaShop 8.1.1, 8.0.5, 1.7.8.10 The first patch for PrestaShop 8.1 and security patches for 8.0.5 and 1.7.8.10 are all available to download. You can read the details about these versions in the release notes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing September PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-8-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-8-2023/</guid>
      <description>The eighth Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, September 13th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
We will go over the latest project updates, take a look at recent changes in the software, changes made in the developer documentation, and more!
Remember that at the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions during the presentation or beforehand. If you have questions related to the open source project, feel free to let us know in advance using this form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - July 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-07-01-2023-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-07-01-2023-07-31/</guid>
      <description>Read about what has been going on in the PrestaShop Project in July 2023. It was a good month with over 340 merged pull requests! 🎉
Even during the Summer we see a lot of great progress in the PrestaShop Project. In July, we merged over 340 pull requests.
We welcomed three new committers:
Guyomar Alexis (@ga-devfront) Clément Désiles (@jokesterfr) Morgan Pichat (@M0rgan01) You can see all current project members on the updated People and Roles page on the project&amp;rsquo;s website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - July 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-7-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-7-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the seventh time this year and streamed live on July 19th, 2023.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows: 00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 01:51 Project news: PrestaShop Developer Conference 04:37 Project news: PrestaShop 8.1 14:39 Demo: enable WebP or Avif in PrestaShop 8.1 20:21 Demo: enable developer mode with cookie in PrestaShop 9.0 24:14 Demo: RectorPHP in PrestaShop 9.0 29:06 Demo: changes in the developer documentation 38:52 Q&amp;amp;A session You can use the timestamps to jump directly to the parts you want to watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing July PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-7-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-7-2023/</guid>
      <description>The seventh Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, July 19th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
We will go over the latest project updates, take a look at recent changes in the software, changes made in the developer documentation, and more!
Remember that at the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions during the presentation or beforehand. If you have questions related to the open source project, feel free to let us know in advance using this form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - June</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-06-01-2023-06-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-06-01-2023-06-30/</guid>
      <description>The new PrestaShop 8.1, ongoing work on PrestaShop 9.0, new content in the developer documentation and more! Read about all this news in the Core Monthly report for June.
PrestaShop 8.1 is out! You read that right! The new PrestaShop 8.1 is out! 🎉 Congratulations to the whole PrestaShop project team, contributors and community members who made this release possible. Version 8.1 is a minor upgrade, with major improvements. The all-new product management page, full support for WebP and Avif and lots of other improvements are waiting for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - June 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-6-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-6-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the sixth time this year and streamed live on June 21st, 2023.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows: 00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 03:00 Project news: PrestaShop Developer Conference 04:33 Project news: PrestaShop 8.1 06:36 Demo: issue management in the PrestaShop project by @hibatallahAouadni 22:22 Demo: PrestaShop 9.0 roadmap by @fabienvallon 32:20 Demo: breaking changes &amp;amp; improvements in PrestaShop 9.0 by @boherm 47:14 Q&amp;amp;A session You can use the timestamps to jump directly to the parts you want to watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing June PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-6-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-6-2023/</guid>
      <description>The sixth Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, June 21st, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
We will go over the latest project updates, take a look at recent changes made in the developer documentation, and present two demos:
Issue management in the PrestaShop Project by @hibatallahAouadni PrestaShop 9.0 roadmap by @fabienvallon Remember that at the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - May 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-05-01-2023-05-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-05-01-2023-05-31/</guid>
      <description>In May, we released PrestaShop 8.1 RC1, shared some exciting news about PrestaShop 9, and continued improving the core and the modules. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at recent developments in the project in May.
Live Update The last Live Update took place on May 17th. You can read all the details in the summary. We didn&amp;rsquo;t share the date of the next Live Update back then, but we agreed now that we will host the next session on June 21st.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
