<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kpodemski on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/kpodemski/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kpodemski on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/kpodemski/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - July 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-07-01-2025-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-07-01-2025-07-31/</guid>
      <description>We are back with the July edition of the PrestaShop Core Monthly! 🌞
Dear community,
July has been an exciting month for the PrestaShop project, filled with significant releases, upcoming feature announcements, and continued community engagement. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into what made this summer month particularly productive for our project.
PrestaShop 8.2.2 maintenance release We released PrestaShop 8.2.2 on July 28th, bringing a comprehensive set of bug fixes and improvements to the 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - July 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-july-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-july-2025/</guid>
      <description>On July 30th, 2025, we hosted another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project, highlighting the announcement of the upcoming One Page Checkout (OPC) feature in PrestaShop 9.1. We also covered the current state of the project, recent releases, and ongoing contribution initiatives, including the Admin API.
PrestaShop Live Update - July 2025 The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows: 00:00 Beginning of the session: introduction 02:21 Project news: PrestaShop 9.0 is available 10:23 Project news: PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update July 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-july-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-july-2025/</guid>
      <description>Yet another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2025 will be hosted on Wednesday, July 30th, 2025, at 4 PM (Paris time) on YouTube!
Join us for the upcoming Live Update, where we will share exciting news about the PrestaShop Project!
We will provide a summary of the Call for Contributions: Hooks Initiative, highlighting the community&amp;rsquo;s efforts and achievements.
But that&amp;rsquo;s not all! One of the highlights of this session will be an exclusive presentation on the highly anticipated One Page Checkout feature, coming in PrestaShop 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - June 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-06-01-2025-06-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-06-01-2025-06-30/</guid>
      <description>We are back with yet another edition of the PrestaShop Core Monthly, your monthly digest of the PrestaShop codebase&amp;rsquo;s latest changes and news from the PrestaShop project.
PrestaShop 9.0.0 is out! 🎉 June marks the completion of one month since the PrestaShop 9.0.0 release, which is now available for download!
This release is a major milestone for the PrestaShop project, as it brings a lot of new features and improvements. We hope you will enjoy it as much as we do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for contributions: hooks - initiative summary</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-hooks-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-hooks-summary/</guid>
      <description>During this year’s FoP Days, we launched a new community initiative focused on improving a specific part of the PrestaShop project: hooks. Rather than casting a wide net, we deliberately concentrated on a single topic. The goal was to make it easier and faster for contributors to submit changes, and for project members to validate them.
Why hooks? Hooks are essential for extending and customizing PrestaShop without overriding core files. They empower developers to build features in a clean, future-proof way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - April 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-april-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-april-2025/</guid>
      <description>On April 23rd, 2025, we hosted another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project. This time we focused on two subjects, the Update Assistant release and the Targeted Contributions initiative.
PrestaShop Live Update - April 2025 In this session, I presented the latest news about the PrestaShop Project, including the Targeted Contributions initiative. This initiative is a great opportunity for contributors to work on projects that matter to them and the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update April 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-april-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-april-2025/</guid>
      <description>The upcoming PrestaShop Project Live Update will take place on Wednesday, April 23rd, 2025 at 4pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
This edition will focus on the latest developments in PrestaShop 8.2.2 and PrestaShop 9. We’ll discuss recent improvements, new features, and what these changes mean for the community and merchants.
A special highlight of this Live Update: we will be joined by PrestaShop SA Core Extensions team members responsible for the Update Assistant module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - March 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-03-01-2025-03-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-03-01-2025-03-31/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s new in the project? We&amp;rsquo;re ending the quarter strong! Project members with the help of the community have been working hard to prepare the next major release of PrestaShop. Release of the completely new version of the Auto Upgrade Update Assistant module, and that&amp;rsquo;s only a glimpse of the work done in March. Read on to learn more about the latest changes in the PrestaShop project.
Stay up to date with the latest developments in the PrestaShop project by reading the Core Monthly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - March 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-march-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-march-2025/</guid>
      <description>On March 5th, 2025, we hosted another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project where we shared more information about PrestaShop 9 Beta 1. We also took a sneak peek at what&amp;rsquo;s coming to PrestaShop 9.1 thanks to a special guest from PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s product team.
PrestaShop Live Update - March 2025 In this session, we focused on PrestaShop 9 Beta 1, stressing the need for developers to prepare for potential breaking changes and major updates within the PrestaShop ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update March 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-march-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-march-2025/</guid>
      <description>The second Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2025 will be hosted on Wednesday, March 5th, 2025 at 4pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
Join us for the upcoming Live Update where we will provide an in-depth walkthrough of the changes under the hood introduced in PrestaShop 9 Beta 1. This session will be particularly valuable for those looking to adapt their PrestaShop solutions or solutions integrating with PrestaShop to the new version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - January</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-01-01-2025-01-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-01-01-2025-01-31/</guid>
      <description>We are back with the first Core Monthly of 2025! 🎉 Discover the latest updates in the PrestaShop project, including new releases, project highlights, community contributions, and more.
Want to stay up to date with the latest developments in the PrestaShop project? Core Monthly is your go-to source for the most important news, updates, and changes in the project. In this edition, we will show you what happened in January 2025.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - January 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-january-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-january-2025/</guid>
      <description>On January 29th, 2025, we hosted another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project with the latest news, announcements, and had the pleasure to host Software Components Squad members from PrestaShop SA.
PrestaShop Live Update - January 2025 During this Live Update, you could learn about the upcoming PrestaShop 9 Beta 1 status, and the patch for PrestaShop 8.2. We also talked about the new experiment called &amp;ldquo;Targeted Contributions&amp;rdquo;, which is our idea on how to streamline the process of contributing to the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update January 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-january-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-january-2025/</guid>
      <description>The first Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2025 will be hosted on Wednesday, January 29th, 2025 at 4pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
Join us for the upcoming Live Update where we will share the latest advancements in the PrestaShop Project. This session is a fantastic opportunity to connect with the Software Components Squad from PrestaShop SA. Learn about their ongoing work and the exciting improvements planned for the multicarrier feature in PrestaShop!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - November 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-november-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-november-2024/</guid>
      <description>On November 27th, 2024, we held another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project with a special focus on the Upgrade Assistant.
PrestaShop Live Update - November 2024 During this Live Update, members of the Seamless Upgrade and Extensibility team from PrestaShop SA presented the upcoming seventh version of the autoupgrade module, which will now be named Upgrade Assistant module. This presentation was originally showcased at the PrestaShop Developer Conference 2024, and we were happy to bring it to you during this Live Update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update November 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-november-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-november-2024/</guid>
      <description>The next Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2024 will happen on Wednesday, November 27th, 2024 at 4pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
We promised to bring you presentations from the PrestaShop Developer Conference 2024, and we are keeping our word!
One of the highlights of this upcoming Live Update will be the presentation titled &amp;ldquo;Long live the update assistant: strengthening trust in your shop&amp;rsquo;s updates&amp;rdquo; by members of the Seamless Upgrade &amp;amp; Extensibility team from PrestaShop SA.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
