<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>8.1.x on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/8.1.x/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 8.1.x on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/8.1.x/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.6 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-6-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-6-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A new patch version for PrestaShop 8.1 is now available. This maintenance release fixes 2 security issues.
The security patch for version 8.1 of PrestaShop is now available. It is recommended that you upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to create a backup before. You can upgrade to the latest version using the 1-Click Upgrade module. There are no database changes in this release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.5 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-5-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-5-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>Another patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available. This release contains interesting improvements as well as a number of bug fixes. In this article, we’ll lean into them because there’s plenty to write about!
PrestaShop 8.1.5 is available. This release fixes some bugs but also brings a lot of improvements.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to backup before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.4 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-4-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-4-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been decided to release a security patch for version 8.1 of PrestaShop.
The security patch for version 8.1 of PrestaShop is now available. This is the first release where it&amp;rsquo;s been decided to separate the security fixes from other bug fixes and improvements, allowing for a quick release of the security patch.
It is recommended that you upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to create a backup before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.3 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-3-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-3-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>We are entering the new year with the release of PrestaShop 8.1.3. The latest update for PrestaShop 8.1 is now available. This version brings two security updates, addresses close to 30 known issues, and introduces various enhancements.
To welcome the new year well, we are releasing a new version of PrestaShop! Version 8.1.3 is available with a slight delay, but this is due to the time it took to complete work on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The second patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available! This release contains 2 security fixes, over 30 bugs have been fixed and some minor improvements have been integrated.
Version 8.1.2 fixes a few security issues found by security researchers and solves a great number of bugs reported by the community and project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance team. It also includes some minor improvements, especially for the new product page and new multi-format image generation system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.1 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available. This release contains a few security fixes, so we highly recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
Version 8.1.1 fixes a few security issues found by security researchers and solves a great number of bugs reported by the community and project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance team.
You can go to the release page to see a full changelog, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning a few notable bug fixes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-0-available/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to announce that PrestaShop 8.1 is officially available.
PrestaShop 8.1 is a minor upgrade with major improvements. It&amp;rsquo;s focused on making things faster and easier for you, transforming the way you use PrestaShop.
The entirely reworked product management page delivers a more efficient and user-friendly experience. This new page makes managing product combinations, prices, taxes, stock, and images quicker and easier. Multistore product management has also been drastically improved.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
