<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tristanlehot on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/tristanlehot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tristanlehot on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/tristanlehot/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UX Guidelines for modules developers</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/ux-guidelines-for-modules-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/ux-guidelines-for-modules-developers/</guid>
      <description>With more than 4000 modules available on PrestaShop Addons marketplace, the diversity of features developed by modules developers or by the PrestaShop team is growing faster every day, making PrestaShop one of the most adaptive and versatile e-commerce solution.
UX Challenge Starting from this statement, one of the challenges PrestaShop has to address is consistency: with the variety of developers and modules comes the need to harmonise the interfaces in order to give our merchants the most fluid and consistent PrestaShop experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 2018 release schedule</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/misc/2018-release-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/misc/2018-release-schedule/</guid>
      <description>Our release calendar for the next versions of PrestaShop 1.7 and 1.6.
Summary In short: we intend to release minor versions of PrestaShop 1.7 every 3 to 4 months, and patch versions for both 1.7 and 1.6 as regularly as possible in-between minor releases.
When? When? When? Here’s a handy table to guide you:
This table was updated on February 26th, 2018. Please note that all dates are estimated, not fixed, and hence subject to change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop loves its community</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-loves-its-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-loves-its-community/</guid>
      <description>And here comes the nice surprise&amp;hellip; 2018 is here, following the gregorian calendar, let us wish you a successful and happy new year again!
So thank you all for this huge year we spent together, on Crowdin or on GitHub, making PrestaShop so proud of its community. We have prepared this nice infographic to have a look at 2017, to see how PrestaShop moved forward and feel fine about it. You deserve to do so, enjoy it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look back on the PrestaShop project in 2016</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-project-github-forge-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-project-github-forge-2016/</guid>
      <description>Following up on both last Friday&amp;rsquo;s HNY post and last Monday&amp;rsquo;s lookback on the translation project, here&amp;rsquo;s an infographic presenting a few stats on the PrestaShop project, from GitHub and the Forge!
This visual look back on the PrestaShop GitHub project and the 1.7 Project on our Forge bugtracker is a way to present the contribution from the community to the improvement of this e-commerce solution. In comparison to the HNY numbers, we added a couple of Forge tidbits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look back on PrestaShop translation project in 2016</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-translation-project-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 06:09:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-translation-project-2016/</guid>
      <description>As we&amp;rsquo;re starting a new year, here is a visual look back on PrestaShop translation project and how it thrived thanks to the help of our translation community!
Thank you all for your involvement :)
This lovely design is from Tristan Lehot, Product Designer at PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
