<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>8.2 on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/8.2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 8.2 on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/8.2/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.1 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch for PrestaShop 8.2 is available. This release contains many bug fixes and improvements, including a new way to handle module filtering in the front office.
We are excited to announce the release of PrestaShop 8.2.1, a new patch that not only addresses a significant number of bugs reported by our dedicated community and Quality Assurance team but also introduces a valuable new feature. This feature allows module developers to filter the display of other modules in PrestaShop, helping them avoid the use of overrides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-2-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-2-0-available/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been decided to release a new minor version of PrestaShop 8.2. This version includes a few improvements, as well as bug fixes.
What&amp;rsquo;s new in PrestaShop 8.2? PrestaShop 8.2 is a minor version that includes a few improvements, as well as bug fixes, and it is relatively small compared to the previous minor versions. Here are some highlights.
Improvements Correctly checking overrides during module installation
PrestaShop used to check for overrides during module installation, but the process didn’t fully block installation if a conflicting override was found.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
