<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>9.1.x on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/9.1.x/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 9.1.x on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/9.1.x/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Shipments in PrestaShop: finally solving the Multicarrier problem</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/introducing-shipments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/introducing-shipments/</guid>
      <description>We are introducing a fundamental paradigm shift in PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s core: moving the order management center of gravity from the Carrier to the Shipment.
This major architectural change is already partially available for testing. Starting with PrestaShop 9.1, you can access these new features under a feature flag. This allows merchants, agencies and developers to start adapting to the new &amp;ldquo;Shipment&amp;rdquo; logic today, without disrupting existing stores.
Work in progress This feature is currently available for testing purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.1 is in feature freeze</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-1-feature-freeze/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-1-feature-freeze/</guid>
      <description>As of December 12th, 2025, PrestaShop version 9.1 has entered the feature freeze phase. Learn more about the feature freeze, the next steps, and what’s coming in PrestaShop 9.1.
PrestaShop 9.1 feature freeze is in effect As of today, PrestaShop 9.1 is in feature freeze. What is a feature freeze? Feature freeze marks a stage in development when no new features are accepted. The focus shifts to polishing what’s built and validating quality before release.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
