<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>beta on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/beta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in beta on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/beta/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 beta is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The beta version of PrestaShop 8.1 is now ready for you to test!
We’re delighted to announce that PrestaShop 8.1 has reached the beta stage. PrestaShop 8.1 is still in development, but we hope you will help us test this release so we can have the best quality release possible, available for everyone, as soon as possible!
Test PrestaShop 8.1.0 beta 1 now! Version 8.1 fixes over 30 bugs found in the previous release and introduces many improvements and new features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0 beta is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 15:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The public beta version of PrestaShop 8.0 is now ready for you to test!
The maintainers team is very happy to announce today the release of the public beta version of PrestaShop 8.0. This version includes many new features, improvements and over 130 bug fixes.
The main new features for this version include an update to Symfony 4.4, compatibility with PHP 8 and 8.1, an enhanced experimental product page, and a new security page which allows shop administrators to manage user sessions and configure their password policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.0 beta is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-1-7-8-0-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-1-7-8-0-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The first Beta version of PrestaShop 1.7.8.0 is now ready for you to test!
We are very happy to announce today the release of the beta version of 1.7.8. This version includes many features and bug fixes, we count on you to test the Beta and report any bugs you encounter.
Main new features are: the redesign of the translation system that facilitates the export and the translation of your modules and themes, a new header for multistore allowing to configure the different stores more easily and quickly, and many other improvements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 Beta 2 Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-7-0-beta2-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-7-0-beta2-release/</guid>
      <description>The second Beta version for PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 is now ready for you to test!
Over 130 Pull Requests have been merged since the first Beta of 1.7.7.0 was released about three months ago. A great number of regressions have been detected and fixed thanks to extensive testing by the community and the PrestaShop team, mainly in the new order pages. However, as new regressions keep being reported, the maintainer team has decided to issue a second Beta release before a Release Candidate is built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 Beta Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-7-0-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-7-0-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The first Beta version for PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 is now ready for you to test!
After more than one year in the making, we are really thrilled to announce that we are releasing the 1.7.7.0 beta. This version is even bigger than the previous one with 957 merged pull requests, compared to 748 for 1.7.6.0 (our previous record) – and we are still at least a month away from the final version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7 minor release lifecycle</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/ps17-minor-release-lifecycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/ps17-minor-release-lifecycle/</guid>
      <description>Watch out! This article is outdated. Head to the developer documentation if you want to read about the current process. The journey of the release of PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 has started. This moment is a nice opportunity to explain PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s minor release lifecycle.
The journey begins: Kanban and scope Each minor version is defined by a feature scope, that is, a number of GitHub issues that we put in a version Kanban (see 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.6.0 beta is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-6-0-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-6-0-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The first Beta version for PrestaShop 1.7.6.0 is now ready for you to test!
We are really happy to announce that we are close to releasing 1.7.6.0.
Over 6 months in the making, PrestaShop 1.7.6.0 will be a huge release, our biggest one yet, with over 600 merged Pull Requests at the time of writing.
As they say, an image is worth a thousand words, so here&amp;rsquo;s a graph to show how this beta compares with previous final releases in terms of number of contributions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.5.0 release candidate is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1.7.5-rc-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1.7.5-rc-release/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks after the beta, the first release candidate for PrestaShop 1.7.5.0 is now ready for you to test!
This is the last step before releasing the final 1.7.5.0. The aim of this version is to verify that all regressions found during the beta have been fixed, and that no new ones are reported by the community users. If nothing is reported by December 17, then the final version of 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.5.0 beta is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-5-0-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 10:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-5-0-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The first Beta version for PrestaShop 1.7.5.0 is now ready for you to test!
We are happy to announce that we are close to releasing 1.7.5.0. This minor version (in the SemVer meaning of the term) brings important new features and improvements to the 1.7 codebase, and we can’t wait to receive your feedback!
This Beta release is a great opportunity for you to start working with it before we release a stable version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.4.0 beta 1 is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-4-0-beta-1-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 16:40:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-4-0-beta-1-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.4 is available for download. Please read important informations about it.
Done:
All pull requests have been merged New features:
Improved back office design Works better on mobile devices (all pages are accessible on mobile now!) New menu, can be scrolled Improved header (looks the same on legacy and symfon pages) Based on Bootstrap 4 final Theme customization New pages migrated to symfony Advanced Parameters &amp;gt; Administration Advanced Parameters &amp;gt; Import Shop Parameters &amp;gt; General Shop Parameters &amp;gt; General &amp;gt; Maintenance Shop Parameters &amp;gt; Product Settings Shop Parameters &amp;gt; Customer Settings Added support for PHP 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.3.0 beta 1 is out!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-3-0-beta-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-3-0-beta-1/</guid>
      <description>The first beta version for PrestaShop 1.7.3.0 is now ready for you to test and give feedback about!
We said it earlier, many times. Now it is the right time to announce proudly that we are close to releasing 1.7.3.0. Features and improvements have found their way to the 1.7 codebase, we are thrilled to let you have a look at it and play with it before everyone else!
However, note that it is a beta version, not a release candidate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.1.0 Beta 1 is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-1-0-beta-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-1-0-beta-1/</guid>
      <description>The first Beta version for PrestaShop 1.7.1.0 is now ready for you to test!
We are happy to announce that we are close to releasing 1.7.1.0. This minor version (in the SemVer meaning of the term) brings several new features and improvements to the 1.7 codebase, and we can’t wait to receive your feedback!
Test PrestaShop 1.7.1.0 Beta 1 now! This Beta release is a great opportunity for you to start working with it before we release a stable version!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 Beta 3 is out!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-beta-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 09:00:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-beta-3/</guid>
      <description>Hot on the heels of Beta 2, here&amp;rsquo;s PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 Beta 3, ready for you to test and give feedback about!
As always during this period of testing and fixing, we need feedback from any merchant, service provider, module developer or theme designer who is reading this.
The release of this Beta 3 is another step in the current period of intensive testing and debugging by the PrestaShop developers, towards a proper RC and eventual release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 reaches Beta 2 stage</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-17-beta2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 09:00:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-17-beta2/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce that PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 is now available for testing in its 2nd Beta version. More than ever, we need YOUR feedback as a merchant, a service provider, a module developer or a theme designer.
The release of this second Beta version is another important milestone in the current period of intensive testing and debugging by the PrestaShop developers.
Test PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 Beta 2 now! PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 is still in development, which means that this new Beta release is a great opportunity for you to discover it before we release a stable version!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 Beta 1 is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-beta-1-open-for-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 00:00:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-beta-1-open-for-feedback/</guid>
      <description>The first Beta version for PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 is now ready for you to test!
We are happy to announce that the development branch of version 1.7 has reached the Beta state, and we can’t wait to receive your feedback as a merchant, a service provider, a module developer or a theme designer.
Test PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 Beta 1 now! PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 is still in development, which means that this Beta release is a great opportunity for you to start working with it before we release a stable version!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
