<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PabloBorowicz on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/PabloBorowicz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PabloBorowicz on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/PabloBorowicz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A New Organization For The Open Source Project</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/a-new-organization-for-the-open-source-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/a-new-organization-for-the-open-source-project/</guid>
      <description>Today, I want to share the new organization for decision-making that will be set up for the PrestaShop project. We believe this organization will help our community grow, get even more involved, and work together in building a better PrestaShop, faster.
Why do we need a new organization? During the last years, we have been observing a steady growth in the number of community pull requests being merged every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An update on the Symfony migration</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/introducing-horizontal-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/introducing-horizontal-migration/</guid>
      <description>In December 2015, a groundbreaking change in PrestaShop was announced: the introduction of the Symfony framework into the CMS. The goal was to gradually replace PrestaShop’s custom framework with Symfony, and switch its templating system from Smarty to Twig. This project was known as “The Symfony migration”. Looking back, we realize that referring to this project as a &amp;ldquo;migration&amp;rdquo; wasn&amp;rsquo;t really accurate at all.
Currently, migrating one page to Symfony involves several steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop beyond 1.7</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-beyond-1-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-beyond-1-7/</guid>
      <description>Five years ago, PrestaShop 1.7 was released to the world, introducing Symfony, the Classic theme and child theme features, interface improvements, and so much more. With each one of the eight minor versions that followed, 1.7 kept on growing both in features and stability. Its maturity is recognized by its success: with over 170,000 live shops detected at the time of writing, it’s the most popular PrestaShop version used in production shops on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing public demos from the maintainers team</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/first-public-oss-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/first-public-oss-demo/</guid>
      <description>Last month, the maintainers team held a special event for the open source project: a public demonstrations session. To better understand what this is about, let&amp;rsquo;s provide some context.
Demonstrations at PrestaShop Historically, the maintainers team of the PrestaShop open source project was only composed of employees from the PrestaShop company, developers assigned by the company to work on the project. This team used many forms of organizations over years, the most recent being a mix of Scrum rituals and Kanban method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From legacy to future architecture: Connecting the dots</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/from-legacy-to-future-architecture-connecting-the-dots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/from-legacy-to-future-architecture-connecting-the-dots/</guid>
      <description>This is the fourth and final article in a series we introduced last year, that aims to describe where we are, where we are going, and some ideas on how we&amp;rsquo;ll get there.
Connecting the dots (or &amp;ldquo;Some ideas on how we&amp;rsquo;ll get from Point A to Point B&amp;rdquo;)
During this series &amp;ldquo;PrestaShop in 2019 and beyond&amp;rdquo;, we described the current architecture (or &amp;ldquo;Point A&amp;rdquo;), its pain points, and what we think PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s future architecture (or &amp;ldquo;Point B&amp;rdquo;) should look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop in 2019 and beyond, part 3: The Future Architecture</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-in-2019-and-beyond-part-3-the-future-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-in-2019-and-beyond-part-3-the-future-architecture/</guid>
      <description>This is the third in a series of articles we introduced earlier this year, that aims to describe where we are, where we are going, and some ideas on how we&amp;rsquo;ll get there.
The Future Architecture (or &amp;ldquo;Point B – Where we are going&amp;rdquo;)
In the first part of the series, we described what the current architecture looks like. Then, the second part covered the fundamental things that were wrong with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop in 2019 and beyond, part 2: The Pain Points</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-in-2019-and-beyond-part-2-pain-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-in-2019-and-beyond-part-2-pain-points/</guid>
      <description>This is the second in a series of articles we introduced earlier this year, which aims to describe where we are, where we are going, and some ideas on how we&amp;rsquo;ll get there.
The Pain Points (or &amp;ldquo;What needs to be improved&amp;rdquo;)
In the previous part, we described what the current architecture looks like. This article aims to analyze what are the main &amp;ldquo;pain points&amp;rdquo;, that is, fundamental problems that are dragging the project down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing end of support for obsolete PHP versions</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/announcing-end-of-support-for-obsolete-php-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/announcing-end-of-support-for-obsolete-php-versions/</guid>
      <description>Current PHP compatibility in PrestaShop You can check the current PHP compatibility of PrestaShop on our documentation. For PrestaShop 1.7 you can check this page. About a year and a half ago, we announced that PrestaShop 1.7.4.0 would be dropping support for PHP 5.4 and 5.5. At that time, this decision was justified by the impending end-of-maintenance for Symfony 2 and its replacement by Symfony 3, which didn&amp;rsquo;t support PHP versions older than 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release of PrestaShop 1.7.5.2 and 1.6.1.24</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-5-2-1-6-1-24-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-5-2-1-6-1-24-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.5.2 and 1.6.1.24 are now available. These versions fix a security issue for both 1.7.5.x and 1.6.1.x. For the details, please read below:
These two security updates address a validation issue on the customer registration form, which is currently being exploited by spammers who were entering URLs as customer name.
This update mitigates the problem by preventing attackers to use URLs as names. However, as we discussed before, the best protection against this kind of attack still is to add a CAPTCHA module on your shop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop in 2019 and beyond, part 1: The current architecture</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-in-2019-and-beyond-part-1-current-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-in-2019-and-beyond-part-1-current-architecture/</guid>
      <description>This is the first in a series of articles we introduced a couple days ago, that aims at describing where we are, where we are going, and some ideas on how we&amp;rsquo;ll get there.
As pointed out in the introduction article, the first step to be able to map a path into the future is to understand where you stand currently. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll try and describe the current architecture of PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop in 2019 and beyond</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-in-2019-and-beyond-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-in-2019-and-beyond-introduction/</guid>
      <description>When working in a project as big and complex as PrestaShop, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get too focused on what you are doing right now, and lose sight of the big picture. However, it&amp;rsquo;s very important not to do that, because every decision we take must be coherent with a bigger plan. In fact, I think that the only way to allow a project such as this to be sustainable, coherent and predictable, is to consistently challenge every decision in light of a long-term vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release of PrestaShop 1.7.4.3 and 1.6.1.21</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-4-3-1-6-1-21-maintenance-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-4-3-1-6-1-21-maintenance-releases/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.4.3 and 1.6.1.21 are now available. These versions fix a security issue for both 1.7.4.x and 1.6.1.x. Some important issues are also fixed for 1.6.1.x. For the details, please read below.
Since these versions fix security problems, we strongly encourage you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
The most notable fix for 1.7.4.3 is:
Fixed a bug where sensitive configuration information could be disclosed when an fatal error occurred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release of PrestaShop 1.7.3.4 and 1.6.1.20</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-3-4-1-6-1-20-maintenance-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-3-4-1-6-1-20-maintenance-releases/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.3.4 and 1.6.1.20 are now available. These versions fix security and PHP compatiblity issues.
Since these versions fix security problems, we strongly encourage you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
The most notable fix for 1.7.3.x is:
Improve cookies encryption Some of the most notable fixes for 1.6.1.x are:
Improve cookies encryption Improve compatibility with PHP 7.1 and 7.2 Download PrestaShop now! Here is the complete list of changes for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release of PrestaShop 1.7.3.3 and 1.6.1.19</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-3-3-1-6-1-19-maintenance-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-3-3-1-6-1-19-maintenance-releases/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.3.3 and 1.6.1.19 are now available. Those maintenance releases fixes specific issues for the GDPR compliance.
Some of the most notable fixes are:
Add GDPR compliance to native modules Fix some diplay errors Download PrestaShop now! Here is the complete list of changes for 1.7.3.3
Back Office: Bug fix: #9026: Fixed display error on back office module selection list Front Office: New feature: #9099: Follow-up to: display GDPR consent checkbox in contactform Improvement: #9104: Add compliance to GDPR law for ps_emailsubscription module Here is the complete list of changes for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release of PrestaShop 1.7.3.2</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-3-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 14:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-3-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.3.2 is now available. This maintenance release fixes 17 issues reported on version 1.7.3.x.
Some of the most notable fixes are:
Updating combinations wasn’t working with PHP &amp;lt; 7.1 Installing a Theme with PrestaTrust modules was failing Various issues with product stock availability The &amp;ldquo;Install_prestashop.html&amp;rdquo; file was not visible on some systems Download PrestaShop 1.7.3.2 now! Here is the complete list of changes:
Back Office: Improvement: #8834: Adds missing Persian translations for data and samples Bug fix: #8752: Check product availability before validating orders #8975: Fix broken &amp;ldquo;you must first create a new language&amp;rdquo; link in BO Translations #8965: Fix theme install with prestatrust modules #8517: Fixed bug when using 2 swap in 1 form #8948: Fixed update of combinations #8762: Specific price created for a cart is displayed in the front end as the product price Front Office: Improvement: #8835: Replace Noto Sans font with Vazir font for Farsi in Classic theme Bug fix: #9005: Fix cannot order oos product even if it&amp;rsquo;s allowed #8951: Fix error display on cart quantity edition #8946: Fix button show password height on Safari #8940: Check product availability in order step #8931: Out of stock message display only if customer can order the product Core: Bug fix: #8973: Fixed undefined class constant #8850: Fix profile permission array construction #8679: Catch Throwable errors on CLI install and check Theme instance in context Installer: Improvement: #8843: Minor install improvements Bug fix: #8949: Remove addition of .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
