<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feature on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/feature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feature on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
  <language>en-us</language>
      <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/feature/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Improved Discounts System in PrestaShop 9.1</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/improved-discounts-system/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/improved-discounts-system/</guid>
          <description>Discounts are a pivotal element in ecommerce, driving sales and customer loyalty. As shops grow, the complexity of managing these promotions increases, often highlighting limitations in flexibility and performance. Recognizing these challenges, we embarked on a mission to revamp the discounts system in PrestaShop, aiming for a solution that is both powerful and easy to use.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Introducing Shipments in PrestaShop: finally solving the Multicarrier problem</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/introducing-shipments/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/introducing-shipments/</guid>
          <description>We are introducing a fundamental paradigm shift in PrestaShop’s core: moving the order management center of gravity from the Carrier to the Shipment.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>A new place to contribute to the PrestaShop project and share your feedback on the next features</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/productboard-portal-launch/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/productboard-portal-launch/</guid>
          <description>As announced here, the Core product team recently adopted a new working tool to gather feedback and prioritize features: Productboard. No more teasing, it is now time to have a look at how it will look and how we will all be able to handle it!</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Product development at PrestaShop</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/product-features-methodology-at-prestashop/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/product-features-methodology-at-prestashop/</guid>
          <description>In March 2020, the Core product team at PrestaShop, in charge of building and prioritizing new features, decided to work with a new tool: Productboard.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Introduction to the fuzzy search</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/introduction-to-the-fuzzy-search/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/introduction-to-the-fuzzy-search/</guid>
          <description>It is always great to see contributions from our community merged, it reminds the power of working on an open-source project. Especially when there are great features at stake, like the fuzzy search.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Stock management in PrestaShop 1.7 - part 4</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/stock-management-in-prestashop-1-7-part-4-prestashop-erp/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/stock-management-in-prestashop-1-7-part-4-prestashop-erp/</guid>
          <description>In the previous posts, we spoke about our motivations for designing a new stock management system and how we’ve built it in the 1.7.2 release. We also described in depth the features and the technology used in these new interfaces. Now it’s time to tell you about the forthcoming advanced features of stock management!</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Stock management in PrestaShop 1.7 - part 3</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/stock-management-in-prestashop-1-7-part-3/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/stock-management-in-prestashop-1-7-part-3/</guid>
          <description>In the previous episodes, we’ve seen the motivations for designing a new stock management interface and how we’ve built it. By now, you must be pretty eager to see what it looks like for real… So let’s dive into the features of this new page of PrestaShop 1.7.2.0.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Stock Management in PrestaShop 1.7 - part 2</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/stock-management-in-prestashop-1-7-part-2/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/stock-management-in-prestashop-1-7-part-2/</guid>
          <description>In a previous article, we’ve explained the reasons why we’re rebuilding the stock management system in 1.7. We detailed the initial brief of this project: the context, our intentions, what was out-of-scope and the expected outcome. In this article, I want to dive into our methodologies and the main steps of this project.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Stock Management in PrestaShop 1.7</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/stock-management-in-prestashop-1-7/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/stock-management-in-prestashop-1-7/</guid>
          <description>In late 2016, the PrestaShop product team took a challenging decision: rebuild the stock management system of PrestaShop 1.7. At the origins of this project was a thorough investigation and a truth-facing moment.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Presenting the Advanced EU Compliance module</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/advanced-eu-compliance/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/advanced-eu-compliance/</guid>
          <description>As good news never come alone, let us introduce you to the new module that is included natively in PrestaShop from 1.6.1.0 version: Advanced EU Compliance.</description>
        </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
