<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rc on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/rc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rc on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/rc/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 Release Candidate Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-rc1-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-rc1-release/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce the first release candidate of PrestaShop 8.1.
We&amp;rsquo;re on the brink of releasing the final 8.1 version. This time, the release candidate version is being shared simultaneously with the community and the project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance (QA) team. The idea is for everyone to collectively confirm that all issues identified in the beta version have been resolved, ensuring their suitability for production use. If no major problems are reported by June 26th, we&amp;rsquo;ll move ahead and launch the final version of 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0 Release Candidate Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-rc1-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-rc1-release/</guid>
      <description>The maintainers team is pleased to announce the first release candidate of PrestaShop 8.0.
This is the last step before releasing the final 8.0 version. This release candidate is intended to allow the community to verify that all regressions found during the beta have been fixed and that the software is ready for production. If no major or critical regression is reported before October 20th, then the final version of 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.0 RC1 Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-1-7-8-0-rc-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-1-7-8-0-rc-release/</guid>
      <description>A few months after the beta, the first release candidate for PrestaShop 1.7.8.0 is now ready for you to test!
This is the last step before releasing the final 1.7.8.0. This version aims to verify that all regressions found during the beta have been fixed and that the software is ready for production. If no major or critical regression is reported by October 5, then the final version of 1.7.8.0 will be made available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 RC1 Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-7-0-rc-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-7-0-rc-release/</guid>
      <description>We are really happy to announce that we are very close to finishing the 1.7.7.0 release, the release candidate is the last step before the final version is out.
This release candidate aims at making sure that all major regressions found during the beta have been fixed, and that no new ones have been spotted. If no new critical or major regression is reported by November 17th, we will make the final version of 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release note 1.7.6 RC2</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-6-0-rc2-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-6-0-rc2-release/</guid>
      <description>Once again the PrestaShop community actively participated in the testing of the PrestaShop 1.7.6 Release Candidate. Thanks to your involvement, 3 regressions were identified and fixed.
Our team is glad to announce PrestaShop 1.7.6.0 Release Candidate 2. If no new regression is reported in the next days, we will make the final version of 1.7.6.0 available by the end of next week (28).
Fixed in this Release Candidate 2 Front Office:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release note 1.7.6 RC1</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-6-0-rc-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-6-0-rc-release/</guid>
      <description>This is the last step before releasing the final 1.7.6.0. It aims at making sure that all regressions found during the beta have been fixed, and that no new ones appeared. If no new regression is reported by July 1st, we will make the final version of 1.7.6.0 available.
Please note that it is not currently possible to perform an automatic upgrade from the Beta to the Release Candidate. Furthermore, it will not be possible to upgrade from this Release Candidate to the final release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.3.0 RC1 is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-3-0-rc-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-3-0-rc-1/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.3.0 Release Candidate is now ready for you to test!
We are happy to announce that we are very close to releasing 1.7.3.0. This minor version (in the SemVer meaning of the term) brings several improvements, some new features and innovative tools to the 1.7 codebase. We can’t wait to receive your feedback about it!
Test PrestaShop 1.7.3.0 RC1 now! This release candidate is a great opportunity for you to start playing with it before we release the final version!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 RC3: Getting there!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC3/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re getting closer! With this new Release Candidate, we deliver a strong RC, which is closer than ever to our quality objectives.
A lot has been done to stabilize and enhance most of the details of the future version 1.7.0.0, and we expect you to be able to work with it as if it was a regular release. Are you feeling it? :)
Test PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 RC3 now! Found an issue?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 RC2: On the Right Track</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC2/</guid>
      <description>Another step in the right direction towards a stable v1.7, this RC2 fixes a lot of stuff and enhances some more.
Again in this RC version, a good chunk of issues have been fixed and improved upon. It&amp;rsquo;s getting better every day, thanks to our community! If you&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting to create a 1.7 theme or to upgrade your 1.6 modules, this is the right time!
Test PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 RC2 now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 RC1: The Real Deal</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC1/</guid>
      <description>Here it comes: the bug fixin&amp;rsquo;, performance improvin&amp;rsquo;, stabilizin, all singin&amp;rsquo; all dancin&amp;rsquo; RC1 for PrestaShop 1.7! It is packed with goodness, and needs your love!
Released on August 29th, the 1.7 RC0 release was dubbed a &amp;ldquo;pre-RC1&amp;rdquo; version, so you knew what was coming. Since then, MANY bugs were fixed and improvements added. We&amp;rsquo;re sure you will like this release even more than RC0! We hope it will be the one you will start working with when building your modules and themes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommended for testing: PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 RC0</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC0/</guid>
      <description>Have you been waiting for a &amp;ldquo;stable enough&amp;rdquo; version of PrestaShop 1.7 in order to start truly testing this new major release? Well, consider yourself in luck, because today we are releasing the RC0 of PrestaShop &amp;ndash; not quite a first RC, but close enough for you to start testing and provide us with the necessary feedback to make 1.7 a good fit for your needs!
We know how the Open Source community at large works with new major versions: pay attention only once 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test PrestaShop 1.6.1.2 RC4</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/prestashop-1-6-1-2-rc4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 14:00:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/prestashop-1-6-1-2-rc4/</guid>
      <description>Today we are releasing the fourth Release Candidate version of version 1.6.1.2.
Let&amp;rsquo;s be honest here: the RC2/RC3 was quite a mess, with last-minute issues which forced us to repackage the whole thing &amp;ndash; twice! Turns out several pull-requests were merged at the last minute in order to fix more issues in this version, and these PR were not as thoroughly tested as they should have been.
So this RC4 took a bit more time than usual, all the while featuring much less changes than the previous RCs: we took the time to revise our workflow, have more eyes look at the code before it was merged, and merged fewer PRs in order to keep the RC focused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test PrestaShop 1.6.1.2 RC3</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/prestashop-1-6-1-2-rc3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 14:00:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/prestashop-1-6-1-2-rc3/</guid>
      <description>We received quite a few feedback reports and pull-requests since we released v1.6.1.2 RC1 two weeks ago, so here&amp;rsquo;s the RC3, which fixes some more issues, and polishes a few more lines of code.
NOTE: The RC2 was first uploaded yesterday (Monday 5th) with a slight parenthesis issue which broke many pages. It was fixed by our Core team and repackaged at around 3 PM (Paris time), and two more small corrections since then have proven essential, hence the RC3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test PrestaShop 1.6.1.2 RC1</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/prestashop-1-6-1-2-rc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 18:00:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/prestashop-1-6-1-2-rc1/</guid>
      <description>As mentionned in the previous Core Weekly report, the team is working on version 1.6.1.2, which after v1.6.1.1 is the second patch version of 1.6.1.0.
Like we did for v1.6.1.1, we want to give v1.6.1.2 a solid testing phase: we are planning two weeks for feedback on the issues that were fixed. This testing phase starts today, with the availability of the first Release Candidate version, or RC1 for short.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test PrestaShop 1.6.1.1 RC2!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/prestashop-1-6-1-1-rc2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 15:45:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/prestashop-1-6-1-1-rc2/</guid>
      <description>Following the publication of version 1.6.1.1 Release Candidate 1, we have fixed a few more issues that had been identified. Thanks for helping with the tests and for the feedback!
As announced earlier, version 1.6.1.0 turned out great, but there were still a few bumps here and there. We have fixed the main issues that were reported: 163 pull requests were merged into this version!
We&amp;rsquo;d like to keep testing it with the help of our Community!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
