<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.1 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download!
After a few weeks of intensive work from all project members, the first maintenance release for version 8 is now available.
In this patch, you can find more than 30 bug fixes and one performance improvement that prevents clearing the system&amp;rsquo;s cache for bulk actions performed from the modules list. You will also get changes from the recent PrestaShop patch release 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – December 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-december-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-december-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in December!
Project news ➕ The PrestaShop project 2022 retrospective 🎉 2023 is here, happy new year! Thank you all for your contributions. With the help of every single one of you, PrestaShop 8.0 was released on October 26, 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8 is now a LTS</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/178-lts-80/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/178-lts-80/</guid>
      <description>Now that PrestaShop 8.0 is out, here is a focus on maintained branches of the PrestaShop project and what to expect.
Reminder: PrestaShop branching strategy In August 2015 PrestaShop adopted a new branching model for the project.
The model was refined over the years, for example with this page on the developer documentation about what bugs do qualify for a patch version or the Backward Compatibility Promise that defines what changes can be introduced in a version, but we can say the model has lived quite well as the project is still following it in 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - December</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2022-12-01-2022-12-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2022-12-01-2022-12-31/</guid>
      <description>Release of PrestaShop 1.7.8.8 and the autoupgrade module, what&amp;rsquo;s next for PrestaShop 8, an overview of ongoing work, and much more. This Core Monthly summarizes what happened in the project during the month of December.
Dear community,
Welcome to the first Core Monthly of 2023! 2022 was a fantastic year for the PrestaShop project, with a new major release, announcement of the upcoming new theme for PrestaShop, and significant changes to the project&amp;rsquo;s structure, which made it more open than it has ever been.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Project Public Demo - December 2022 Session</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/public-demo-9-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/public-demo-9-2022/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s public demo was held for the ninth time this year and streamed live on December 14th, 2022.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows:
00:00 Beginning of the session: introduction 02:24 Project news: PrestaShop 1.7.8.8 04:04 Project news: new project members 04:36 Project news: Hummingbird theme, status update 08:53 Project news: core monthly 10:04 Demo: availability labels per combination by @Hlavtox 16:08 Demo: more options for discontinued products by @Hlavtox 22:03 Demo: ability to configure backorder status by @Hlavtox 24:23 Pull Requests overview 33:48 Questions &amp;amp; answers (do you have any questions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing December PrestaShop Project Public Demo</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/upcoming-demo-9-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/upcoming-demo-9-2022/</guid>
      <description>Friendly reminder, that the public demo for the PrestaShop Project will happen tomorrow, on Wednesday, December 14th, 2022 at 4pm CET!
I expect to share with you project news. Additionally, a few demos are planned:
Availability labels for product combinations, by @Hlavtox New options for discountinued products, by @Hlavtox Better managing the order state for backorder products, by @Hlavtox At the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions beforehand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.8 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-1-7-8-8-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-1-7-8-8-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>It has been decided to deliver a new maintenance release for 1.7.8.x branch. Please note that this will be the last regular 1.7.8.x patch version, as the branch now enters security-only maintenance phase. Next regular patches will now target 8.0.x branch.
This release fixes some bugs and regressions as well as a security fix.
We suggest upgrading your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to backup before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – November 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-november-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-november-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in November!
Project news ➕ Our translation guide is now available 🎉 Christmas draws near. We teased our little gift last month and it is finally here (drumrolls): the translation guide to PrestaShop software is now available. The guide has everything you need to get started or dig deeper into the Crowdin project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - November</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/core-monthly-2022-11-01-2022-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/core-monthly-2022-11-01-2022-11-30/</guid>
      <description>In this Core Monthly, I will focus on a few important topics that are being worked on inside the project, the new product page, initiatives, new releases, and some great contributions from the community.
Dear developers,
Here it is! The first edition of the Core Monthly. I know through community feedback about the impact weekly summaries recently had, this is why it was decided to summarize the entire month in one article to make them more useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing: PrestaShop Project Office Hours</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/office-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/office-hours/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, a new initiative was started: PrestaShop Project Office Hours.
The concept is simple: once a week, project members make themselves available to the community to discuss topics directly related to the PrestaShop open source project.
So far, three meetings have been held which were a chance to discuss a number of topics:
project structure and processes helping finish and merge some PRs from the community multi-store features the future of core architecture And hopefully more discussions will come during the upcoming meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Project Public Demo - November 2022 Session</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/public-demo-8-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/public-demo-8-2022/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s public demo was held for the eighth time this year and streamed live on November 9th, 2022.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows:
00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 01:55 Project news: PrestaShop 8.0 is available! 03:17 Demo: introducing new back office API by @atomiix 11:47 Demo: PrestaShop 8.1 and beyond by @FabienVallon 24:36 Questions &amp;amp; answers (do you have any questions? Fill this form and we&amp;rsquo;ll answer in the next session).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – October 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in October!
Project news ➕ PrestaShop 8 is now available to the world 🎉 PrestaShop 8 is here! While it’s been translated into multiple languages already (thank you all for your contributions!), new translation strings are added regularly, so keep an eye out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing November PrestaShop Project Public Demo</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/upcoming-demo-8-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/upcoming-demo-8-2022/</guid>
      <description>Friendly reminder, that the public demo for the PrestaShop Project from the maintainers team will happen next week, on Wednesday, November 9th, 2022 at 4pm CET!
We expect to share with you project news and present two topics:
Introducing: new back office API, by @atomiix PrestaShop 8.1 and beyond, by @FabienVallon At the end of every meeting, we hold a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions beforehand. If you have some, about things related to the open source project, feel free to ask using this form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Weekly - Week 43 of 2022</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/coreweekly-43-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/coreweekly-43-2022/</guid>
      <description>This edition of the Core Weekly report highlights changes in PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s core codebase from Monday 24th to Sunday 30th of October 2022.
General messages Dear developers,
PrestaShop 8 is available! This is an important moment for everyone involved in the project. All project members would like to thank the community for their involvement in this new version.
The Hummingbird theme maintainers team decided to release its early version. If you are working with PrestaShop themes, this is a great chance to get your hands on this new version to see what the future holds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-0-available/</guid>
      <description>The maintainers team is pleased to announce that PrestaShop 8.0 is officially available.
PrestaShop 8, the first major version since the original release of PrestaShop 1.7.0 back in 2016, is an important milestone for the project.
A significant cleanup has been performed in the codebase, with several internal components updated, modified or removed. PrestaShop 8 is also the project’s first company-neutral release, meaning that it no longer includes commercial products and services built-in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
