<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update January 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-january-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-january-2024/</guid>
      <description>The first Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2024 will happen on Wednesday, January 17th, 2024 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
In the first Live Update of the year, we have some news to share, and we will have a special guest. Łukasz Janik from the e-commerce agency Waynet will join us to talk about CI/CD processes for PrestaShop, they use in their projects. This presentation was originally presented during the PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSDevCon 2023: PrestaShop News - Where We Are And Where We’re Going</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-news-where-we-are-and-where-we-are-going/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-news-where-we-are-and-where-we-are-going/</guid>
      <description>The PrestaShop Developer Conference happened on the 30th of November 2023. During the day, I was able to present a conference, titled “PrestaShop news - Where we are and where we&amp;rsquo;re going”. This blog post is a written version of the presentation that I also partially presented at the December Live Update on December 20th.
This post does not cover the first part of the presentation titled “PrestaShop 8.1 &amp;amp; 2023 - What’s new” because PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - December 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-10-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-10-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the tenth time this year and streamed live on December 20th, 2023.
PrestaShop Live Update - December 2023 The first Live Update after a month-long break, due to the PrestaShop Developer Conference, was the occasion for an important announcement, which probably comes as no surprise now that you&amp;rsquo;re reading this blog. The project now has the same branding PrestaShop SA has been using for several months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.3 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-3-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-3-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>We are entering the new year with the release of PrestaShop 8.1.3. The latest update for PrestaShop 8.1 is now available. This version brings two security updates, addresses close to 30 known issues, and introduces various enhancements.
To welcome the new year well, we are releasing a new version of PrestaShop! Version 8.1.3 is available with a slight delay, but this is due to the time it took to complete work on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.11 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-1-7-8-11-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-1-7-8-11-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A security patch for PrestaShop 1.7 is now available.
As part of the extended support policy for PrestaShop 1.7, which involves taking care of critical and security fixes for the 1.7.8.x branch, we are releasing today a new patch for this version. This release fixes one high severity security issue found by security researchers.
For more details regarding security fixes, you can check the security advisories section below.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – November 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-november-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-november-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about coding, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in November 2023.
A few stats 4 members joined the project this month. 13 members were active on the project. A total of 8,533 words have been translated and 8,860 validated. All this in 13 different languages. Thank you all very much for your involvement!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris: Synopsis Of The Day</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-2023/</guid>
      <description>The European community of PrestaShop developers gathered to talk code, commerce and also open source in Paris, on November 30, 2023, at the PrestaShop Developer Conference. It was so exciting to see approximately 150 people come to follow conferences and other technical presentations, as well as network during the day.
PrestaShop Developer Conference 2023 The event opened its doors at 9AM and very quickly the venue filled up. Attendees were able to enjoy breakfast before diving into the day&amp;rsquo;s introduction in the main room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Branding For The Project</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/new-project-branding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/new-project-branding/</guid>
      <description>This week will see some changes with the Project. PrestaShop SA, the company, is making the open source Project consistent with the new PrestaShop branding.
New PrestaShop Project branding Unveiled earlier this year, PrestaShop launched its new brand identity to affirm PrestaShop’s strengths, showing more credibility and trust.
Therefore, in the next few days, to align with this new identity, all materials related to the Project will change. You’ll see the rebranded Project’s website, developer documentation, this blog, and other Project-related content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hooks in the Hummingbird theme</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/hummingbird-theme-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/hummingbird-theme-hooks/</guid>
      <description>Hummingbird is the new theme set to be introduced in PrestaShop 9. This theme represents a complete overhaul of the Classic theme, featuring a fresh design and new functionalities. The Product Design team at PrestaShop has developed a visual guide to the hooks available in this theme, aimed at simplifying customization for front-end developers who want to work with it.
What is a hook? As described in the developer documentation:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing December PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-10-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-10-2023/</guid>
      <description>The tenth Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, December 20th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
This time, we will announce project updates and follow two presentations originally given at the PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris:
PrestaShop news - where we are and where we&amp;rsquo;re going by @matks API OAuth/CQRS in PrestaShop 9 by @jolelievre Join us on YouTube! Remember that at the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - November</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-11-01-2023-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-11-01-2023-11-30/</guid>
      <description>November was marked by the first PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris.
PrestaShop Developer Conference On November 30th, PrestaShop organized its first developer conference in Paris. The event was a great success, with around 150 attendees, over 25 speakers, and almost 20 talks. It was a great opportunity to discuss best practices for working with PrestaShop software, exchange experiences between developers and discuss PrestaShop development.
The great turnout proved to everyone we need more events of that type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – October 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about coding, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in October 2023.
Project news Developer Conference in Paris We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the translation project at the Developer Conference on November 30, 2023 in Paris, France. If you’re attending the event, meet us at 3 pm in the Tech room. See you there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris: Program and Registration</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-agenda-registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-agenda-registration/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re a PrestaShop developer or enthusiast looking to broaden your knowledge and connect with fellow community members, the PrestaShop Developer Conference is the event for you.
Scheduled for November 30, 2023, in Paris, France, the conference promises an in-depth exploration of technical topics, innovative solutions, and ample opportunities to network and engage with peers who share your passion for PrestaShop. We&amp;rsquo;re also very happy to go over the recent unveiling of the agenda, packed with compelling sessions and engaging activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - October</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-10-01-2023-10-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-10-01-2023-10-31/</guid>
      <description>In this Core Monthly, check out what we&amp;rsquo;ve been up to in October with PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s core and modules. Also, get a sneak peek at the agenda and speakers for the upcoming PrestaShop Developer Conference.
PrestaShop Developer Conference A few weeks ago we closed the call for papers for the conference, and it&amp;rsquo;s time to share with you the agenda as well as speakers for the event. We received a lot of great submissions, and we&amp;rsquo;re excited to share the agenda with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - October 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-9-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-9-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the ninth time this year and streamed live on October 11th, 2023.
PrestaShop Live Update - October 2023 It was a special Live Update where we said goodbye to the project leader, Pablo Borowicz, who, after over six years, is leaving the PrestaShop company. On behalf of everyone in the project, I would like to thank him for all the work he has done for the project and wish him all the best in his future endeavors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
