<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - August</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-08-01-2023-08-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-08-01-2023-08-31/</guid>
      <description>A little later than usual, discover the latest happenings in the PrestaShop Project for August 2023. We had a productive month, successfully merging more than 240 pull requests and releasing PrestaShop 8.1.1 and some security patches. Read on to find out more!
PrestaShop 8.1.1, 8.0.5, 1.7.8.10 The first patch for PrestaShop 8.1 and security patches for 8.0.5 and 1.7.8.10 are all available to download. You can read the details about these versions in the release notes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing September PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-8-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-8-2023/</guid>
      <description>The eighth Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, September 13th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
We will go over the latest project updates, take a look at recent changes in the software, changes made in the developer documentation, and more!
Remember that at the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions during the presentation or beforehand. If you have questions related to the open source project, feel free to let us know in advance using this form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – July 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-july-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-july-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in July.
Project news 🇯🇵/ 🇧🇦Looking for Japanese/Bosnian translators and proofreaders 🇯🇵The Japanese translation project is looking for translators and proofreaders! If you wish to join efforts and help contributor momo-i translate PrestaShop into Japanese — or if you simply want to ask a question, send me a message on Crowdin or on Slack!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - July 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-07-01-2023-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-07-01-2023-07-31/</guid>
      <description>Read about what has been going on in the PrestaShop Project in July 2023. It was a good month with over 340 merged pull requests! 🎉
Even during the Summer we see a lot of great progress in the PrestaShop Project. In July, we merged over 340 pull requests.
We welcomed three new committers:
Guyomar Alexis (@ga-devfront) Clément Désiles (@jokesterfr) Morgan Pichat (@M0rgan01) You can see all current project members on the updated People and Roles page on the project&amp;rsquo;s website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.1 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available. This release contains a few security fixes, so we highly recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
Version 8.1.1 fixes a few security issues found by security researchers and solves a great number of bugs reported by the community and project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance team.
You can go to the release page to see a full changelog, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning a few notable bug fixes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.5 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-5-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-5-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The fifth patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download! This release contains a few security fixes, so we highly recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
PrestaShop 8.0.x branch is no longer supported since the release of PrestaShop 8.1, but due to the high severity of the security issues fixed in this release, we decided to release a patch version for this branch.
Apart from the security fixes, this release also contains a few bug fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.10 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-10-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-10-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A security patch for PrestaShop 1.7 is now available.
As part of the extended support policy for PrestaShop 1.7, which involves taking care of critical and security fixes for the 1.7.8.x branch, we are releasing today a new patch for this version. This release fixes a few security issues found by security researchers.
For more details regarding security fixes, you can check the security advisories section below.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PrestaShop Developer Conference is coming to Paris!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-coming-to-paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-coming-to-paris/</guid>
      <description>Are you a passionate PrestaShop developer or enthusiast, wanting to expand your knowledge and network within the community? The PrestaShop team is happy to let you know the call for presentations is open for the PrestaShop Developer Conference, taking place in Paris, France on November 30, 2023. This event promises to be an opportunity to engage in technical discussions, discover solutions, and connect with like-minded peers in the community.
So, what is the PrestaShop Developer Conference?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - July 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-7-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-7-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the seventh time this year and streamed live on July 19th, 2023.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows: 00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 01:51 Project news: PrestaShop Developer Conference 04:37 Project news: PrestaShop 8.1 14:39 Demo: enable WebP or Avif in PrestaShop 8.1 20:21 Demo: enable developer mode with cookie in PrestaShop 9.0 24:14 Demo: RectorPHP in PrestaShop 9.0 29:06 Demo: changes in the developer documentation 38:52 Q&amp;amp;A session You can use the timestamps to jump directly to the parts you want to watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing July PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-7-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-7-2023/</guid>
      <description>The seventh Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, July 19th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
We will go over the latest project updates, take a look at recent changes in the software, changes made in the developer documentation, and more!
Remember that at the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions during the presentation or beforehand. If you have questions related to the open source project, feel free to let us know in advance using this form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – June 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-june-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-june-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in June.
Project news 🌍 Translating the PrestaShop documentation If you didn’t know, you can help translate the PrestaShop 8 documentation into your own language! For now, the PrestaShop 8 docs are only available in English and French, but if you wish to help translate it, let me know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - June</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-06-01-2023-06-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-06-01-2023-06-30/</guid>
      <description>The new PrestaShop 8.1, ongoing work on PrestaShop 9.0, new content in the developer documentation and more! Read about all this news in the Core Monthly report for June.
PrestaShop 8.1 is out! You read that right! The new PrestaShop 8.1 is out! 🎉 Congratulations to the whole PrestaShop project team, contributors and community members who made this release possible. Version 8.1 is a minor upgrade, with major improvements. The all-new product management page, full support for WebP and Avif and lots of other improvements are waiting for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-0-available/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to announce that PrestaShop 8.1 is officially available.
PrestaShop 8.1 is a minor upgrade with major improvements. It&amp;rsquo;s focused on making things faster and easier for you, transforming the way you use PrestaShop.
The entirely reworked product management page delivers a more efficient and user-friendly experience. This new page makes managing product combinations, prices, taxes, stock, and images quicker and easier. Multistore product management has also been drastically improved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freelance Developer and Translator: Meet SNor42</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-snor42/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-snor42/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who’s hiding behind a Crowdin username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project.
For the second interview of 2023, we interview Norbert, aka SNor42.
Ranked 29th on the top translator page, Norbert is a translator and proofreader on the Hungarian project.
Hello SNor! :-) 👋 Can you tell me more about yourself?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - June 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-6-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-6-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the sixth time this year and streamed live on June 21st, 2023.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows: 00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 03:00 Project news: PrestaShop Developer Conference 04:33 Project news: PrestaShop 8.1 06:36 Demo: issue management in the PrestaShop project by @hibatallahAouadni 22:22 Demo: PrestaShop 9.0 roadmap by @fabienvallon 32:20 Demo: breaking changes &amp;amp; improvements in PrestaShop 9.0 by @boherm 47:14 Q&amp;amp;A session You can use the timestamps to jump directly to the parts you want to watch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
