<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - November</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-11-01-2023-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-11-01-2023-11-30/</guid>
      <description>November was marked by the first PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris.
PrestaShop Developer Conference On November 30th, PrestaShop organized its first developer conference in Paris. The event was a great success, with around 150 attendees, over 25 speakers, and almost 20 talks. It was a great opportunity to discuss best practices for working with PrestaShop software, exchange experiences between developers and discuss PrestaShop development.
The great turnout proved to everyone we need more events of that type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – October 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about coding, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in October 2023.
Project news Developer Conference in Paris We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the translation project at the Developer Conference on November 30, 2023 in Paris, France. If you’re attending the event, meet us at 3 pm in the Tech room. See you there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris: Program and Registration</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-agenda-registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-agenda-registration/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re a PrestaShop developer or enthusiast looking to broaden your knowledge and connect with fellow community members, the PrestaShop Developer Conference is the event for you.
Scheduled for November 30, 2023, in Paris, France, the conference promises an in-depth exploration of technical topics, innovative solutions, and ample opportunities to network and engage with peers who share your passion for PrestaShop. We&amp;rsquo;re also very happy to go over the recent unveiling of the agenda, packed with compelling sessions and engaging activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - October</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-10-01-2023-10-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-10-01-2023-10-31/</guid>
      <description>In this Core Monthly, check out what we&amp;rsquo;ve been up to in October with PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s core and modules. Also, get a sneak peek at the agenda and speakers for the upcoming PrestaShop Developer Conference.
PrestaShop Developer Conference A few weeks ago we closed the call for papers for the conference, and it&amp;rsquo;s time to share with you the agenda as well as speakers for the event. We received a lot of great submissions, and we&amp;rsquo;re excited to share the agenda with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - October 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-9-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-9-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the ninth time this year and streamed live on October 11th, 2023.
PrestaShop Live Update - October 2023 It was a special Live Update where we said goodbye to the project leader, Pablo Borowicz, who, after over six years, is leaving the PrestaShop company. On behalf of everyone in the project, I would like to thank him for all the work he has done for the project and wish him all the best in his future endeavors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing October PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-9-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-9-2023/</guid>
      <description>The ninth Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, October 11th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
We will go over the latest project updates, take a look at recent changes in the software, changes made in the developer documentation and at the end of the session we will make a very special announcement.
Join us on YouTube! Remember that at the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – September 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-september-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-september-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about coding, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in September 2023.
Project news New strings are ready for translation As you may have noticed, new strings were added to Crowdin on September 28. It&amp;rsquo;s usually not possible to add new strings outside the release of a minor or major version of PrestaShop but we had to do it to fix a bug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - September</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-09-01-2023-09-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-09-01-2023-09-30/</guid>
      <description>In this article, delve into September&amp;rsquo;s updates and news from the project. As well as Hacktoberfest 2023&amp;rsquo;s kick off, offering a month-long celebration of open-source contributions. Keep reading for more information.
PrestaShop 8.1.2 In September, the project saw the release of PrestaShop 8.1.2. This second patch for the 8.1 series brings two security fixes and addresses over 30 bugs. The release also includes minor enhancements, particularly to the new product page and the multi-format image generation system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The second patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available! This release contains 2 security fixes, over 30 bugs have been fixed and some minor improvements have been integrated.
Version 8.1.2 fixes a few security issues found by security researchers and solves a great number of bugs reported by the community and project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance team. It also includes some minor improvements, especially for the new product page and new multi-format image generation system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/hacktoberfest-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/hacktoberfest-2023/</guid>
      <description>The month of October is coming quickly! So be prepared for Hacktoberfest, a month-long celebration of open source software.
Hacktoberfest 2023 The online event has been happening every October since 2013 and is sponsored by DigitalOcean. This year marks the 10th anniversary of the event, with changes to help ensure its sustainability for the next decade. You’ll learn about these right below. How can you participate? Very simple: people are encouraged to create at least 4 pull requests for open source projects on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – August 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-august-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-august-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in August 2023.
Project news Some updates on the translation project Starting September 18th 2023, the PrestaShop translation project will be managed by both @Julievrz and @axel.viersac. As such, they will be the ones taking care of everything related to the project, including this newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - September 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-8-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-8-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the eighth time this year and streamed live on September 13th, 2023.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows: 00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 02:30 Project news: PrestaShop Developer Conference 04:28 Project news: PrestaShop 8.1.1, 8.0.5 and 1.7.8.10 08:56 Demo: changes in the developer documentation by @thomasnares 43:00 Q&amp;amp;A session You can use the timestamps to jump directly to the parts you want to watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - August</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-08-01-2023-08-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-08-01-2023-08-31/</guid>
      <description>A little later than usual, discover the latest happenings in the PrestaShop Project for August 2023. We had a productive month, successfully merging more than 240 pull requests and releasing PrestaShop 8.1.1 and some security patches. Read on to find out more!
PrestaShop 8.1.1, 8.0.5, 1.7.8.10 The first patch for PrestaShop 8.1 and security patches for 8.0.5 and 1.7.8.10 are all available to download. You can read the details about these versions in the release notes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing September PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-8-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-8-2023/</guid>
      <description>The eighth Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, September 13th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
We will go over the latest project updates, take a look at recent changes in the software, changes made in the developer documentation, and more!
Remember that at the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions during the presentation or beforehand. If you have questions related to the open source project, feel free to let us know in advance using this form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – July 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-july-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-july-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in July.
Project news 🇯🇵/ 🇧🇦Looking for Japanese/Bosnian translators and proofreaders 🇯🇵The Japanese translation project is looking for translators and proofreaders! If you wish to join efforts and help contributor momo-i translate PrestaShop into Japanese — or if you simply want to ask a question, send me a message on Crowdin or on Slack!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
