<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Call for contributions: Admin API - great start!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-admin-api-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-admin-api-progress/</guid>
      <description>Two months ago, we launched our second Call for Contributions initiative, this time focusing on the Admin API. We&amp;rsquo;re excited to share the progress that&amp;rsquo;s been made!
What is this initiative about? Following the success of our first Call for Contributions focused on hooks, we asked the community during the FoP Days to vote on what to tackle next. The Admin API emerged as a top priority, alongside hooks and web accessibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - October 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-10-01-2025-10-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-10-01-2025-10-31/</guid>
      <description>October has been an exceptional month for the PrestaShop project! We released the first maintenance version of PrestaShop 9, opened registration for our biggest community event of the year, and watched the Admin API contribution initiative gain incredible momentum. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into what made this month so special.
October was truly a milestone month for PrestaShop. The energy and enthusiasm from both PrestaShop SA and our community contributors have been remarkable, resulting in impressive progress across multiple fronts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0.1 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch version for PrestaShop 9 is now available! This maintenance release focuses on resolving some of the key issues to ensure a smoother experience for all users.
A strong start for PrestaShop 9 Since its release, PrestaShop 9 has been met with great enthusiasm from our community. Many developers, agencies, and merchants have actively tested the new version and shared their valuable feedback. This collaborative effort has been instrumental in helping us refine the new version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference 2025: Register now!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/register-for-prestashop-developer-conference-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/register-for-prestashop-developer-conference-2025/</guid>
      <description>The ecommerce world is advancing at an exciting pace, creating fresh opportunities for developers and businesses. That’s why we are excited to announce the third edition of the PrestaShop Developer Conference, taking place on November 19, 2025, in Paris and, for the first time, online.
Why attend the conference? The PrestaShop Developer Conference is more than just a day of talks, it’s a hub for passionate developers to connect, collaborate, and learn from leading voices in the PrestaShop community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - September 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-09-01-2025-09-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-09-01-2025-09-30/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the September edition of the Core Monthly! This month was buzzing with activity around PrestaShop 9, with the team working on its first patch release and the community stepping up to expand the new Admin API. We also saw some fantastic new tools and improvements, all thanks to dedicated contributors.
PrestaShop 9: patch in progress and Admin API Call for Contributions September has been a busy month for the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - August 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-08-01-2025-08-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-08-01-2025-08-31/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the August edition of Core Monthly. This month brought an important security patch for 8.2, a new community feature in the back office, and a fresh call for contributions to expand the Admin API in PrestaShop 9.
Security: PrestaShop 8.2.3 A security-driven patch release for PrestaShop 8.2 is out. Version 8.2.3 fixes an email enumeration vulnerability on the back office password reset page. While PrestaShop 9 is not affected, we strongly recommend updating if you are on the 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.3 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-3-security-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-3-security-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 8.2.3 is available. It is a security‑driven patch release for the 8.2 branch. Its primary goal is to address an email enumeration vulnerability in the back office password reset feature. A handful of low-risk improvements and bug fixes that have already been validated have also been included.
Why this release now? PrestaShop 8.2 is in the extended support phase, so only security and critical fixes are shipped. Over the past days, we observed (via community reports and partners) automated probes abusing the back office password reset page to enumerate employee emails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the PrestaShop Wall of Fame</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/meet-prestashop-wall-of-fame/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/meet-prestashop-wall-of-fame/</guid>
      <description>From its very first release, PrestaShop has been built and improved thanks to the dedication of its open source community. Today, we&amp;rsquo;re introducing a new way to celebrate that dedication - directly in your back office.
The Wall of Fame is a new tab in the back office available through the ps_distributionapiclient (version 1.2.0) module that showcases the top companies and individuals contributing to PrestaShop. Merchants can now see, right where they manage their store, the vibrant community making the software better every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for contributions: Admin API</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-admin-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-admin-api/</guid>
      <description>After the success of our first Call for Contributions focused on hooks, it&amp;rsquo;s time to launch a new round. This time, we&amp;rsquo;re inviting the community to contribute to one of the most significant changes in PrestaShop 9: the new Admin API.
Why the Admin API? During FoP Days, we asked attendees to vote on future contribution topics. Three stood out: Hooks, Admin API, and Web Accessibility (EAA). We started with Hooks, work on the EAA subject will be part of Hummingbird 2, led by PrestaShop S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - July 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-07-01-2025-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-07-01-2025-07-31/</guid>
      <description>We are back with the July edition of the PrestaShop Core Monthly! 🌞
Dear community,
July has been an exciting month for the PrestaShop project, filled with significant releases, upcoming feature announcements, and continued community engagement. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into what made this summer month particularly productive for our project.
PrestaShop 8.2.2 maintenance release We released PrestaShop 8.2.2 on July 28th, bringing a comprehensive set of bug fixes and improvements to the 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - July 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-july-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-july-2025/</guid>
      <description>On July 30th, 2025, we hosted another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project, highlighting the announcement of the upcoming One Page Checkout (OPC) feature in PrestaShop 9.1. We also covered the current state of the project, recent releases, and ongoing contribution initiatives, including the Admin API.
PrestaShop Live Update - July 2025 The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows: 00:00 Beginning of the session: introduction 02:21 Project news: PrestaShop 9.0 is available 10:23 Project news: PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update July 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-july-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-july-2025/</guid>
      <description>Yet another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2025 will be hosted on Wednesday, July 30th, 2025, at 4 PM (Paris time) on YouTube!
Join us for the upcoming Live Update, where we will share exciting news about the PrestaShop Project!
We will provide a summary of the Call for Contributions: Hooks Initiative, highlighting the community&amp;rsquo;s efforts and achievements.
But that&amp;rsquo;s not all! One of the highlights of this session will be an exclusive presentation on the highly anticipated One Page Checkout feature, coming in PrestaShop 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 8.2.2 is here! This latest patch version brings a range of updates, addressing reported issues and introducing enhancements to improve the platform for merchants and developers alike.
We are happy to announce the release of PrestaShop 8.2.2, a patch version that not only resolves numerous bugs reported by our dedicated community and Quality Assurance team but also introduces some improvements.
As part of the Call for Contributions challenge, PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - June 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-06-01-2025-06-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-06-01-2025-06-30/</guid>
      <description>We are back with yet another edition of the PrestaShop Core Monthly, your monthly digest of the PrestaShop codebase&amp;rsquo;s latest changes and news from the PrestaShop project.
PrestaShop 9.0.0 is out! 🎉 June marks the completion of one month since the PrestaShop 9.0.0 release, which is now available for download!
This release is a major milestone for the PrestaShop project, as it brings a lot of new features and improvements. We hope you will enjoy it as much as we do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.x is now in the extended support phase</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/82x-extended-support-phase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/82x-extended-support-phase/</guid>
      <description>Now that PrestaShop 9.0 is out, here is a focus on maintained branches of the PrestaShop project and what to expect.
Reminder: PrestaShop branching strategy In August 2015 PrestaShop adopted a new branching model for the project.
The model was refined over the years, for example with this developer documentation page about which bugs qualify for a patch version or the Backward Compatibility Promise that defines which changes can be introduced in a version.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
