<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.3 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-3-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-3-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The third patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download!
It was a rather bumpy road at the end because of issues we found during the release process, but here it is! In the newest patch version for PrestaShop 8 you can find a security improvement, and three fixes: one related to inaccurate wording in web services configuration, one which fixes the link to the user documentation in the installer, and one significant fix which improves how clearing the cache behaves in the software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - March 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-3-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-3-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the third time this year and streamed live on March 8th, 2023.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows: 00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 02:30 Project news: PrestaShop 8.0.2 will be available soon 03:48 Project news: PrestaShop 8.1-beta1 is now available 07:16 Project news: Google Analytics 4 for PrestaShop is now available 10:08 Demo: Developer documentation improvements, by @kpodemski 23:21 Demo: PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The second patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download!
Version 8.0.2 is available! In this patch, you can find over 20 bug fixes. As a patch version, 8.0.2 brings further goodness and stability to the 8.0 branch.
There were several noteworthy issues addressed in PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s 8.0.2 milestone. The upgrade mechanism had a problem where it couldn&amp;rsquo;t check if the PHP session had started on some webservers, which was reported by many community members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing March PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-3-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-3-2023/</guid>
      <description>The third Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, March 8th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
Tomorrow we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss what happened in the project in February. We&amp;rsquo;ll show you recent changes in the developer documentation, and some of the new features from PrestaShop 8.1.
At the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions beforehand. If you have some, about things related to the open source project, feel free to ask using this form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - February</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-02-01-2023-02-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-02-01-2023-02-28/</guid>
      <description>As we move into March, let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to review the progress made in February across the project. While PrestaShop 8.0.2 and 8.1 are certainly two key priorities, a lot of work has also been put in on other aspects of the project. Nonetheless, the final touches for PrestaShop 8.0.2 are currently underway, and progress on PrestaShop 8.1 continues to move forward steadily. Additionally, several exciting new features have been merged that will be incorporated into PrestaShop 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – February 2023 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/2023-03-02-do-you-speak-prestashop-february-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/2023-03-02-do-you-speak-prestashop-february-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in February!
Project news 🌐 The top translators page is back up After a short interruption due to a bug, the top translators page is now back up and running! This is where you&amp;rsquo;ll find the top contributors of the translation project, sorted by translated words as well as the progress of every language and fully translated languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 beta is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The beta version of PrestaShop 8.1 is now ready for you to test!
We’re delighted to announce that PrestaShop 8.1 has reached the beta stage. PrestaShop 8.1 is still in development, but we hope you will help us test this release so we can have the best quality release possible, available for everyone, as soon as possible!
Test PrestaShop 8.1.0 beta 1 now! Version 8.1 fixes over 30 bugs found in the previous release and introduces many improvements and new features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - February 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-2-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-2-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the second time this year and streamed live on February 8th, 2023.
Demos that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to miss! Safe to say, this was one of the best, if not the best, live updates we ever held. During February&amp;rsquo;s event, we had a chance to see one of the most popular PrestaShop community projects. Integration between PrestaShop and Vue Storefront created by BinShops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – January 2023 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-january-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-january-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in January!
Project news ➕ A new language is available for translation! Thanks to Ali Zhumagaliev, the Karakalpak language is now available for translation on the Crowdin project!
💕 Many thanks to January’s newcomers Many people subscribe to the project(s) of their choice each month, but not so many start translating straight away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - January 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-01-01-2023-01-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-01-01-2023-01-31/</guid>
      <description>The PrestaShop project had a busy January with a focus on releasing PrestaShop 8.0.1 and final touches for PrestaShop 8.1 before the feature-freeze. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at what happened in the project last month.
Yes, that really was a very busy January! The current dynamic in the project is at the top level. What happened last month?
PrestaShop 8.0.1 PrestaShop 8.0.1 was released on January 6th, and it is the first patch version for PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing February PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-2-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-2-2023/</guid>
      <description>The second Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, February 8th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
We prepared some very exciting demos for all of you!
New product page in PrestaShop 8.1, by @MatShir and @jolelievre PrestaShop x Vuestorefront integration, by @samberrry Faceted search module evolution, by @Hlavtox At the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions beforehand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 is now in feature freeze</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-feature-freeze/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-feature-freeze/</guid>
      <description>As of February 1, 2023, PrestaShop version 8.1 has entered the feature freeze phase. This article provides more information about the feature freeze, what the next steps will be, and what to expect from PrestaShop 8.1.
Feature freeze for PrestaShop 8.1 As of today, PrestaShop version 8.1 has entered a feature freeze. What is a feature freeze? Feature freeze refers to a specific stage in the software development process after which no new features can be added to a version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Discussions are now enabled in the PrestaShop Project!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/github-discussions-are-now-enabled-in-the-prestashop-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/github-discussions-are-now-enabled-in-the-prestashop-project/</guid>
      <description>Today, GitHub Discussions are being enabled for the PrestaShop Project. This feature will provide a more organized and easily accessible way for community members to collaborate, ask questions, and share ideas.
What are GitHub Discussions? GitHub Discussions is a new feature in GitHub that provides a space for community members to discuss directly on the project’s GitHub page, similarly to traditional forum boards. This feature is a great way to ask questions, share ideas, and collaborate with other community members, and it has proven its value in other open-source communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - January 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-1-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-1-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s first live update was held for the first time this year and streamed live on January 11th, 2023.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows:
00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 02:50 Project news: PrestaShop 8.0.1 is available 03:26 Project news: Autoupgrade 4.15 is available 07:01 Demo: Hummingbird theme, news &amp;amp; walkthrough, by @NeOMaking 30:05 Demo: WebP and Avif in PrestaShop: multiple image format generation, by @matthieu-rolland 38:16 Questions &amp;amp; answers (do you have any questions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing January PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-1-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-1-2023/</guid>
      <description>The first Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, January 11th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube! Public Demo is now called Live update, as it is planned to experiment with formats other than you could see in previous sessions, like live coding, interviews, etc.
This time, as always, I expect to share with you project news, and a couple of demos are planned:
Overview of the Hummingbird theme, by @NeOMaking WebP and Avif in PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
