<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference 2025 Filmed Sessions - Modern Development Practices and Architecture</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/developer-conference-2025-filmed-modern-development-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/developer-conference-2025-filmed-modern-development-architecture/</guid>
      <description>The PrestaShop Developer Conference took place a few months ago: last week, we&amp;rsquo;ve started publishing a series of blog posts diving into the event&amp;rsquo;s sessions, sharing insights and key takeaways with you. We are continuing the series with another spotlight on modern development practices and architectural approaches.
If you missed the event or want to revisit the key moments, we&amp;rsquo;ve made all sessions available on PrestaShop’s YouTube channel.
From automated deployment strategies to innovative module architecture patterns, the talks provide practical knowledge you can immediately apply to your projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.1 Beta is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/prestashop-9-1-beta1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/prestashop-9-1-beta1/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 9.1 Beta is here, and it includes several major improvements that you can already start exploring and sharing feedback on. Your input is valuable for the final release of PrestaShop 9.1.
We are excited to announce the availability of the first beta version of PrestaShop 9.1. This release brings significant changes, including a new default Hummingbird theme, a revamped discount system, and multi-carrier support.
Remember, this beta version is pre-release software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Discounts System in PrestaShop 9.1</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/improved-discounts-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/improved-discounts-system/</guid>
      <description>Discounts are a pivotal element in ecommerce, driving sales and customer loyalty. As shops grow, the complexity of managing these promotions increases, often highlighting limitations in flexibility and performance. Recognizing these challenges, we embarked on a mission to revamp the discounts system in PrestaShop, aiming for a solution that is both powerful and easy to use.
Here is a closer look at the improved discounts system coming to PrestaShop 9.1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Shipments in PrestaShop: finally solving the Multicarrier problem</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/introducing-shipments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/introducing-shipments/</guid>
      <description>We are introducing a fundamental paradigm shift in PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s core: moving the order management center of gravity from the Carrier to the Shipment.
This major architectural change is already partially available for testing. Starting with PrestaShop 9.1, you can access these new features under a feature flag. This allows merchants, agencies and developers to start adapting to the new &amp;ldquo;Shipment&amp;rdquo; logic today, without disrupting existing stores.
Work in progress This feature is currently available for testing purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference 2025 - Filmed Morning Sessions and Q&amp;A Now Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/prestashop-developer-conference-2025-keynote-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/prestashop-developer-conference-2025-keynote-sessions/</guid>
      <description>The PrestaShop Developer Conference happened a few weeks ago, and this year&amp;rsquo;s edition brought together our vibrant community for a day packed with technical insights, product announcements, and open discussions about the future of PrestaShop.
Over the coming weeks, we&amp;rsquo;ll be publishing a series of blog posts, similar to this one, diving into the event’s sessions, giving you insights and takeaways. Each post will spotlight different talks and themes from the conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 2025: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-year-in-review-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-year-in-review-2025/</guid>
      <description>As 2025 comes to a close, it&amp;rsquo;s time to reflect on an incredible year for the PrestaShop project. From the highly anticipated release of PrestaShop 9 to the vibrant gatherings at FOP Days and the Developer Conference, this year has been defined by innovation, collaboration, and the unwavering dedication of our community.
We’ve seen major technical advancements, new contribution initiatives, and a renewed focus on developer experience. Let’s take a month-by-month journey through the milestones that shaped 2025.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Good Intentions to Measurable Impact: PrestaShop&#39;s Call for Contributions at Open Source Experience</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-open-source-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-open-source-experience/</guid>
      <description>This month of December, Paule Morizot and Fabien Moreau of PrestaShop spoke at Open Source Experience about the project’s Call for Contributions. What a great place to give an update on this topic and to show an experienced crowd what we are currently doing at PrestaShop.
Open Source Experience, held at the Cité des Sciences in Paris, is one of Europe&amp;rsquo;s premier events for open source software, bringing together maintainers, contributors, and organizations committed to collaborative development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0.2-2.1: what happened and why the version looks different</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-2-2-1-patch-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-2-2-1-patch-version/</guid>
      <description>Some of you hit an unexpected issue when installing PrestaShop 9.0.2 from prestashop.com, and some also noticed a slightly unusual version number: 9.0.2-2.1, which has been used since the start of PrestaShop 9 but hadn’t been explicitly explained until now.
This post is not release notes. It&amp;rsquo;s a transparency update: what happened, what we changed in response, and what we&amp;rsquo;re doing to reduce the chance of a similar incident.
A blocking installation issue reported by the community A community report on GitHub described a problem during a fresh installation of PrestaShop 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.1 is in feature freeze</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-1-feature-freeze/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-1-feature-freeze/</guid>
      <description>As of December 12th, 2025, PrestaShop version 9.1 has entered the feature freeze phase. Learn more about the feature freeze, the next steps, and what’s coming in PrestaShop 9.1.
PrestaShop 9.1 feature freeze is in effect As of today, PrestaShop 9.1 is in feature freeze. What is a feature freeze? Feature freeze marks a stage in development when no new features are accepted. The focus shifts to polishing what’s built and validating quality before release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 9.0.2 is now available! This second patch version represents yet another step in making PrestaShop 9 more reliable. It focuses on fixing some reported issues to provide a more stable and seamless experience for merchants and developers.
PrestaShop 9 continues to focus on stability and polish With the second maintenance release, our attention has shifted from broad feature work to refining the platform based on real-world feedback. 9.0.2 brings targeted fixes that improve reliability, developer experience, and daily merchant operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fresh Start for PrestaShop Issues: Bringing Clarity to Chaos</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/reorganization-of-prestashop-issue-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/reorganization-of-prestashop-issue-management/</guid>
      <description>2,300 issues. One number. One challenge. Imagine searching for a needle in a haystack of 2,300 straws. That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what PrestaShop contributors experience today when trying to check if their bug has already been reported. It&amp;rsquo;s also the daily challenge for our QA teams navigating this ocean of issues, some dating back to 2018.
This historical centralization in PrestaShop/PrestaShop made sense&amp;hellip; until it didn&amp;rsquo;t. Today, we&amp;rsquo;re changing course.
Our vision: every issue in its place, a place for every issue We&amp;rsquo;re opening issues directly in each repository that needs them (Core, Themes, Modules) so every repo tracks its own bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference 2025 - Event Recap</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-developer-conference-2025-event-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-developer-conference-2025-event-recap/</guid>
      <description>On November 19, 2025, the PrestaShop developer community convened in Paris, and online via a global livestream, for the third PrestaShop Developer Conference. The program featured hands-on sessions, live demonstrations, and expert talks, alongside a major announcement. Attendees deepened their understanding of the PrestaShop ecosystem, gained project information, and explored practical advancements they can apply in their daily work.
Highlights from a day of insightful sessions on the Main Stage Throughout the day, the Main Stage featured expert-led talks from the PrestaShop community, unveiling a major announcement regarding MCP and also sessions regarding AI, PrestaShop Enterprise, PrestaShop Core, deployment, Hummingbird and call for contributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hummingbird v2.0.0 Beta Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/hummingbird-v2-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/hummingbird-v2-beta/</guid>
      <description>We are thrilled to announce the release of Hummingbird v2.0.0 Beta. This milestone is the result of a monumental effort, representing more than 320 commits, 500 file changes, 50,000 additions, and 30,000 deletions. The goal is to deliver a developer-first, lightweight, and modular theme that establishes a new standard for the PrestaShop ecosystem.
Hummingbird will become the new default theme in PrestaShop starting from version 9.1, while the Classic theme will remain available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunsetting the PrestaShop cron service</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/sunsetting-the-prestashop-cron-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/sunsetting-the-prestashop-cron-service/</guid>
      <description>The PrestaShop cron service will be officially shut down in December 2025, marking the end of a legacy component that once helped stores without full server access automate scheduled tasks.
What is the PrestaShop cron service? This service was originally introduced to assist merchants on shared hosting environments that did not allow setting up native cron jobs. It worked together with the cronjobs module, sending periodic requests to execute scheduled actions such as currency rate updates or module maintenance routines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for contributions: Admin API - great start!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-admin-api-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-admin-api-progress/</guid>
      <description>Two months ago, we launched our second Call for Contributions initiative, this time focusing on the Admin API. We&amp;rsquo;re excited to share the progress that&amp;rsquo;s been made!
What is this initiative about? Following the success of our first Call for Contributions focused on hooks, we asked the community during the FoP Days to vote on what to tackle next. The Admin API emerged as a top priority, alongside hooks and web accessibility.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
