<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9 minimum PHP version will be PHP8.1</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-9-min-php-version-will-be-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-9-min-php-version-will-be-81/</guid>
      <description>The develop branch contains the source code that will give birth to PrestaShop 9. This is the future of PrestaShop: it will be released either at the end of the year 2023 or at the beginning of the year 2024 and must carry on the ambition of the project for 2024. This major version must also embrace the change in the PHP ecosystem, and consequently, it must drop the support of obsolete PHP versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louis Authie: Freelancer, Contributor and Author</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-louis-authie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-louis-authie/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who’s hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project.
This month, meet Louis Authie, aka LouisAUTHIE.
Louis is a freelance full stack developer at Web Helpers, with over 120 contributions on GitHub. He’s also a member of Friends of Presta, an association that gathers a community of developers and integrators around the open source ecommerce solution PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – April 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-april-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-april-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in April.
Project news 📖 Coming soon: PrestaShop 8.1 translation catalog!
The PrestaShop 8.1 translation catalog will be uploaded to Crowdin soon, meaning that you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to translate PrestaShop 8.1 into your language. And, as usual, an article will be released to list all particularities of these new strings and add a bit of context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - April</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-04-01-2023-04-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-04-01-2023-04-30/</guid>
      <description>As we enter May, let&amp;rsquo;s recap the key accomplishments within the PrestaShop project during April. We focused on vital security upgrades, namely PrestaShop 8.0.4 and 1.7.8.9, as well as putting the final touches on PrestaShop 8.1. A new project organization was also introduced, and the developer documentation received several updates. Read on to learn more about the latest developments in the PrestaShop project.
New project organization On April 19th, 2023, @eternoendless unveiled &amp;ldquo;a clearer, more transparent, more collaborative organization&amp;rdquo; for the project, that has been under development for the past few months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.4 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-4-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-4-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The fourth patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download! This release contains a few security fixes, so we recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
PrestaShop 8.0.4 is now available. This time there are three security fixes thanks to reports from community researchers. This release also contains a few bug fixes besides security fixes. The incorrect translation of pagination labels in products and combinations lists has been fixed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.9 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-9-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 16:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-9-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>Security patch for PrestaShop 1.7 is now available.
As part of the extended support policy for PrestaShop 1.7, which involves taking care of critical and security fixes for 1.7.8.x branch, we are releasing today a new patch for this version. This release fixes a few security issues reported by community researchers and upgrades some third-party libraries to their latest versions to ensure the stability and security of your shop.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Organization For The Open Source Project</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/a-new-organization-for-the-open-source-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/a-new-organization-for-the-open-source-project/</guid>
      <description>Today, I want to share the new organization for decision-making that will be set up for the PrestaShop project. We believe this organization will help our community grow, get even more involved, and work together in building a better PrestaShop, faster.
Why do we need a new organization? During the last years, we have been observing a steady growth in the number of community pull requests being merged every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - March 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-03-01-2023-03-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-03-01-2023-03-31/</guid>
      <description>In this Core Monthly, most important topics include new patch releases for PrestaShop 8, improvements in the developer documentation, data transparency policy, and more. Discover the latest updates on our ongoing projects and catch up on what our project members have been working on throughout the month of March.
Patch releases for PrestaShop 8 Two new versions for PrestaShop 8 are now available. 8.0.2 and 8.0.3 versions were both released a few weeks ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – March 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-march-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-march-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in March.
Project news 🎤 Contributor interviews are back! You’ve read that right – contributor interviews are back! The first interview sheds light on PrestaShop ambassador, merchant and contributor AmirRzd, who’s been contributing to the translation project for nearly 8 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - April 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-4-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-4-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the fourth time this year and streamed live on April 12th, 2023.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows: 00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 01:54 Project news: PrestaShop 8.0.2 and 8.0.3 releases 03:11 Project news: a new organization for the project 44:05 Demo: developer documentation improvements, by @kpodemski and @thomasnares You can use the timestamps to jump directly to the parts you want to watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop ambassador, merchant and contributor: meet AmirRzd</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-amirhossein/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-amirhossein/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who’s hiding behind a Crowdin username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project.
For the first interview of 2023, I interviewed Amirhossein, aka AmirRzd.
Ranked 31st on the top translator page, Amirhossein is a translator and proofreader on the Persian project.
Hello AmirRzd! :-) Can you tell us more about yourself?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing April PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-4-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-4-2023/</guid>
      <description>The fourth Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, April 12th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
Tomorrow we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the project, show you recent changes in the developer documentation, and, most importantly, @eternoendless will share exciting news about the project&amp;rsquo;s organization.
Remember that at the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions during the presentation or beforehand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.3 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-3-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-3-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The third patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download!
It was a rather bumpy road at the end because of issues we found during the release process, but here it is! In the newest patch version for PrestaShop 8 you can find a security improvement, and three fixes: one related to inaccurate wording in web services configuration, one which fixes the link to the user documentation in the installer, and one significant fix which improves how clearing the cache behaves in the software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - March 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-3-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-3-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the third time this year and streamed live on March 8th, 2023.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows: 00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 02:30 Project news: PrestaShop 8.0.2 will be available soon 03:48 Project news: PrestaShop 8.1-beta1 is now available 07:16 Project news: Google Analytics 4 for PrestaShop is now available 10:08 Demo: Developer documentation improvements, by @kpodemski 23:21 Demo: PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The second patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download!
Version 8.0.2 is available! In this patch, you can find over 20 bug fixes. As a patch version, 8.0.2 brings further goodness and stability to the 8.0 branch.
There were several noteworthy issues addressed in PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s 8.0.2 milestone. The upgrade mechanism had a problem where it couldn&amp;rsquo;t check if the PHP session had started on some webservers, which was reported by many community members.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
