<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - June 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-06-01-2025-06-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-06-01-2025-06-30/</guid>
      <description>We are back with yet another edition of the PrestaShop Core Monthly, your monthly digest of the PrestaShop codebase&amp;rsquo;s latest changes and news from the PrestaShop project.
PrestaShop 9.0.0 is out! 🎉 June marks the completion of one month since the PrestaShop 9.0.0 release, which is now available for download!
This release is a major milestone for the PrestaShop project, as it brings a lot of new features and improvements. We hope you will enjoy it as much as we do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.x is now in the extended support phase</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/82x-extended-support-phase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/82x-extended-support-phase/</guid>
      <description>Now that PrestaShop 9.0 is out, here is a focus on maintained branches of the PrestaShop project and what to expect.
Reminder: PrestaShop branching strategy In August 2015 PrestaShop adopted a new branching model for the project.
The model was refined over the years, for example with this developer documentation page about which bugs qualify for a patch version or the Backward Compatibility Promise that defines which changes can be introduced in a version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Speakers: PrestaShop Developer Conference Returns in November 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-speakers-prestashop-developer-conference-november-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-speakers-prestashop-developer-conference-november-2025/</guid>
      <description>We are very excited to announce that the call for presentations is now open for the third edition of the PrestaShop Developer Conference, happening on November 19, 2025 in Paris, France and virtually.
This event is your chance to engage with the tech community, participate in discussions, explore more practical solutions, and connect with other professionals from the community.
What is the PrestaShop Developer Conference? The PrestaShop Developer Conference is an event that brings together developers, product teams, and agency leaders to share insights, collaborate, and grow within the PrestaShop ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for contributions: hooks - initiative summary</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-hooks-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-contributions-hooks-summary/</guid>
      <description>During this year’s FoP Days, we launched a new community initiative focused on improving a specific part of the PrestaShop project: hooks. Rather than casting a wide net, we deliberately concentrated on a single topic. The goal was to make it easier and faster for contributors to submit changes, and for project members to validate them.
Why hooks? Hooks are essential for extending and customizing PrestaShop without overriding core files. They empower developers to build features in a clean, future-proof way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dominik Shaim Ulrich: contributing locally with a business providing hosting services</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/Dominik-Shaim-Ulrich-contributing-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/Dominik-Shaim-Ulrich-contributing-locally/</guid>
      <description>Ever wondered who&amp;rsquo;s behind a GitHub username? Now’s your chance to find out! Contributor interviews, like the one you are about to read, let you connect with the people driving the PrestaShop project forward.
Dear readers, meet Dominik from OpenServis.cz. Dominik, his company, and team members have been very active contributors to the project in the last few years. We wanted to get to know him and his company and understand what motivated him to contribute to the PrestaShop project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-available/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s finally here! PrestaShop 9 is available for download. This new version brings a modernized architecture, new developer tools, and powerful features designed to support the future of ecommerce.
PrestaShop 9 is here! After over two years of development and collaboration with the community, it&amp;rsquo;s time to take another major step forward. PrestaShop 9 is here. This version brings valuable improvements and marks a significant advancement for anyone looking to grow their business online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0 RC1 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-rc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-rc1/</guid>
      <description>The first Release Candidate of PrestaShop 9.0 is now available for testing. This is a significant milestone in the development cycle, and we encourage all users to test it thoroughly.
PrestaShop 9.0 Release Candidate 1 This version marks the final stage before the stable release. It includes all planned features, improvements, and changes introduced since the alpha and beta phases — including the new Hummingbird theme, Admin API, PHP 8.4 and Symfony 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSDevCon2024: Cybersecurity – What No One Dares to Say</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/PSDevCon2024-Cybersecurity-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/PSDevCon2024-Cybersecurity-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Application security is often a forgotten aspect of the digital world. Everyone agrees that it is essential, but no one really wants to face its consequences. Today, in this guest blog post, it&amp;rsquo;s time to share the truths that no one wants to say.
This PrestaShop Developer Conference 2024 guest blog post is authored by Vincent Guesnard from TouchWeb and summarizes the presentation given during the event.
1. Why does no one want to publish vulnerabilities?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codencode agency - contributing to work more sustainably over time</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/codencode-agency-contributor-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/codencode-agency-contributor-interview/</guid>
      <description>Ever wondered who&amp;rsquo;s behind a GitHub username? Now’s your chance to find out! Contributor interviews, like the one you are about to read, let you connect with the people driving the PrestaShop project forward.
Meet Paolo and CODENCODE Dear readers, meet Paolo from CODENCODE. Paolo has been one of the most active members of the community in recent months. We wanted to get to know him and his company and understand what motivated him to contribute to the PrestaShop project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - April 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-april-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-april-2025/</guid>
      <description>On April 23rd, 2025, we hosted another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project. This time we focused on two subjects, the Update Assistant release and the Targeted Contributions initiative.
PrestaShop Live Update - April 2025 In this session, I presented the latest news about the PrestaShop Project, including the Targeted Contributions initiative. This initiative is a great opportunity for contributors to work on projects that matter to them and the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update April 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-april-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-april-2025/</guid>
      <description>The upcoming PrestaShop Project Live Update will take place on Wednesday, April 23rd, 2025 at 4pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
This edition will focus on the latest developments in PrestaShop 8.2.2 and PrestaShop 9. We’ll discuss recent improvements, new features, and what these changes mean for the community and merchants.
A special highlight of this Live Update: we will be joined by PrestaShop SA Core Extensions team members responsible for the Update Assistant module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - March 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-03-01-2025-03-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-03-01-2025-03-31/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s new in the project? We&amp;rsquo;re ending the quarter strong! Project members with the help of the community have been working hard to prepare the next major release of PrestaShop. Release of the completely new version of the Auto Upgrade Update Assistant module, and that&amp;rsquo;s only a glimpse of the work done in March. Read on to learn more about the latest changes in the PrestaShop project.
Stay up to date with the latest developments in the PrestaShop project by reading the Core Monthly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOP Days 2025 - a wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/fop-days-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/fop-days-2025/</guid>
      <description>The 2025 edition of Friends of Presta (FOP) Days has come to an end, leaving behind two days of discussions, technical insights, and networking. Held on March 26-27 at Le Nida in Issy-les-Moulineaux, the event brought together developers, agencies, and ecommerce professionals from the PrestaShop community.
Collaboration and improving expertise Organized by Friends of Presta, a French non-profit association in the PrestaShop ecosystem, this event was all about collaboration and innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update Assistant module v7.0.0 is available (Autoupgrade)</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/autoupgrade-v7.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/autoupgrade-v7.0-release/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to introduce the latest major release of the Update Assistant module (formerly known as 1-Click Upgrade).
First launched in 2012, this module takes a significant leap forward with this new version, which is the result of several months of development and over 350 merged Pull Requests. As announced at the PrestaShop Developer Conference and on the Live Update in November 2024, this release pushes the boundaries of PrestaShop store updates even further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adapting to PrestaShop 9: Guzzle is gone, what&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/breaking-change-guzzle-removal-v9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/breaking-change-guzzle-removal-v9/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 9 is a major release, meaning it introduces breaking changes, including the removal of certain dependencies. One of the most impactful changes for module developers is the removal of Guzzle, a popular HTTP client that many modules relied on.
If your module depends on Guzzle, it will no longer be available by default in PrestaShop 9. In this article, we’ll explain why Guzzle was removed, what this means for your module, and how to migrate to a suitable alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
