<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PSDevCon2024: Cybersecurity – What No One Dares to Say</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/PSDevCon2024-Cybersecurity-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/PSDevCon2024-Cybersecurity-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Application security is often a forgotten aspect of the digital world. Everyone agrees that it is essential, but no one really wants to face its consequences. Today, in this guest blog post, it&amp;rsquo;s time to share the truths that no one wants to say.
This PrestaShop Developer Conference 2024 guest blog post is authored by Vincent Guesnard from TouchWeb and summarizes the presentation given during the event.
1. Why does no one want to publish vulnerabilities?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codencode agency - contributing to work more sustainably over time</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/codencode-agency-contributor-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/codencode-agency-contributor-interview/</guid>
      <description>Ever wondered who&amp;rsquo;s behind a GitHub username? Now’s your chance to find out! Contributor interviews, like the one you are about to read, let you connect with the people driving the PrestaShop project forward.
Meet Paolo and CODENCODE Dear readers, meet Paolo from CODENCODE. Paolo has been one of the most active members of the community in recent months. We wanted to get to know him and his company and understand what motivated him to contribute to the PrestaShop project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - April 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-april-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-april-2025/</guid>
      <description>On April 23rd, 2025, we hosted another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project. This time we focused on two subjects, the Update Assistant release and the Targeted Contributions initiative.
PrestaShop Live Update - April 2025 In this session, I presented the latest news about the PrestaShop Project, including the Targeted Contributions initiative. This initiative is a great opportunity for contributors to work on projects that matter to them and the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update April 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-april-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-april-2025/</guid>
      <description>The upcoming PrestaShop Project Live Update will take place on Wednesday, April 23rd, 2025 at 4pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
This edition will focus on the latest developments in PrestaShop 8.2.2 and PrestaShop 9. We’ll discuss recent improvements, new features, and what these changes mean for the community and merchants.
A special highlight of this Live Update: we will be joined by PrestaShop SA Core Extensions team members responsible for the Update Assistant module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - March 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-03-01-2025-03-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-03-01-2025-03-31/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s new in the project? We&amp;rsquo;re ending the quarter strong! Project members with the help of the community have been working hard to prepare the next major release of PrestaShop. Release of the completely new version of the Auto Upgrade Update Assistant module, and that&amp;rsquo;s only a glimpse of the work done in March. Read on to learn more about the latest changes in the PrestaShop project.
Stay up to date with the latest developments in the PrestaShop project by reading the Core Monthly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOP Days 2025 - a wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/fop-days-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/fop-days-2025/</guid>
      <description>The 2025 edition of Friends of Presta (FOP) Days has come to an end, leaving behind two days of discussions, technical insights, and networking. Held on March 26-27 at Le Nida in Issy-les-Moulineaux, the event brought together developers, agencies, and ecommerce professionals from the PrestaShop community.
Collaboration and improving expertise Organized by Friends of Presta, a French non-profit association in the PrestaShop ecosystem, this event was all about collaboration and innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update Assistant module v7.0.0 is available (Autoupgrade)</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/autoupgrade-v7.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/autoupgrade-v7.0-release/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to introduce the latest major release of the Update Assistant module (formerly known as 1-Click Upgrade).
First launched in 2012, this module takes a significant leap forward with this new version, which is the result of several months of development and over 350 merged Pull Requests. As announced at the PrestaShop Developer Conference and on the Live Update in November 2024, this release pushes the boundaries of PrestaShop store updates even further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adapting to PrestaShop 9: Guzzle is gone, what&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/breaking-change-guzzle-removal-v9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/breaking-change-guzzle-removal-v9/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 9 is a major release, meaning it introduces breaking changes, including the removal of certain dependencies. One of the most impactful changes for module developers is the removal of Guzzle, a popular HTTP client that many modules relied on.
If your module depends on Guzzle, it will no longer be available by default in PrestaShop 9. In this article, we’ll explain why Guzzle was removed, what this means for your module, and how to migrate to a suitable alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the community at the FOP (Friends of Presta) Days in Paris</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/friends-of-presta-days-in-paris-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/friends-of-presta-days-in-paris-2025/</guid>
      <description>The Friends of Presta (FOP) Days is an event for PrestaShop and open source ecommerce enthusiasts. Taking place on March 26-27, 2025, at Le Nida, Issy-les-Moulineaux, in the Paris region, this event is dedicated to open source collaboration, technical innovation, and business insights dedicated to the PrestaShop community. You will be able to meet other professionals, exchange ideas, and contribute to the community&amp;rsquo;s future.
Friends of Presta and the PrestaShop ecosystem This event is organized by Friends of Presta, which is a French non-profit and brings together developers, integrators and agencies, among other types of members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reworking the &#34;Update Assistant&#34; Module V7: Our Experience</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/reworking-the-update-assistant-module-v7-our-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/reworking-the-update-assistant-module-v7-our-experience/</guid>
      <description>Let’s face it—our Update Assistant module was messy. The front-end was confusing, the user experience was challenging, and even minor adjustments were a little more complex than what we would have liked.
As part of the Seamless Upgrade &amp;amp; Extensibility squad, one of our key missions is to improve the reliability of PrestaShop upgrades. And to do that, we knew the Update Assistant module needed more than just a few patches—it needed a complete reinvention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - March 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-march-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/live-update-march-2025/</guid>
      <description>On March 5th, 2025, we hosted another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project where we shared more information about PrestaShop 9 Beta 1. We also took a sneak peek at what&amp;rsquo;s coming to PrestaShop 9.1 thanks to a special guest from PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s product team.
PrestaShop Live Update - March 2025 In this session, we focused on PrestaShop 9 Beta 1, stressing the need for developers to prepare for potential breaking changes and major updates within the PrestaShop ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update March 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-march-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/upcoming-live-update-march-2025/</guid>
      <description>The second Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2025 will be hosted on Wednesday, March 5th, 2025 at 4pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
Join us for the upcoming Live Update where we will provide an in-depth walkthrough of the changes under the hood introduced in PrestaShop 9 Beta 1. This session will be particularly valuable for those looking to adapt their PrestaShop solutions or solutions integrating with PrestaShop to the new version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.1 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch for PrestaShop 8.2 is available. This release contains many bug fixes and improvements, including a new way to handle module filtering in the front office.
We are excited to announce the release of PrestaShop 8.2.1, a new patch that not only addresses a significant number of bugs reported by our dedicated community and Quality Assurance team but also introduces a valuable new feature. This feature allows module developers to filter the display of other modules in PrestaShop, helping them avoid the use of overrides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0 beta is now available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The first beta version of PrestaShop 9.0 is now available for testing. This version includes many new features and improvements, a new Hummingbird theme, a new Admin API, PHP 8.4 and Symfony 6.4 support, many bug fixes, and a significant codebase cleanup. Read on to learn more about the new features and improvements.
PrestaShop 9.0 beta 1 In June, when we released the alpha 1 version, we also published the first overview of new features and improvements that PrestaShop 9 will bring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - January</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-01-01-2025-01-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-01-01-2025-01-31/</guid>
      <description>We are back with the first Core Monthly of 2025! 🎉 Discover the latest updates in the PrestaShop project, including new releases, project highlights, community contributions, and more.
Want to stay up to date with the latest developments in the PrestaShop project? Core Monthly is your go-to source for the most important news, updates, and changes in the project. In this edition, we will show you what happened in January 2025.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
