<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>legal on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/legal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in legal on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 12:30:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/legal/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to make your module compliant with PrestaShop’s Official GDPR Compliance Module</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/module/how-to-make-your-module-compliant-with-prestashop-official-gdpr-compliance-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 12:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/module/how-to-make-your-module-compliant-with-prestashop-official-gdpr-compliance-module/</guid>
      <description>Everybody must already know, there are a few steps to follow in order to make your module compliant with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)
Add a consent confirmation checkbox if the module collects personal data Allow users to ask for total removal of their personal data Allow users to ask for a comprehensive export of their personal data owned by the site The Official GDPR Compliance Module by PrestaShop will be available soon, and it provides you with 4 new hooks to help you meet these requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting the Advanced EU Compliance module</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/advanced-eu-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/advanced-eu-compliance/</guid>
      <description>As good news never come alone, let us introduce you to the new module that is included natively in PrestaShop from 1.6.1.0 version: Advanced EU Compliance.
Why did we create this module? E-commerce evolves at a very fast pace, and the more it evolves the more new legislations are appearing to frame it. These legislations can - over time - become a real headache for e-shop owners, who have to adapt their website themselves, or to hire someone to do it for them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
