<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>psdevcon on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/psdevcon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in psdevcon on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/psdevcon/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference 2025 - Filmed Morning Sessions and Q&amp;A Now Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/prestashop-developer-conference-2025-keynote-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2026/prestashop-developer-conference-2025-keynote-sessions/</guid>
      <description>The PrestaShop Developer Conference happened a few weeks ago, and this year&amp;rsquo;s edition brought together our vibrant community for a day packed with technical insights, product announcements, and open discussions about the future of PrestaShop.
Over the coming weeks, we&amp;rsquo;ll be publishing a series of blog posts, similar to this one, diving into the event’s sessions, giving you insights and takeaways. Each post will spotlight different talks and themes from the conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference 2025 - Event Recap</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-developer-conference-2025-event-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-developer-conference-2025-event-recap/</guid>
      <description>On November 19, 2025, the PrestaShop developer community convened in Paris, and online via a global livestream, for the third PrestaShop Developer Conference. The program featured hands-on sessions, live demonstrations, and expert talks, alongside a major announcement. Attendees deepened their understanding of the PrestaShop ecosystem, gained project information, and explored practical advancements they can apply in their daily work.
Highlights from a day of insightful sessions on the Main Stage Throughout the day, the Main Stage featured expert-led talks from the PrestaShop community, unveiling a major announcement regarding MCP and also sessions regarding AI, PrestaShop Enterprise, PrestaShop Core, deployment, Hummingbird and call for contributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference 2025: Register now!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/register-for-prestashop-developer-conference-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/register-for-prestashop-developer-conference-2025/</guid>
      <description>The ecommerce world is advancing at an exciting pace, creating fresh opportunities for developers and businesses. That’s why we are excited to announce the third edition of the PrestaShop Developer Conference, taking place on November 19, 2025, in Paris and, for the first time, online.
Why attend the conference? The PrestaShop Developer Conference is more than just a day of talks, it’s a hub for passionate developers to connect, collaborate, and learn from leading voices in the PrestaShop community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Speakers: PrestaShop Developer Conference Returns in November 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-speakers-prestashop-developer-conference-november-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-speakers-prestashop-developer-conference-november-2025/</guid>
      <description>We are very excited to announce that the call for presentations is now open for the third edition of the PrestaShop Developer Conference, taking place in Paris on November 19, 2025, in a hybrid format, with both onsite and online attendance options.
This event is your chance to engage with the tech community, participate in discussions, explore more practical solutions, and connect with other professionals from the community.
What is the PrestaShop Developer Conference?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSDevCon2024: Cybersecurity – What No One Dares to Say</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/PSDevCon2024-Cybersecurity-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/PSDevCon2024-Cybersecurity-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Application security is often a forgotten aspect of the digital world. Everyone agrees that it is essential, but no one really wants to face its consequences. Today, in this guest blog post, it&amp;rsquo;s time to share the truths that no one wants to say.
This PrestaShop Developer Conference 2024 guest blog post is authored by Vincent Guesnard from TouchWeb and summarizes the presentation given during the event.
1. Why does no one want to publish vulnerabilities?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSDevCon 2024 - testing and analyzing your PrestaShop modules automatically</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/testing-and-analyzing-your-prestashop-modules-automatically/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/testing-and-analyzing-your-prestashop-modules-automatically/</guid>
      <description>During the PrestaShop Developer Conference 2024, Jonathan Danse presented methods for automatically testing and analyzing modules, ensuring their quality and reliability. In this guest article, Jonathan shares the key points from his conference and offers practical advice. Learn how to ensure high-performing modules with every deployment.
You can find the sources for the module created in this article on the following GitHub repository: PrestaEdit/modulenine. Jonathan, the floor is now yours!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSDevCon 2024 - PUIK (PrestaShop UI Kit) - The new UI kit from PrestaShop</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/puik-the-new-ui-kit-from-prestashop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/puik-the-new-ui-kit-from-prestashop/</guid>
      <description>During the second PrestaShop Developer Conference on November 6, 2024, I was able to introduce PUIK (PrestaShop UI Kit) to participants. This blog post provides a written summary of the presentation. During the talk, the audience gained a clearer understanding of PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s UI Kit, based on the new PrestaShop Design System. Learn how this library aims to provide a complete set of reusable components for the entire PrestaShop ecosystem. The GitHub repository is available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Synopsis - PrestaShop Developer Conference 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-developer-conference-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-developer-conference-2024/</guid>
      <description>On November 6, 2024, the PrestaShop developer community gathered in Paris for a day of learning and networking at the second PrestaShop Developer Conference. The agenda was filled with insightful sessions and demonstrations. The event provided a platform to grow and learn more about PrestaShop’s ecosystem, get project information as well as explore advancements usable in daily professional activities.
Insightful sessions during the day Throughout the day, the main stage hosted presentations by experts in the PrestaShop community, who shared insights on optimizing performance, leveraging advanced new Admin APIs, implementing continuous integration and workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris: Synopsis Of The Day</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-2023/</guid>
      <description>The European community of PrestaShop developers gathered to talk code, commerce and also open source in Paris, on November 30, 2023, at the PrestaShop Developer Conference. It was so exciting to see approximately 150 people come to follow conferences and other technical presentations, as well as network during the day.
PrestaShop Developer Conference 2023 The event opened its doors at 9AM and very quickly the venue filled up. Attendees were able to enjoy breakfast before diving into the day&amp;rsquo;s introduction in the main room.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
