<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PrestaShop on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/PrestaShop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PrestaShop on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/PrestaShop/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 8.2.2 is here! This latest patch version brings a range of updates, addressing reported issues and introducing enhancements to improve the platform for merchants and developers alike.
We are happy to announce the release of PrestaShop 8.2.2, a patch version that not only resolves numerous bugs reported by our dedicated community and Quality Assurance team but also introduces some improvements.
As part of the Call for Contributions challenge, PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Speakers: PrestaShop Developer Conference Returns in November 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-speakers-prestashop-developer-conference-november-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-speakers-prestashop-developer-conference-november-2025/</guid>
      <description>We are very excited to announce that the call for presentations is now open for the third edition of the PrestaShop Developer Conference, taking place in Paris on November 19, 2025, in a hybrid format, with both onsite and online attendance options.
This event is your chance to engage with the tech community, participate in discussions, explore more practical solutions, and connect with other professionals from the community.
What is the PrestaShop Developer Conference?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-available/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s finally here! PrestaShop 9 is available for download. This new version brings a modernized architecture, new developer tools, and powerful features designed to support the future of ecommerce.
PrestaShop 9 is here! After over two years of development and collaboration with the community, it&amp;rsquo;s time to take another major step forward. PrestaShop 9 is here. This version brings valuable improvements and marks a significant advancement for anyone looking to grow their business online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0 RC1 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-rc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-rc1/</guid>
      <description>The first Release Candidate of PrestaShop 9.0 is now available for testing. This is a significant milestone in the development cycle, and we encourage all users to test it thoroughly.
PrestaShop 9.0 Release Candidate 1 This version marks the final stage before the stable release. It includes all planned features, improvements, and changes introduced since the alpha and beta phases — including the new Hummingbird theme, Admin API, PHP 8.4 and Symfony 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.1 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch for PrestaShop 8.2 is available. This release contains many bug fixes and improvements, including a new way to handle module filtering in the front office.
We are excited to announce the release of PrestaShop 8.2.1, a new patch that not only addresses a significant number of bugs reported by our dedicated community and Quality Assurance team but also introduces a valuable new feature. This feature allows module developers to filter the display of other modules in PrestaShop, helping them avoid the use of overrides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0 beta is now available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The first beta version of PrestaShop 9.0 is now available for testing. This version includes many new features and improvements, a new Hummingbird theme, a new Admin API, PHP 8.4 and Symfony 6.4 support, many bug fixes, and a significant codebase cleanup. Read on to learn more about the new features and improvements.
PrestaShop 9.0 beta 1 In June, when we released the alpha 1 version, we also published the first overview of new features and improvements that PrestaShop 9 will bring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Injection attacks alert and security enhancements for PrestaShop</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/sql-injection-attacks-alert-and-security-enhancements-for-prestashop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/sql-injection-attacks-alert-and-security-enhancements-for-prestashop/</guid>
      <description>A recent wave of attacks has targeted PrestaShop stores, leveraging SQL Injection vulnerabilities in third-party modules to compromise data security. Malicious actors exploit these vulnerabilities to inject harmful code into the PrestaShop database, enabling the theft of sensitive customer information by loading unauthorized JavaScript scripts.
According to the investigation, this vulnerability is not in the PrestaShop core but in third-party modules. Stores using a custom database prefix and without SQL Injection-vulnerable modules installed should remain unaffected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Project Newsletter Launch: Stay Informed!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/introducing-prestashop-project-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/introducing-prestashop-project-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>At PrestaShop, we are always looking for ways to strengthen our relationship with the community. In line with this, we are thrilled to announce the launch of the PrestaShop Project Newsletter, a new initiative designed to bring you technical insights, exclusive updates, and educational content like never before.
The launch of this newsletter is happening now, and the timing is no coincidence! With the PrestaShop Developer Conference just around the corner on November 6, 2024, we want to highlight our commitment to the technical community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Register Now for the PrestaShop Developer Conference 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/register-for-the-prestashop-developer-conference-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/register-for-the-prestashop-developer-conference-2024/</guid>
      <description>The world of ecommerce is constantly evolving, and staying on top of the latest trends and innovations is essential for developers and businesses. That’s why we are thrilled to invite you to the second edition of the PrestaShop Developer Conference, taking place on November 6, 2024, in Paris.
Why Attend the Conference? The PrestaShop Developer Conference is more than just a series of presentations - it’s a space where passionate developers come together to exchange ideas, learn from one another, and engage with some of the leading voices in the PrestaShop community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-2-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-2-0-available/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been decided to release a new minor version of PrestaShop 8.2. This version includes a few improvements, as well as bug fixes.
What&amp;rsquo;s new in PrestaShop 8.2? PrestaShop 8.2 is a minor version that includes a few improvements, as well as bug fixes, and it is relatively small compared to the previous minor versions. Here are some highlights.
Improvements Correctly checking overrides during module installation
PrestaShop used to check for overrides during module installation, but the process didn’t fully block installation if a conflicting override was found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second PrestaShop Developer Conference - Participate as a Speaker</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/Second-PrestaShop-Developer-Conference-Participate-as-Speaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 09:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/Second-PrestaShop-Developer-Conference-Participate-as-Speaker/</guid>
      <description>Are you a passionate PrestaShop developer or enthusiast? We are happy to announce that the call for presentations is now open for the second edition of the PrestaShop Developer Conference, happening on November 6, 2024 in Paris, France. This event offers a prime opportunity to engage in developer discussions, better understand solutions, and connect with fellow community members.
What is this event about? The PrestaShop Developer Conference empowers the developer community within the PrestaShop ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.7 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-7-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-7-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A new patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is now available! This release includes several significant improvements and numerous bug fixes. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore these updates in detail.
PrestaShop 8.1.7 is now available. This release addresses several bugs and brings various improvements.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to backup before. Upgrade is possible using the latest version of the 1-Click Upgrade module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9 Alpha 1 is Available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-9-alpha1-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-9-alpha1-available/</guid>
      <description>Here it is. The first public alpha of PrestaShop 9 is available. We decided it was time to share with you the first results of our work on PrestaShop 9.
Please note that this version is in the early stages of development. To achieve a stable release, we anticipate several months of further work. As we are prior to the feature-freeze phase, the features and content of PrestaShop 9 are subject to change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying releases with a single Zip</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/new-zip-distribution-channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/new-zip-distribution-channel/</guid>
      <description>As we continue to evolve and adapt to the global e-commerce landscape, we are implementing changes to streamline our operations and enhance our project’s trajectory. In 2022, we aimed to make PrestaShop a company-neutral open source project. Today, while keeping the project neutral, we are changing how we distribute the PrestaShop solution, starting with the upcoming 9.0 release.
One release, one Zip As you know, versions are distributed as two separate Zips, one on GitHub and a later one on prestashop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.6 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-6-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-6-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A new patch version for PrestaShop 8.1 is now available. This maintenance release fixes 2 security issues.
The security patch for version 8.1 of PrestaShop is now available. It is recommended that you upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to create a backup before. You can upgrade to the latest version using the 1-Click Upgrade module. There are no database changes in this release.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
