<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ColineGinestet on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/ColineGinestet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ColineGinestet on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 11:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/ColineGinestet/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7 modules - Latest releases &amp; updates</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1.7-modules-latest-releases-and-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1.7-modules-latest-releases-and-updates/</guid>
      <description>All product and core teams have been quite busy over the past 6 months, working hard on delivering PrestaShop 1.7.6, but not only! We have also worked on bringing new features and improving the 1.7 version through our PrestaShop modules.
The PrestaShop software is usually seen as a single “brick” and users tend to forget that it is actually accompanied by more than 80 built-in modules, which bring many features to your store such as design, marketing and statistics tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update your store for GDPR</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/update-your-prestashop-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/update-your-prestashop-store/</guid>
      <description>Almost all of our merchants have to comply with the law. That’s why we have released the GDPR official module by PrestaShop (1.6 and 1.7 live, 1.5 to be released very soon), helping merchants and contributors to comply with the law.
Do you have a PrestaShop version 1.7 store? The module is already available in your back-office
Introduction As already explained on our Prestashop.com blog and on build.prestashop.com, the GDPR has and ready to be installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop &amp; GDPR</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-and-gdpr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-and-gdpr/</guid>
      <description>As you are probably already aware, in a few weeks (May 25th of this year) the new european law on personal data protection will come into effect.
As an e-commerce software, our goal is to help merchants all around the world to sell their products while complying with legal regulations. This is why it is important for us to provide a tool which will allow your shop to become GDPR compliant.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
