<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MehdiBadrani on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/MehdiBadrani/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MehdiBadrani on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 11:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/MehdiBadrani/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>E2E testing from the trenches: Our new approach</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/E2E-testing-from-the-trenches-our-new-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/E2E-testing-from-the-trenches-our-new-approach/</guid>
      <description>This article is intended to catch you up with the most important changes in our testing framework. Terms, architecture, tools, and approaches to E2E testing in Prestashop in 2019.
It combines many good practices in testing well working at Prestashop where we implemented different testing solutions for different projects and contexts. I invite you to have a look on our previous article to refresh your memory.
But what are E2E tests?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PrestaShop Test Framework</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-test-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-test-framework/</guid>
      <description>Last time we announced a new suite of functional tests to ensure our software quality, today we are proud to present you our new feature, the PrestaShop Test Framework!
It is a cool toolkit like a Swiss knife which will help to save a lot of time by running at least 50 automated functional tests on your browser&amp;hellip; and this is only the beginning! It makes easier to create basic acceptance testing when adding Addons, submitting pull requests or making some customizations on your Prestashop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
