<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>coffrep on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/coffrep/</link>
    <description>Recent content in coffrep on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/coffrep/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Event Synopsis - PrestaShop Developer Conference 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-developer-conference-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-developer-conference-2024/</guid>
      <description>On November 6, 2024, the PrestaShop developer community gathered in Paris for a day of learning and networking at the second PrestaShop Developer Conference. The agenda was filled with insightful sessions and demonstrations. The event provided a platform to grow and learn more about PrestaShop’s ecosystem, get project information as well as explore advancements usable in daily professional activities.
Insightful sessions during the day Throughout the day, the main stage hosted presentations by experts in the PrestaShop community, who shared insights on optimizing performance, leveraging advanced new Admin APIs, implementing continuous integration and workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OW2 Webinar - PrestaShop Presentation on September 26</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/OW2WebinarPrestaShopPresentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 09:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/OW2WebinarPrestaShopPresentation/</guid>
      <description>On September 26, the OW2 organization will hold a webinar, presented in part by Clément Désiles from PrestaShop.
During this event, PrestaShop will be presenting alongside ALLMA, a project based on the /e/OS fork of Android and integrating the best of open source modern LLMs. The project is sponsored by a European fund, NGI Search. Pierre-Yves Gibello, OW2’s CEO, will be introducing the webinar at the beginning of the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris: Synopsis Of The Day</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-2023/</guid>
      <description>The European community of PrestaShop developers gathered to talk code, commerce and also open source in Paris, on November 30, 2023, at the PrestaShop Developer Conference. It was so exciting to see approximately 150 people come to follow conferences and other technical presentations, as well as network during the day.
PrestaShop Developer Conference 2023 The event opened its doors at 9AM and very quickly the venue filled up. Attendees were able to enjoy breakfast before diving into the day&amp;rsquo;s introduction in the main room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris: Program and Registration</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-agenda-registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-agenda-registration/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re a PrestaShop developer or enthusiast looking to broaden your knowledge and connect with fellow community members, the PrestaShop Developer Conference is the event for you.
Scheduled for November 30, 2023, in Paris, France, the conference promises an in-depth exploration of technical topics, innovative solutions, and ample opportunities to network and engage with peers who share your passion for PrestaShop. We&amp;rsquo;re also very happy to go over the recent unveiling of the agenda, packed with compelling sessions and engaging activities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
