<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>community on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in community on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/community/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Announcing December PrestaShop Project Public Demo</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/upcoming-demo-9-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/upcoming-demo-9-2022/</guid>
      <description>Friendly reminder, that the public demo for the PrestaShop Project will happen tomorrow, on Wednesday, December 14th, 2022 at 4pm CET!
I expect to share with you project news. Additionally, a few demos are planned:
Availability labels for product combinations, by @Hlavtox New options for discountinued products, by @Hlavtox Better managing the order state for backorder products, by @Hlavtox At the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions beforehand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing: PrestaShop Project Office Hours</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/office-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/office-hours/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, a new initiative was started: PrestaShop Project Office Hours.
The concept is simple: once a week, project members make themselves available to the community to discuss topics directly related to the PrestaShop open source project.
So far, three meetings have been held which were a chance to discuss a number of topics:
project structure and processes helping finish and merge some PRs from the community multi-store features the future of core architecture And hopefully more discussions will come during the upcoming meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Project Public Demo - November 2022 Session</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/public-demo-8-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/public-demo-8-2022/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s public demo was held for the eighth time this year and streamed live on November 9th, 2022.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows:
00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 01:55 Project news: PrestaShop 8.0 is available! 03:17 Demo: introducing new back office API by @atomiix 11:47 Demo: PrestaShop 8.1 and beyond by @FabienVallon 24:36 Questions &amp;amp; answers (do you have any questions? Fill this form and we&amp;rsquo;ll answer in the next session).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing November PrestaShop Project Public Demo</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/upcoming-demo-8-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/upcoming-demo-8-2022/</guid>
      <description>Friendly reminder, that the public demo for the PrestaShop Project from the maintainers team will happen next week, on Wednesday, November 9th, 2022 at 4pm CET!
We expect to share with you project news and present two topics:
Introducing: new back office API, by @atomiix PrestaShop 8.1 and beyond, by @FabienVallon At the end of every meeting, we hold a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions beforehand. If you have some, about things related to the open source project, feel free to ask using this form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest and PrestaShop: how you can participate in this 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/hacktoberfest-2022-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/hacktoberfest-2022-started/</guid>
      <description>October is now here and Hacktoberfest, a month-long celebration of open source software, has started. We have recently written an article about the event, how you can get involved and all the different rules. You can know more in our Hacktoberfest 2022 article.
In a few words, participation is very simple: people are encouraged to create at least 4 pull requests for open source projects on GitHub.
How to get started If you are wondering how to get started, we are listing in this blog post issues that could be a good starting point for new contributors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Project Public Demo - October 2022 Session</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/public-demo-7-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/public-demo-7-2022/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s public demo was held for the seventh time this year and streamed live on October 5th, 2022.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows:
00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 02:11 Project news: PrestaShop 8.0 - status update 03:12 Project news: Hacktoberfest 2022 05:10 Project news: Q&amp;amp;A - new format 06:04 Project news: new members in the project 06:55 Pull Requests overview 17:43 Demo: upgrade from 1.7.8 to your own PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing October PrestaShop Project Public Demo</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/upcoming-demo-7-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/upcoming-demo-7-2022/</guid>
      <description>Friendly reminder, that the public demo for the PrestaShop Project from the maintainers team will happen next week, on Wednesday, October 5th, 2022 at 4pm CEST!
We expect to share with you project news and present one topic:
Update from PrestaShop 1.7.8 to 8.0 using autoupgrade module, by @kpodemski At the end of every meeting, we hold a Q&amp;amp;A session. This month we decided to start gathering questions beforehand. If you have any questions about things related to the open source project feel free to ask using this form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest 2022</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/hacktoberfest-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/hacktoberfest-2022/</guid>
      <description>With the month of October coming in a few days, be prepared for Hacktoberfest, a month-long celebration of open source software. The online event has been happening every October for the last 9 years and is sponsored by the American cloud hosting company DigitalOcean. How can you participate? Very simple: people are encouraged to create at least 4 pull requests for open source projects on GitHub.
If you are not sure how to get involved in open source projects and where to start, Hacktoberfest might be the perfect opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing September PrestaShop Public OSS Demo</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/upcoming-demo-6-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/upcoming-demo-6-2022/</guid>
      <description>Friendly reminder, that the public PrestaShop demo from the maintainers team will happen next week, on Wednesday, September 7, 2022 at 4pm CEST!
We expect to share with you project news and present 2 topics:
How could we implement the PrestaShop hooks system in Vue components? @NeOMakinG New features for developers in PrestaShop 8 @kpodemski Join us on YouTube! The session will be kept in record on YouTube, so that even if you can&amp;rsquo;t attend to the live stream, you will still be able to catch up later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing July PrestaShop Public OSS Demo</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/upcoming-demo-5-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/upcoming-demo-5-2022/</guid>
      <description>Friendly reminder, that the public PrestaShop demo from the maintainers team will happen next week, on Wednesday, July 6, 2022 at 4pm CEST!
We expect to share with you project news and present 2 very interesting topics:
New password policy by @matks New product page by @jolelievre and @MatShir In addition, @eshraw will present you the new initiative from the Product Team, &amp;ldquo;Product discovery for v8.1 and above&amp;rdquo;.
Join us on YouTube!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jonathan Danse: module developer and one of the first contributors</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/contributor-interview-jonathan-danse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/contributor-interview-jonathan-danse/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. This month, meet Jonathan Danse, aka PrestaEdit.
Jonathan is a module developer. He’s also one of the first contributors to the PrestaShop project. It all started, somewhat by chance, during a job interview 12 years ago. In this article, Jonathan talks about his experience with PrestaShop, his work as a module developer, and his dedication to the open source project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing June PrestaShop Public OSS Demo</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/upcoming-demo-4-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/upcoming-demo-4-2022/</guid>
      <description>Friendly reminder, after one month break the next session of the public PrestaShop demo from the maintainers team will happen this week, on Wednesday, June 1, 2022 at 4pm CEST!
We expect to share with you project news and present 4 topics:
Update on the Horizontal migration by @matks and @tegbessou PHP 8.1 compatibility by @atomiix Improvements for Email alerts module by @marsaldev Update on the Hummingbird theme by @Hlavtox Join us on YouTube!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julius Zukauskas: Partner Agency Employee and Top Contributor</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/contributor-interview-julius-zukauskas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/contributor-interview-julius-zukauskas/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. This month, meet Julius Zukauskas, aka zuk3975.
Julius comes from Lithuania. He works at Invertus, an ecommerce agency with a Platinum partner status in the PrestaShop Agency Partner program. Half of his time is dedicated to the open source project, and more specifically to the Symfony migration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merchant, freelance developer, and top contributor: Daniel Hlaváček’s experience with the PrestaShop project</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/contributor-interview-daniel-hlavacek/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/contributor-interview-daniel-hlavacek/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. This month, meet Daniel Hlaváček, aka Hlavtox.
Daniel spends most of his time managing his family business’ online stores. The rest of the time, he works as a freelance developer for 10 clients, whose stores are all based on PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing April PrestaShop Public OSS Demo</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/upcoming-demo-3-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/upcoming-demo-3-2022/</guid>
      <description>Friendly reminder, the next session of the public PrestaShop demo from the maintainers team will happen Wednesday, April 6, 2022 at 4pm CEST!
We expect to share with you project news and present 3 topics:
New distribution API @atomiix Front office improvements by @Hlavtox Current hummingbird theme state by @NeOMakinG Join us on YouTube! The session will be kept in record on YouTube, so that even if you can&amp;rsquo;t attend to the live stream, you will still be able to catch up later.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
