<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>community on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in community on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/community/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Announcing May PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-5-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-5-2023/</guid>
      <description>The fifth Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, May 17th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
We will go over the latest project updates, take a look at recent changes made in the developer documentation, and share some exciting news about PrestaShop 9.0.
Remember that at the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions during the presentation or beforehand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louis Authie: Freelancer, Contributor and Author</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-louis-authie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-louis-authie/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who’s hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project.
This month, meet Louis Authie, aka LouisAUTHIE.
Louis is a freelance full stack developer at Web Helpers, with over 120 contributions on GitHub. He’s also a member of Friends of Presta, an association that gathers a community of developers and integrators around the open source ecommerce solution PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Organization For The Open Source Project</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/a-new-organization-for-the-open-source-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/a-new-organization-for-the-open-source-project/</guid>
      <description>Today, I want to share the new organization for decision-making that will be set up for the PrestaShop project. We believe this organization will help our community grow, get even more involved, and work together in building a better PrestaShop, faster.
Why do we need a new organization? During the last years, we have been observing a steady growth in the number of community pull requests being merged every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - April 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-4-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-4-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the fourth time this year and streamed live on April 12th, 2023.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows: 00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 01:54 Project news: PrestaShop 8.0.2 and 8.0.3 releases 03:11 Project news: a new organization for the project 44:05 Demo: developer documentation improvements, by @kpodemski and @thomasnares You can use the timestamps to jump directly to the parts you want to watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop ambassador, merchant and contributor: meet AmirRzd</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-amirhossein/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-amirhossein/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who’s hiding behind a Crowdin username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project.
For the first interview of 2023, I interviewed Amirhossein, aka AmirRzd.
Ranked 31st on the top translator page, Amirhossein is a translator and proofreader on the Persian project.
Hello AmirRzd! :-) Can you tell us more about yourself?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing April PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-4-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-4-2023/</guid>
      <description>The fourth Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, April 12th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
Tomorrow we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the project, show you recent changes in the developer documentation, and, most importantly, @eternoendless will share exciting news about the project&amp;rsquo;s organization.
Remember that at the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions during the presentation or beforehand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - March 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-3-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-3-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the third time this year and streamed live on March 8th, 2023.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows: 00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 02:30 Project news: PrestaShop 8.0.2 will be available soon 03:48 Project news: PrestaShop 8.1-beta1 is now available 07:16 Project news: Google Analytics 4 for PrestaShop is now available 10:08 Demo: Developer documentation improvements, by @kpodemski 23:21 Demo: PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing March PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-3-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-3-2023/</guid>
      <description>The third Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, March 8th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
Tomorrow we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss what happened in the project in February. We&amp;rsquo;ll show you recent changes in the developer documentation, and some of the new features from PrestaShop 8.1.
At the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions beforehand. If you have some, about things related to the open source project, feel free to ask using this form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - February 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-2-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-2-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the second time this year and streamed live on February 8th, 2023.
Demos that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to miss! Safe to say, this was one of the best, if not the best, live updates we ever held. During February&amp;rsquo;s event, we had a chance to see one of the most popular PrestaShop community projects. Integration between PrestaShop and Vue Storefront created by BinShops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing February PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-2-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-2-2023/</guid>
      <description>The second Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, February 8th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
We prepared some very exciting demos for all of you!
New product page in PrestaShop 8.1, by @MatShir and @jolelievre PrestaShop x Vuestorefront integration, by @samberrry Faceted search module evolution, by @Hlavtox At the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions beforehand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Discussions are now enabled in the PrestaShop Project!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/github-discussions-are-now-enabled-in-the-prestashop-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/github-discussions-are-now-enabled-in-the-prestashop-project/</guid>
      <description>Today, GitHub Discussions are being enabled for the PrestaShop Project. This feature will provide a more organized and easily accessible way for community members to collaborate, ask questions, and share ideas.
What are GitHub Discussions? GitHub Discussions is a new feature in GitHub that provides a space for community members to discuss directly on the project’s GitHub page, similarly to traditional forum boards. This feature is a great way to ask questions, share ideas, and collaborate with other community members, and it has proven its value in other open-source communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - January 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-1-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-1-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s first live update was held for the first time this year and streamed live on January 11th, 2023.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows:
00:00 Beginning of the session: the introduction 02:50 Project news: PrestaShop 8.0.1 is available 03:26 Project news: Autoupgrade 4.15 is available 07:01 Demo: Hummingbird theme, news &amp;amp; walkthrough, by @NeOMaking 30:05 Demo: WebP and Avif in PrestaShop: multiple image format generation, by @matthieu-rolland 38:16 Questions &amp;amp; answers (do you have any questions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing January PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-1-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-1-2023/</guid>
      <description>The first Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, January 11th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube! Public Demo is now called Live update, as it is planned to experiment with formats other than you could see in previous sessions, like live coding, interviews, etc.
This time, as always, I expect to share with you project news, and a couple of demos are planned:
Overview of the Hummingbird theme, by @NeOMaking WebP and Avif in PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Project Public Demo - December 2022 Session</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/public-demo-9-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/public-demo-9-2022/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s public demo was held for the ninth time this year and streamed live on December 14th, 2022.
The session&amp;rsquo;s agenda was as follows:
00:00 Beginning of the session: introduction 02:24 Project news: PrestaShop 1.7.8.8 04:04 Project news: new project members 04:36 Project news: Hummingbird theme, status update 08:53 Project news: core monthly 10:04 Demo: availability labels per combination by @Hlavtox 16:08 Demo: more options for discontinued products by @Hlavtox 22:03 Demo: ability to configure backorder status by @Hlavtox 24:23 Pull Requests overview 33:48 Questions &amp;amp; answers (do you have any questions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing December PrestaShop Project Public Demo</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/upcoming-demo-9-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/upcoming-demo-9-2022/</guid>
      <description>Friendly reminder, that the public demo for the PrestaShop Project will happen tomorrow, on Wednesday, December 14th, 2022 at 4pm CET!
I expect to share with you project news. Additionally, a few demos are planned:
Availability labels for product combinations, by @Hlavtox New options for discountinued products, by @Hlavtox Better managing the order state for backorder products, by @Hlavtox At the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session. You can ask your questions beforehand.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
