<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>performance on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/performance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in performance on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 15:50:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/performance/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PHP, scalability &amp; filesystems</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/PHP-scalability-and-filesystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 15:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/PHP-scalability-and-filesystem/</guid>
      <description>In this third article in the performance series we started last year, we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about PHP, scalability and its impact on the filesystem!
Also, we&amp;rsquo;re glad to announce that our White Paper about PrestaShop Performance is now published. So, if you&amp;rsquo;re interested by performance in general and PrestaShop in particular, have a look at it and let us know what you think!
Without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into PHP, filetystem and scalability!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache vs. NGINX: Match of the Millennium</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/apache-vs-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 16:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/apache-vs-nginx/</guid>
      <description>Here is the second article in the performance series we started last year, dealing with the old feud between Apache and NGINX.
As you may have heard of, we will soon publish a White Paper about PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s performances, how to tune your shop, enhance its response time, and so on.
During these benchmarks, we did compare performances between Apache &amp;amp; NGINX, the usual contenders, with identical setups.
Though this article probably won&amp;rsquo;t end the long debate between those two, let&amp;rsquo;s hope it will help you find some clarity on the matter and find out which one is best suited for your configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance (&amp; PrestaShop)</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/performance-and-prestashop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/performance-and-prestashop/</guid>
      <description>Introducing a new series of article to talk about performance, benchmarking and PrestaShop!
You may have heard of it, but we&amp;rsquo;ll soon release a White Paper, which is all about PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s performance, how to benchmark it and how it behaves under loads. And what to do to keep it responding under 300ms.
Still, there are a number of matters that can&amp;rsquo;t be covered in a White Paper - hopefully the first in a series, fingers crossed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the 1.7.2.2 performance improvement</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-2-2-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 01:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-2-2-performance/</guid>
      <description>A small line might have gone unnoticed in the PrestaShop 1.7.2.2 release announcement: &amp;ldquo;1.7 front-end should now be faster than 1.6’s for popular stores&amp;rdquo;. What does it apply to, and how did we test for such performances? Here&amp;rsquo;s how.
With the release of PrestaShop 1.7.2.2, we have tried to remove a few point of contention which were affecting badly overall PrestaShop performance:
Specific price computation Bad sale page pagination, which loaded too many products on one page Let&amp;rsquo;s check the specific price improvement!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.6.1.0: a new level of performances</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/prestashop-1-6-1-0-performances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 18:29:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/prestashop-1-6-1-0-performances/</guid>
      <description>A lot of things have been improved on PrestaShop 1.6.1.0:
Design. Invoices. Search. Performance. We have done a lot of work to improve the overall performances of PrestaShop, and reached in some cases a whooping 10x improvement.
Let’s now dig into the optimizations we have put in place, and do some benchmarks.
Note: This article was first published by Jocelyn on his blog at Softizy. Read the original here.
Which parts of PrestaShop are faster?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
