<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JuneByun on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/JuneByun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JuneByun on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/JuneByun/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – July 2020 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-july-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-july-2020/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in April.
Project news First news, a way to boost translations 🔥 As I mentioned in the previous Crowdin Monthly, many PrestaShop translation projects, such as Esperanto, are reaching higher translation rates thanks to dedicated contributors. To help and encourage them, I did some tests by translating strings with Crowdin’s Pre-translation via Translation Memory (TM) tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – June 2020 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-june-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 14:30:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-june-2020/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in May.
Project news First news, Esperanto is on the rise 🔥 I am thrilled to let you know that Esperanto has been on the rise since the last past months. From the beginning of May to the end of June, the Esperanto translation project went from 9% to 34% words translated, that is to say a 25% evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – May 2020 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-may-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 14:30:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-may-2020/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in May.
Project news First news, Swahili will be available in PrestaShop 1.7.8! 🎉 I have the pleasure to announce that PrestaShop will finally be available in Swahili in the 1.7.8 version! I thus encourage you to translate, suggest, and proofread the PrestaShop Swahili project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.7.7 is ready for translation</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/v177-is-ready-for-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/v177-is-ready-for-translation/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.7 is now freshly baked and ready for translation and validation! Translation files have already been pushed on Crowdin projects, so you are all set! 😉
Everybody is invited to translate, spot mistakes, and validate to get an accurate translation catalog for the release.
The beta 1.7.7 is released 🚀 A few weeks ago, the beta version of PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 was launched. Our PrestaShop team is very excited about it and hope that you will be delighted as well because new features and big improvements have been made!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – April 2020 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-april-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-april-2020/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in April.
Project news First news, new content manager 🎉 I would like to take this opportunity to present myself to all of you! My name is June, I joined the PrestaCrew as the new Product Content Manager last week, and I will be in charge of the Crowdin&amp;rsquo;s translation projects in the next several months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
