<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>psday on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/psday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in psday on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 09:10:11 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/psday/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Day Paris is coming this week!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-day-paris-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-day-paris-this-week/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop Day is shaping up to be a great event again (grab your ticket!), and we are happy to welcome contributors at both the Contributor Night on the day before, and at the barcamp within the PS Day.
PS Day Paris will bring together hundreds of members of the PrestaShop ecosystem, including merchants, agencies, freelancers, students, etc.
Many are coming to Paris especially for this event (as well as the WordCamp Europe from our friends in the WordPress community on Friday and Saturday).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barcamp conversations: Symfony, PHP performance, Cloud e-commerce, SEO, Customer Returns and more!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-day-paris-2016-barcamp-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-day-paris-2016-barcamp-schedule/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;d like to thank for the numerous suggestions we received: we were able to build a fantastic program for the barcamp in just a few days!
(Because the PrestaShop Day Paris event (and thus the barcamp) will be entirely in French, so will the rest of this article. Thank you for your understanding.)
Quelques jours seulement après avoir lancé un appel à suggestions, voici le programme des discussions du barcamp lors du PrestaShop Day Paris 2016 :</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
