<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>alexeven on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/alexeven/</link>
    <description>Recent content in alexeven on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 06:09:47 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/alexeven/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – August 2017 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/do-you-speak-prestashop-august-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/do-you-speak-prestashop-august-2017/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report tells you how the translations of the software evolved in August.
Project news Get ready for version 1.7.3.0 We&amp;rsquo;re currently working on version 1.7.3, which is planned for October. That means an update of the content source on Crowdin, and possibly new strings to be translated in October. We&amp;rsquo;ll let you know when it&amp;rsquo;s ready for you to translate!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some resources to help you with the translation of PrestaShop</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/translation-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/translation-resources/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop is quite a large open translation project and as a new translation contributor, you may wonder where to start. You’ll find here all you need to know to help with the translation of our e-commerce software, and a few tips to get you started. Thanks for your help!
Translator guide To get all the information about translating PrestaShop in Crowdin, read our Translator’s guide: PrestaShop_Translator_Guide.pdf
This guide was written for PrestaShop 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – July 2017 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/do-you-speak-prestashop-july-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/do-you-speak-prestashop-july-2017/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part to the PrestaShop translation project! Read this report to see how the translations of the software evolved in July.
Project news Adding Esperanto We&amp;rsquo;ve received the request to add - for the second time! - Esperanto to PrestaShop. It&amp;rsquo;s been added to the Crowdin project this week, so please join us if you want our e-commerce software to be available in Esperanto :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An update on the 1.7 RTL project</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/PrestaShop-RTL-project-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/PrestaShop-RTL-project-update/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago we announced the launch of a project to better adapt PrestaShop to right-to-left (RTL) languages. We already have a small community overviewing what is going on (thank you!). To make sure everybody shares the same level of information, here is where we stand so far.
Choosing a method: RTL script We had to figure out which method to use to adapt PrestaShop to RTL languages. Here are the many methods that have been reviewed, and why we’ve chosen to go for a script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – June 2017 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/do-you-speak-prestashop-june-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/do-you-speak-prestashop-june-2017/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part to the PrestaShop translation project! Read this report to see how the translations of the software evolved in June.
Project news 1.7.1 made way for 1.7.2 As we&amp;rsquo;ve recently released the new version 1.7.2.0, the translations folder for the version 1.7.1 has been removed. This version brings some new content; you can read more about it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.7.2 is ready for translation</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/2017-06-26-172-Translations-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/2017-06-26-172-Translations-update/</guid>
      <description>As you might have guessed, PrestaShop 1.7.2 is on its way, and with it some new strings are coming too. We&amp;rsquo;ve just updated the Crowdin project to add the strings that appeared since v1.7.1.0: PrestaShop 1.7.2 is now open for translation!
Our goal is to release PrestaShop 1.7.2 with the highest possible level of translation, therefore we&amp;rsquo;re opening the translation some time before the actual release takes place. It is possible that some strings will be updated afterward - if we spot some mistakes or add some more domains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – May 2017 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/do-you-speak-prestashop-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/do-you-speak-prestashop-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part to the PrestaShop translation project! Read this report to see how the translations of the software evolved in May.
Project news Top languages evolution since January A lot of words have been translated since the beginning of the year :) Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick overview of the evolution of the most active languages over the past few months - Thanks for your involvement!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – April 2017 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/do-you-speak-prestashop-april-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/do-you-speak-prestashop-april-2017/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part to the PrestaShop translation project! Read this report to see how the translations of the software evolved in April.
Project news Spanish tone harmonization A good news is that the Spanish translation is now 100% complete! However, there is sometimes a mix of polite versus familiar tone (tu/usted) that needs harmonization. To be aligned with the global tone of PrestaShop, we&amp;rsquo;re choosing to use &amp;rsquo;tu&amp;rsquo; when talking to merchants in Spanish (= in the back office).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – March 2017 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/do-you-speak-prestashop-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/do-you-speak-prestashop-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>More and more languages are available on PrestaShop 1.7 thanks to the help of the community on the PrestaShop translation project! Read this report to see how the project evolved in March.
Project news New strings to translate in project 1.6 With the update of the 1-Click-Upgrade module for 1.6 (to allow the upgrade to 1.7), we added several new strings to the 1.6 Crowdin project. We need your help to reach the completion level we had before, as some languages are no longer 100% translated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to translate your theme in PrestaShop 1.7</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/how-to-translate-your-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/how-to-translate-your-theme/</guid>
      <description>This article is outdated PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s translation system has evolved since this article was originally published in 2017. Make sure to read the latest documentation on how to use translations in PrestaShop for modules, and for themes. By now you’re probably aware that the 1.7 version comes with a new translation system and that the theme you are building can benefit from it. However, we didn’t give much details on how it works yet, so here is what you should know if you want to translate your theme for PrestaShop 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new regarding translations in PrestaShop 1.7.1.0</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/2017-03-15-translation-news-171/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/2017-03-15-translation-news-171/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.1.0 has been shipped with several new features to improve internationalization and localization. Here is a short tour of what&amp;rsquo;s new and how it makes things better for you, both as a merchant and a translator!
Daily language packs update Previously translation packs were updated manually on our side, and at this frequency:
1.6 - every two weeks 1.7 - every Monday This wasn&amp;rsquo;t convenient for translators who wanted to quickly see their contribution into production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making PrestaShop RTL-compliant together with you</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/PrestaShop-RTL-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/PrestaShop-RTL-project/</guid>
      <description>As an editor of a free software translated in many languages, our wish has always been that merchants from anywhere around the world could be able to sell easily thanks to PrestaShop.
This strong focus on internationalization implies more than “just” having the software translated. It also means supporting more formats and behaviours. As a first step towards a full internationalization, we’d like to make sure that PrestaShop 1.7 version is compliant with right-to-left languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.1.0 is available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-1-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-1-0-available/</guid>
      <description>Many of you have been waiting for it: PrestaShop 1.7.1.0 is now available, and it is all you&amp;rsquo;ve ever wanted v1.7 to be!
The feedback we received from the beta version of v1.7.1.0 was very conclusive, and we are happy to release this new minor version of PrestaShop (in the SemVer sense of the word) this April &amp;ndash; a few days later than we initially expected.
Download 1.7.1.0 now! Let’s dive in, shall we?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – February 2017 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/do-you-speak-prestashop-feb-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 06:09:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/do-you-speak-prestashop-feb-2017/</guid>
      <description>With 1.7.1 version soon to be released, there has been some activity on the PrestaShop translation project last month. And that comes with good news for translators too!
Project news Translation for 1.7.1 are there The next minor version of PrestaShop, V.1.7.1, is open for testing as a beta version. At the same time, we opened it for translation on Crowdin.
We now have a 1.7.1 project, with fresh new strings to translate!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.7.1 is ready for translation</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/2017-02-22-171-Translations-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 06:09:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/2017-02-22-171-Translations-update/</guid>
      <description>As you&amp;rsquo;ve heard, PrestaShop 1.7.1 is on its way, and with it some new strings are coming too. We&amp;rsquo;ve just updated the Crowdin project to add the strings that appeared since v1.7.0.0: PrestaShop 1.7.1 is now open for translation!
Our goal is to release PrestaShop 1.7.1 with the highest possible level of translation, therefore we&amp;rsquo;re opening the translation some time before the actual release takes place. It is possible that some strings will be updated afterward - if we spot some mistakes or add some more domains.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
