<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1.7.0.0 on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/1.7.0.0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1.7.0.0 on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 09:10:11 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/1.7.0.0/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 RC3: Getting there!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC3/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re getting closer! With this new Release Candidate, we deliver a strong RC, which is closer than ever to our quality objectives.
A lot has been done to stabilize and enhance most of the details of the future version 1.7.0.0, and we expect you to be able to work with it as if it was a regular release. Are you feeling it? :)
Test PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 RC3 now! Found an issue?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 RC2: On the Right Track</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC2/</guid>
      <description>Another step in the right direction towards a stable v1.7, this RC2 fixes a lot of stuff and enhances some more.
Again in this RC version, a good chunk of issues have been fixed and improved upon. It&amp;rsquo;s getting better every day, thanks to our community! If you&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting to create a 1.7 theme or to upgrade your 1.6 modules, this is the right time!
Test PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 RC2 now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 RC1: The Real Deal</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC1/</guid>
      <description>Here it comes: the bug fixin&amp;rsquo;, performance improvin&amp;rsquo;, stabilizin, all singin&amp;rsquo; all dancin&amp;rsquo; RC1 for PrestaShop 1.7! It is packed with goodness, and needs your love!
Released on August 29th, the 1.7 RC0 release was dubbed a &amp;ldquo;pre-RC1&amp;rdquo; version, so you knew what was coming. Since then, MANY bugs were fixed and improvements added. We&amp;rsquo;re sure you will like this release even more than RC0! We hope it will be the one you will start working with when building your modules and themes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommended for testing: PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 RC0</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-RC0/</guid>
      <description>Have you been waiting for a &amp;ldquo;stable enough&amp;rdquo; version of PrestaShop 1.7 in order to start truly testing this new major release? Well, consider yourself in luck, because today we are releasing the RC0 of PrestaShop &amp;ndash; not quite a first RC, but close enough for you to start testing and provide us with the necessary feedback to make 1.7 a good fit for your needs!
We know how the Open Source community at large works with new major versions: pay attention only once 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 Beta 3 is out!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-beta-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 09:00:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-beta-3/</guid>
      <description>Hot on the heels of Beta 2, here&amp;rsquo;s PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 Beta 3, ready for you to test and give feedback about!
As always during this period of testing and fixing, we need feedback from any merchant, service provider, module developer or theme designer who is reading this.
The release of this Beta 3 is another step in the current period of intensive testing and debugging by the PrestaShop developers, towards a proper RC and eventual release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 reaches Beta 2 stage</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-17-beta2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 09:00:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-17-beta2/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce that PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 is now available for testing in its 2nd Beta version. More than ever, we need YOUR feedback as a merchant, a service provider, a module developer or a theme designer.
The release of this second Beta version is another important milestone in the current period of intensive testing and debugging by the PrestaShop developers.
Test PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 Beta 2 now! PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 is still in development, which means that this new Beta release is a great opportunity for you to discover it before we release a stable version!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 Beta 1 is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-beta-1-open-for-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 00:00:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-beta-1-open-for-feedback/</guid>
      <description>The first Beta version for PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 is now ready for you to test!
We are happy to announce that the development branch of version 1.7 has reached the Beta state, and we can’t wait to receive your feedback as a merchant, a service provider, a module developer or a theme designer.
Test PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 Beta 1 now! PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 is still in development, which means that this Beta release is a great opportunity for you to start working with it before we release a stable version!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here comes PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 alpha 4!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/here-comes-prestashop-1-7-alpha-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 02:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/here-comes-prestashop-1-7-alpha-4/</guid>
      <description>Three weeks ago we released PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 alpha 3. Since then, and with the help of the community, we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on it to fix the bugs you&amp;rsquo;ve reported and to keep improving this new version. We&amp;rsquo;re now releasing PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 alpha 4 version, so we can keep gathering feedback and make sure that the final and stable version will be the best it can be!
While this alpha version is not ready for production stores, it is a great basis for us to get your feedbacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 alpha 3 now!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-alpha-3-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 02:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-alpha-3-is-here/</guid>
      <description>Here it is. After two internal alpha versions, we’re happy to present to you this public alpha release of PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 &amp;ndash; the first in a series of public alpha/beta/RC versions that we intend to release over several weeks, in order to gather feedback and make sure that the final and stable version is the best it can be!
Here is your chance to dive into what’s coming in 1.7:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
