<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/security/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.1 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available. This release contains a few security fixes, so we highly recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
Version 8.1.1 fixes a few security issues found by security researchers and solves a great number of bugs reported by the community and project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance team.
You can go to the release page to see a full changelog, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning a few notable bug fixes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.5 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-5-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-5-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The fifth patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download! This release contains a few security fixes, so we highly recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
PrestaShop 8.0.x branch is no longer supported since the release of PrestaShop 8.1, but due to the high severity of the security issues fixed in this release, we decided to release a patch version for this branch.
Apart from the security fixes, this release also contains a few bug fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.10 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-10-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-10-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A security patch for PrestaShop 1.7 is now available.
As part of the extended support policy for PrestaShop 1.7, which involves taking care of critical and security fixes for the 1.7.8.x branch, we are releasing today a new patch for this version. This release fixes a few security issues found by security researchers.
For more details regarding security fixes, you can check the security advisories section below.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major Security Vulnerability on PrestaShop Websites</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/major-security-vulnerability-on-prestashop-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/major-security-vulnerability-on-prestashop-websites/</guid>
      <description>Attackers have found a way to use a security vulnerability to carry out arbitrary code execution in servers running PrestaShop websites. For details, please read the entire article.
What&amp;rsquo;s happening The maintainer team has been made aware that malicious actors are exploiting a combination of known and unknown security vulnerabilities to inject malicious code in PrestaShop websites, allowing them to execute arbitrary instructions, and potentially steal customer&amp;rsquo;s payment information.
While investigating this attack, we found a previously unknown vulnerability chain that we are fixing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Of PrestaShop 1.7.6.9</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-9-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-9-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The ongoing work on security for PrestaShop software continues. We have identified and fixed a new security issue, it has been decided to deliver a new maintenance release for 1.7.6.X branch.
Reminder: the 1-Click Upgrade module’s latest version is v4.10.1, don’t forget to upgrade it.
Security fixes 1 security fix has been included in this patch version:
Improper Access Control with submitReorder function (security advisory) More information about why it is important to update:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Of PrestaShop 1.7.6.8</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-8-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-8-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The ongoing work on security for PrestaShop software continues. We have identified and fixed new minor security issues, it has been decided to deliver a new maintenance release for 1.7.6.X branch.
Reminder: the 1-Click Upgrade module’s latest version is v4.10.1, don’t forget to upgrade it.
Security fixes 4 security fixes have been included in this patch version:
Stored XSS in upload files (security advisory) Blind SQLi in Catalog Product edition (security advisory) Potential XSS injection with contact form (security advisory) We also include an updated version of the contactform module</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bug Bounty Program, the retrospective</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/bug-bounty-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/bug-bounty-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>For several months, we experimented a Bug Bounty Program with the YesWeHack platform. Here is a retrospective, explaining why we did it, and what happened during this period.
Private program The security of software cannot be assessed unless it is tested by a lot of hunters.
PrestaShop relies on a lot of dependencies, with hundreds of thousands lines of code, and this has been true since the very first versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing our first Bug Bounty program</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/bug-bounty-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/bug-bounty-program/</guid>
      <description>Protecting the business, data and privacy of PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s users is one of our top priorities. We build our software with this goal in mind. That&amp;rsquo;s why we decided to put our security to the test. To encourage the security community to help us, today we are announcing our first bug bounty program!
Why this program Bug bounties are used by many leading companies to improve the security of their products. These programs provide an incentive for researchers to responsibly disclose software bugs and allow security teams to leverage the external community to help keep users safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Of PrestaShop 1.7.6.6</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-6-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-6-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The ongoing work on security for PrestaShop software continues. We have identified and fixed new minor security issues and since we don&amp;rsquo;t expect PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 final to be released before a few weeks, it has been decided to deliver a new maintenance release for 1.7.6.X branch.
Similarly to 1.7.6.5, this maintenance release fixes not only regressions found on versions 1.7.6.0 to 1.7.6.5, but also a few security issues from 1.5, 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We were at Google&#39;s CMS Security Summit 2020</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/cms-security-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/cms-security-summit/</guid>
      <description>Once again, open source CMSs Security leads shared knowledge together last February at an event organized by Google in Munich.
Lightning talks &amp;amp; Security technologies After spending the first evening with stakeholders and meeting the newcomers over a few beers, the attendees and I spent two days at Google&amp;rsquo;s Munich office and Information Security Hub (ISH) to talk about what we have achieved since last year and about what&amp;rsquo;s coming. And of course we learned a lot about each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Of PrestaShop 1.7.6.5</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-5-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-5-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, the PrestaShop core team has decided to make a forthright patch release process and deliver patch versions on a more regular basis, every time it’s needed. So here we are, 6 weeks after the release of 1.7.6.4, PrestaShop 1.7.6.5 is now available!
This maintenance release is a bit special as it does not only fix regressions found on version 1.7.6.0 to 1.7.6.4, but it also has put a focus on fixing many security issues, from 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Of PrestaShop 1.7.6.4</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-4-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-4-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.6.4 is finally available! A critical security issue and regressions found on the previous 1.7.6 versions have been fixed. Upgrading your shop is highly recommended.
This maintenance release fixes 9 issues reported from versions 1.7.6.0 to 1.7.6.3. Since this version fixes a security problem, we strongly encourage you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible. We suggest upgrading your shop quickly to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to backup before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security issue with PHPUnit, post-incident analysis</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/phpunit-security-issue-post-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/phpunit-security-issue-post-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Early January, we encountered a security issue with PHPUnit in some modules that allowed attackers to perform arbitrary code execution without authorization through the PHPUnit dependency. This vulnerability was discovered through a merchant whose shops were compromised.
Background At PrestaShop, we use an automated system to build packages for native modules and make them available through the Addons Marketplace API. This process uses Composer to install dependencies before creating the zip package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical security vulnerability in PrestaShop modules</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/critical-security-vulnerability-in-prestashop-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 14:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/critical-security-vulnerability-in-prestashop-modules/</guid>
      <description>Attackers are using a vulnerability in a popular dependency used by modules to take control of PrestaShop sites. For details, please read the entire article.
What’s happening It has come to our attention that attackers are exploiting a vulnerability in PHPUnit to perform arbitrary code execution in servers running PrestaShop websites. The issue is fixed in PHPUnit 7.5.19 and 8.5.1. To our knowledge, all previous versions are vulnerable, at least for certain server configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release of PrestaShop 1.7.5.2 and 1.6.1.24</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-5-2-1-6-1-24-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-5-2-1-6-1-24-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.5.2 and 1.6.1.24 are now available. These versions fix a security issue for both 1.7.5.x and 1.6.1.x. For the details, please read below:
These two security updates address a validation issue on the customer registration form, which is currently being exploited by spammers who were entering URLs as customer name.
This update mitigates the problem by preventing attackers to use URLs as names. However, as we discussed before, the best protection against this kind of attack still is to add a CAPTCHA module on your shop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
