<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/security/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.3 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-3-security-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-3-security-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 8.2.3 is available. It is a security‑driven patch release for the 8.2 branch. Its primary goal is to address an email enumeration vulnerability in the back office password reset feature. A handful of low-risk improvements and bug fixes that have already been validated have also been included.
Why this release now? PrestaShop 8.2 is in the extended support phase, so only security and critical fixes are shipped. Over the past days, we observed (via community reports and partners) automated probes abusing the back office password reset page to enumerate employee emails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Injection attacks alert and security enhancements for PrestaShop</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/sql-injection-attacks-alert-and-security-enhancements-for-prestashop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/sql-injection-attacks-alert-and-security-enhancements-for-prestashop/</guid>
      <description>A recent wave of attacks has targeted PrestaShop stores, leveraging SQL Injection vulnerabilities in third-party modules to compromise data security. Malicious actors exploit these vulnerabilities to inject harmful code into the PrestaShop database, enabling the theft of sensitive customer information by loading unauthorized JavaScript scripts.
According to the investigation, this vulnerability is not in the PrestaShop core but in third-party modules. Stores using a custom database prefix and without SQL Injection-vulnerable modules installed should remain unaffected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.6 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-6-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-6-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A new patch version for PrestaShop 8.1 is now available. This maintenance release fixes 2 security issues.
The security patch for version 8.1 of PrestaShop is now available. It is recommended that you upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to create a backup before. You can upgrade to the latest version using the 1-Click Upgrade module. There are no database changes in this release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.4 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-4-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-4-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been decided to release a security patch for version 8.1 of PrestaShop.
The security patch for version 8.1 of PrestaShop is now available. This is the first release where it&amp;rsquo;s been decided to separate the security fixes from other bug fixes and improvements, allowing for a quick release of the security patch.
It is recommended that you upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to create a backup before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.3 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-3-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-3-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>We are entering the new year with the release of PrestaShop 8.1.3. The latest update for PrestaShop 8.1 is now available. This version brings two security updates, addresses close to 30 known issues, and introduces various enhancements.
To welcome the new year well, we are releasing a new version of PrestaShop! Version 8.1.3 is available with a slight delay, but this is due to the time it took to complete work on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.11 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-1-7-8-11-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-1-7-8-11-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A security patch for PrestaShop 1.7 is now available.
As part of the extended support policy for PrestaShop 1.7, which involves taking care of critical and security fixes for the 1.7.8.x branch, we are releasing today a new patch for this version. This release fixes one high severity security issue found by security researchers.
For more details regarding security fixes, you can check the security advisories section below.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.1 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available. This release contains a few security fixes, so we highly recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
Version 8.1.1 fixes a few security issues found by security researchers and solves a great number of bugs reported by the community and project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance team.
You can go to the release page to see a full changelog, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning a few notable bug fixes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.5 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-5-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-5-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The fifth patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download! This release contains a few security fixes, so we highly recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
PrestaShop 8.0.x branch is no longer supported since the release of PrestaShop 8.1, but due to the high severity of the security issues fixed in this release, we decided to release a patch version for this branch.
Apart from the security fixes, this release also contains a few bug fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.10 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-10-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-10-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A security patch for PrestaShop 1.7 is now available.
As part of the extended support policy for PrestaShop 1.7, which involves taking care of critical and security fixes for the 1.7.8.x branch, we are releasing today a new patch for this version. This release fixes a few security issues found by security researchers.
For more details regarding security fixes, you can check the security advisories section below.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major Security Vulnerability on PrestaShop Websites</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/major-security-vulnerability-on-prestashop-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/major-security-vulnerability-on-prestashop-websites/</guid>
      <description>Attackers have found a way to use a security vulnerability to carry out arbitrary code execution in servers running PrestaShop websites. For details, please read the entire article.
What&amp;rsquo;s happening The maintainer team has been made aware that malicious actors are exploiting a combination of known and unknown security vulnerabilities to inject malicious code in PrestaShop websites, allowing them to execute arbitrary instructions, and potentially steal customer&amp;rsquo;s payment information.
While investigating this attack, we found a previously unknown vulnerability chain that we are fixing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Of PrestaShop 1.7.6.9</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-9-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-9-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The ongoing work on security for PrestaShop software continues. We have identified and fixed a new security issue, it has been decided to deliver a new maintenance release for 1.7.6.X branch.
Reminder: the 1-Click Upgrade module’s latest version is v4.10.1, don’t forget to upgrade it.
Security fixes 1 security fix has been included in this patch version:
Improper Access Control with submitReorder function (security advisory) More information about why it is important to update:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Of PrestaShop 1.7.6.8</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-8-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-8-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The ongoing work on security for PrestaShop software continues. We have identified and fixed new minor security issues, it has been decided to deliver a new maintenance release for 1.7.6.X branch.
Reminder: the 1-Click Upgrade module’s latest version is v4.10.1, don’t forget to upgrade it.
Security fixes 4 security fixes have been included in this patch version:
Stored XSS in upload files (security advisory) Blind SQLi in Catalog Product edition (security advisory) Potential XSS injection with contact form (security advisory) We also include an updated version of the contactform module</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bug Bounty Program, the retrospective</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/bug-bounty-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/bug-bounty-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>For several months, we experimented a Bug Bounty Program with the YesWeHack platform. Here is a retrospective, explaining why we did it, and what happened during this period.
Private program The security of software cannot be assessed unless it is tested by a lot of hunters.
PrestaShop relies on a lot of dependencies, with hundreds of thousands lines of code, and this has been true since the very first versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing our first Bug Bounty program</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/bug-bounty-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/bug-bounty-program/</guid>
      <description>Protecting the business, data and privacy of PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s users is one of our top priorities. We build our software with this goal in mind. That&amp;rsquo;s why we decided to put our security to the test. To encourage the security community to help us, today we are announcing our first bug bounty program!
Why this program Bug bounties are used by many leading companies to improve the security of their products. These programs provide an incentive for researchers to responsibly disclose software bugs and allow security teams to leverage the external community to help keep users safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Of PrestaShop 1.7.6.6</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-6-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-6-6-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The ongoing work on security for PrestaShop software continues. We have identified and fixed new minor security issues and since we don&amp;rsquo;t expect PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 final to be released before a few weeks, it has been decided to deliver a new maintenance release for 1.7.6.X branch.
Similarly to 1.7.6.5, this maintenance release fixes not only regressions found on versions 1.7.6.0 to 1.7.6.5, but also a few security issues from 1.5, 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
