<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>autoupgrade on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/autoupgrade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in autoupgrade on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/autoupgrade/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Autoupgrade module v6.1.0 and 6.2.0 are Available (1-Click Upgrade)</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/autoupgrade-v6.1-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/autoupgrade-v6.1-release/</guid>
      <description>In the footsteps of the latest module releases (see version 6.0.0 release blogpost), these versions bring a number of improvements to streamline PrestaShop updates. Explore the changelog below to find out what version 6.1.0 and 6.2.0 bring to the upgrade module.
What’s inside Global improvements: Version comparison - Fix an issue on the PHP version check before starting an upgrade, which was reporting some valid versions as incompatible. Version comparison - Fix an issue where the number of altered or deleted core files is always zero.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autoupgrade module v6.0.0 is Available (1-Click Upgrade)</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/autoupgrade-v6-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/autoupgrade-v6-release/</guid>
      <description>In the footsteps of the latest module releases (see versions 5.0.2 and 5.0.3 live presentation), this version brings a number of improvements to streamline PrestaShop updates. Explore the changelog below to find out what version 6.0.0 brings to the Autoupgrade module.
What’s inside Global improvements: Ensure update path - Optimization of the upgrade path to the latest version of PrestaShop 8 when using the minor channel. Enable usage &amp;amp; error analytics - Introduce anonymous analytics with Segment and voluntary error reporting based on Sentry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test the updated 1-Click Upgrade module!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/updated-1-click-upgrade-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/updated-1-click-upgrade-module/</guid>
      <description>After much work and hair-pulling, we finally did it: the 1-Click Upgrade module supports upgrading from 1.6 to 1.7.1.0. Are you ready to test it before the release?
This is your chance to try your hand at the updated 1-Click Upgrade module! We’ve tested it in many configurations, but there’s nothing like community feedback!
Download the update 1-Click upgrade module now! The story so far Those of you who follow our Git history know this: the ‘autoupgrade’ project had not received serious attention for a long time when the team started cleaning up the code in November 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
