<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>development on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in development on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/development/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9 minimum PHP version will be PHP8.1</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-9-min-php-version-will-be-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-9-min-php-version-will-be-81/</guid>
      <description>The develop branch contains the source code that will give birth to PrestaShop 9. This is the future of PrestaShop: it will be released either at the end of the year 2023 or at the beginning of the year 2024 and must carry on the ambition of the project for 2024. This major version must also embrace the change in the PHP ecosystem, and consequently, it must drop the support of obsolete PHP versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing TypeScript</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/introducing-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/introducing-typescript/</guid>
      <description>Following a recent Architecture Decision Records (ADR) submission and a Proof of Concept (POC), the Core Maintainers team has decided to introduce TypeScript (TS) on the project.
Why TypeScript? During the last few years, the PrestaShop Project has been increasingly raising the code quality bar. To help maintainers ensure that quality keeps increasing, a number of automatic quality verification tools have been added to the CI pipeline:
ESLint analyzes the whole JavaScript codebase to ensure it follows our code style and find problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heads up: old development branches are going away</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/old-branches-are-going-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/old-branches-are-going-away/</guid>
      <description>The month of June is fast approaching, so it&amp;rsquo;s time for a late Spring clean!
On June 1st, 2021 we will delete all branches from our main repository that are no longer subject to new releases.
The affected branches are:
1.7.0.x 1.7.1.x 1.7.2.x 1.7.3.x 1.7.4.x 1.7.5.x 1.7.6.x Future branches will be deleted as well once they will become stale (e.g. 1.7.7.x will be deleted shortly after 1.7.8 is out).
Important note: Please be aware that this is a routine cleanup and has absolutely no impact on source code availability for previous versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop is now available on Composer</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-available-composer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-available-composer/</guid>
      <description>Released almost 10 years ago, Composer is the most popular package manager for the PHP ecosystem. PrestaShop has been using it since 1.7.0 to manage its dependencies, including all the native modules.
Today we are announcing the general availability of PrestaShop itself through Composer. Thanks to this, it is now possible to easily create a new PrestaShop project from the command line, like this:
composer create-project prestashop/prestashop Or, if you want to download a specific version instead of the latest release:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A journey to improve the Time To Interactive metric in Classic Theme</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/journey-to-improve-the-time-to-interactive-metric/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/journey-to-improve-the-time-to-interactive-metric/</guid>
      <description>The project Core Web Vitals from Google has announced that loading time and performance will have an impact on the website ranking in search results. Google mentions lazy loading in their suggestions. Lazy loading will be available on Classic Theme in version 1.7.8 thanks to Progi1984 and it will definitely improve both user experience and loading time on your site!
What is lazy loading ? Lazy loading is a technique that defers loading of non-critical resources at page load time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Question: What about not committing generated files anymore?</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/open-question-not-commiting-assets-anymore/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/open-question-not-commiting-assets-anymore/</guid>
      <description>This post is the first of a new kind. We decided to open up more with you about technical questioning and decisions for the PrestaShop project. This one is about generated asset files.
[EDIT] February 7th 2020: Considered the positive feedback we received after publishing the article, we decided to remove the generated files and to add the make assets command. Learn more in the devdoc.
Details of the feedback: 27 &amp;ldquo;Upvote&amp;rdquo; and 1 &amp;ldquo;Sad&amp;rdquo; reactions in Disqus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.6.0 is available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-6-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-6-0-available/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce PrestaShop 1.7.6.0 is officially available!
It has been quite a journey to deliver this huge release, our biggest yet since 1.7.1.0. Six months of development, a six week-long Beta, two Release Candidates&amp;hellip; Was it worth it? We absolutely think so, and hope that you will enjoy using it.
In this version we focused on improving and bringing back important 1.6 features to merchants, and kept working on code quality and performance improvements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSD Paris 2019: a space dedicated to developers</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/psd-2019-developer-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 14:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/psd-2019-developer-space/</guid>
      <description>That’s official, there will be a dedicated space for developers at the PSD Paris 2019. If you are developing themes and modules or contributing to the core, this is the place to be the 4th of June 2019.
Having such a place was expected by many people in the community. There was no dedicated space last year: that was possible to speak standing, exchange, but not possible to work. But this year, we do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing end of support for obsolete PHP versions</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/announcing-end-of-support-for-obsolete-php-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/announcing-end-of-support-for-obsolete-php-versions/</guid>
      <description>Current PHP compatibility in PrestaShop You can check the current PHP compatibility of PrestaShop on our documentation. For PrestaShop 1.7 you can check this page. About a year and a half ago, we announced that PrestaShop 1.7.4.0 would be dropping support for PHP 5.4 and 5.5. At that time, this decision was justified by the impending end-of-maintenance for Symfony 2 and its replacement by Symfony 3, which didn&amp;rsquo;t support PHP versions older than 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.5.0 is available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-5-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 10:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-5-0-available/</guid>
      <description>After a Beta and a Release Candidate, the long awaited PrestaShop 1.7.5.0 has been released and is available for download. As usual, you can upgrade with the Auto upgrade module. However, considering that the current period is usually critical for merchants sales, for sure, some might prefer to wait for a more appropriate time :-)
Changes A lot has been done to make this “minor” PrestaShop version a reality. Here’s 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.4.0 is available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-4-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 17:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-4-0-available/</guid>
      <description>Dear community, after a little bit more than four months, the new minor version of PrestaShop is available: please welcome 1.7.4.0!
Download PrestaShop 1.7.4.0 now! Be careful! If you plan to upgrade, we recommend you to use the version 4.0 of the 1-click upgrade, currently available as a beta on GitHub, instead of the version 3.0 available on the marketplace. What’s new Let’s have a look at the new features and improvements that will enhance the merchants’ experience, like UI and performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.3.0 is available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-3-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-3-0-available/</guid>
      <description>Dear community, it is a great day for us all. Many “when will it be released?” later, we are thrilled to announce the birth of PrestaShop 1.7.3!
After six months of blood, sweat, and tears (okay, we’re just kidding), here it is, the new minor version has come. We are aware that these six months of work have raised some very high expectations. You won’t be disappointed, because we have spent a lot of time improving and testing it for you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.3.0 RC1 is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-3-0-rc-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-1-7-3-0-rc-1/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.3.0 Release Candidate is now ready for you to test!
We are happy to announce that we are very close to releasing 1.7.3.0. This minor version (in the SemVer meaning of the term) brings several improvements, some new features and innovative tools to the 1.7 codebase. We can’t wait to receive your feedback about it!
Test PrestaShop 1.7.3.0 RC1 now! This release candidate is a great opportunity for you to start playing with it before we release the final version!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PrestaShop Test Framework</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-test-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-test-framework/</guid>
      <description>Last time we announced a new suite of functional tests to ensure our software quality, today we are proud to present you our new feature, the PrestaShop Test Framework!
It is a cool toolkit like a Swiss knife which will help to save a lot of time by running at least 50 automated functional tests on your browser&amp;hellip; and this is only the beginning! It makes easier to create basic acceptance testing when adding Addons, submitting pull requests or making some customizations on your Prestashop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Integration Fund is still alive</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/integration-fund-is-still-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/integration-fund-is-still-alive/</guid>
      <description>Dear contributors, remember when, about two years ago, we presented you the Integration Fund? We even made an amazing video where we talk about this no less amazing Integration Fund. Well, we are still here and running, and for all this we would like to thank you.
Now, some of you may be wondering: “Integration Fund? Never heard of it!”. So if you&amp;rsquo;ve missed the previous articles, here is where you should go:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
