<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>releases on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/releases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in releases on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/releases/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.1 is in feature freeze</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-1-feature-freeze/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-1-feature-freeze/</guid>
      <description>As of December 12th, 2025, PrestaShop version 9.1 has entered the feature freeze phase. Learn more about the feature freeze, the next steps, and what’s coming in PrestaShop 9.1.
PrestaShop 9.1 feature freeze is in effect As of today, PrestaShop 9.1 is in feature freeze. What is a feature freeze? Feature freeze marks a stage in development when no new features are accepted. The focus shifts to polishing what’s built and validating quality before release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 9.0.2 is now available! This second patch version represents yet another step in making PrestaShop 9 more reliable. It focuses on fixing some reported issues to provide a more stable and seamless experience for merchants and developers.
PrestaShop 9 continues to focus on stability and polish With the second maintenance release, our attention has shifted from broad feature work to refining the platform based on real-world feedback. 9.0.2 brings targeted fixes that improve reliability, developer experience, and daily merchant operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0.1 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch version for PrestaShop 9 is now available! This maintenance release focuses on resolving some of the key issues to ensure a smoother experience for all users.
A strong start for PrestaShop 9 Since its release, PrestaShop 9 has been met with great enthusiasm from our community. Many developers, agencies, and merchants have actively tested the new version and shared their valuable feedback. This collaborative effort has been instrumental in helping us refine the new version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.3 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-3-security-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-3-security-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 8.2.3 is available. It is a security‑driven patch release for the 8.2 branch. Its primary goal is to address an email enumeration vulnerability in the back office password reset feature. A handful of low-risk improvements and bug fixes that have already been validated have also been included.
Why this release now? PrestaShop 8.2 is in the extended support phase, so only security and critical fixes are shipped. Over the past days, we observed (via community reports and partners) automated probes abusing the back office password reset page to enumerate employee emails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 8.2.2 is here! This latest patch version brings a range of updates, addressing reported issues and introducing enhancements to improve the platform for merchants and developers alike.
We are happy to announce the release of PrestaShop 8.2.2, a patch version that not only resolves numerous bugs reported by our dedicated community and Quality Assurance team but also introduces some improvements.
As part of the Call for Contributions challenge, PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.x is now in the extended support phase</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/82x-extended-support-phase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/82x-extended-support-phase/</guid>
      <description>Now that PrestaShop 9.0 is out, here is a focus on maintained branches of the PrestaShop project and what to expect.
Reminder: PrestaShop branching strategy In August 2015 PrestaShop adopted a new branching model for the project.
The model was refined over the years, for example with this developer documentation page about which bugs qualify for a patch version or the Backward Compatibility Promise that defines which changes can be introduced in a version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-available/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s finally here! PrestaShop 9 is available for download. This new version brings a modernized architecture, new developer tools, and powerful features designed to support the future of ecommerce.
PrestaShop 9 is here! After over two years of development and collaboration with the community, it&amp;rsquo;s time to take another major step forward. PrestaShop 9 is here. This version brings valuable improvements and marks a significant advancement for anyone looking to grow their business online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0 RC1 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-rc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-rc1/</guid>
      <description>The first Release Candidate of PrestaShop 9.0 is now available for testing. This is a significant milestone in the development cycle, and we encourage all users to test it thoroughly.
PrestaShop 9.0 Release Candidate 1 This version marks the final stage before the stable release. It includes all planned features, improvements, and changes introduced since the alpha and beta phases — including the new Hummingbird theme, Admin API, PHP 8.4 and Symfony 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adapting to PrestaShop 9: Guzzle is gone, what&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/breaking-change-guzzle-removal-v9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/breaking-change-guzzle-removal-v9/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 9 is a major release, meaning it introduces breaking changes, including the removal of certain dependencies. One of the most impactful changes for module developers is the removal of Guzzle, a popular HTTP client that many modules relied on.
If your module depends on Guzzle, it will no longer be available by default in PrestaShop 9. In this article, we’ll explain why Guzzle was removed, what this means for your module, and how to migrate to a suitable alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reworking the &#34;Update Assistant&#34; Module V7: Our Experience</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/reworking-the-update-assistant-module-v7-our-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/reworking-the-update-assistant-module-v7-our-experience/</guid>
      <description>Let’s face it—our Update Assistant module was messy. The front-end was confusing, the user experience was challenging, and even minor adjustments were a little more complex than what we would have liked.
As part of the Seamless Upgrade &amp;amp; Extensibility squad, one of our key missions is to improve the reliability of PrestaShop upgrades. And to do that, we knew the Update Assistant module needed more than just a few patches—it needed a complete reinvention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.1 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch for PrestaShop 8.2 is available. This release contains many bug fixes and improvements, including a new way to handle module filtering in the front office.
We are excited to announce the release of PrestaShop 8.2.1, a new patch that not only addresses a significant number of bugs reported by our dedicated community and Quality Assurance team but also introduces a valuable new feature. This feature allows module developers to filter the display of other modules in PrestaShop, helping them avoid the use of overrides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0 beta is now available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The first beta version of PrestaShop 9.0 is now available for testing. This version includes many new features and improvements, a new Hummingbird theme, a new Admin API, PHP 8.4 and Symfony 6.4 support, many bug fixes, and a significant codebase cleanup. Read on to learn more about the new features and improvements.
PrestaShop 9.0 beta 1 In June, when we released the alpha 1 version, we also published the first overview of new features and improvements that PrestaShop 9 will bring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-2-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-2-0-available/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been decided to release a new minor version of PrestaShop 8.2. This version includes a few improvements, as well as bug fixes.
What&amp;rsquo;s new in PrestaShop 8.2? PrestaShop 8.2 is a minor version that includes a few improvements, as well as bug fixes, and it is relatively small compared to the previous minor versions. Here are some highlights.
Improvements Correctly checking overrides during module installation
PrestaShop used to check for overrides during module installation, but the process didn’t fully block installation if a conflicting override was found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.7 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-7-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-7-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A new patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is now available! This release includes several significant improvements and numerous bug fixes. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore these updates in detail.
PrestaShop 8.1.7 is now available. This release addresses several bugs and brings various improvements.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to backup before. Upgrade is possible using the latest version of the 1-Click Upgrade module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9 Alpha 1 is Available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-9-alpha1-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-9-alpha1-available/</guid>
      <description>Here it is. The first public alpha of PrestaShop 9 is available. We decided it was time to share with you the first results of our work on PrestaShop 9.
Please note that this version is in the early stages of development. To achieve a stable release, we anticipate several months of further work. As we are prior to the feature-freeze phase, the features and content of PrestaShop 9 are subject to change.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
