<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>version on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/version/</link>
    <description>Recent content in version on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/version/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0 RC1 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-rc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-rc1/</guid>
      <description>The first Release Candidate of PrestaShop 9.0 is now available for testing. This is a significant milestone in the development cycle, and we encourage all users to test it thoroughly.
PrestaShop 9.0 Release Candidate 1 This version marks the final stage before the stable release. It includes all planned features, improvements, and changes introduced since the alpha and beta phases — including the new Hummingbird theme, Admin API, PHP 8.4 and Symfony 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.1 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch for PrestaShop 8.2 is available. This release contains many bug fixes and improvements, including a new way to handle module filtering in the front office.
We are excited to announce the release of PrestaShop 8.2.1, a new patch that not only addresses a significant number of bugs reported by our dedicated community and Quality Assurance team but also introduces a valuable new feature. This feature allows module developers to filter the display of other modules in PrestaShop, helping them avoid the use of overrides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9.0 beta is now available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-9-0-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The first beta version of PrestaShop 9.0 is now available for testing. This version includes many new features and improvements, a new Hummingbird theme, a new Admin API, PHP 8.4 and Symfony 6.4 support, many bug fixes, and a significant codebase cleanup. Read on to learn more about the new features and improvements.
PrestaShop 9.0 beta 1 In June, when we released the alpha 1 version, we also published the first overview of new features and improvements that PrestaShop 9 will bring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-2-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-2-0-available/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been decided to release a new minor version of PrestaShop 8.2. This version includes a few improvements, as well as bug fixes.
What&amp;rsquo;s new in PrestaShop 8.2? PrestaShop 8.2 is a minor version that includes a few improvements, as well as bug fixes, and it is relatively small compared to the previous minor versions. Here are some highlights.
Improvements Correctly checking overrides during module installation
PrestaShop used to check for overrides during module installation, but the process didn’t fully block installation if a conflicting override was found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.7 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-7-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-7-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A new patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is now available! This release includes several significant improvements and numerous bug fixes. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore these updates in detail.
PrestaShop 8.1.7 is now available. This release addresses several bugs and brings various improvements.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to backup before. Upgrade is possible using the latest version of the 1-Click Upgrade module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9 Alpha 1 is Available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-9-alpha1-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-9-alpha1-available/</guid>
      <description>Here it is. The first public alpha of PrestaShop 9 is available. We decided it was time to share with you the first results of our work on PrestaShop 9.
Please note that this version is in the early stages of development. To achieve a stable release, we anticipate several months of further work. As we are prior to the feature-freeze phase, the features and content of PrestaShop 9 are subject to change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.6 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-6-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-6-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A new patch version for PrestaShop 8.1 is now available. This maintenance release fixes 2 security issues.
The security patch for version 8.1 of PrestaShop is now available. It is recommended that you upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to create a backup before. You can upgrade to the latest version using the 1-Click Upgrade module. There are no database changes in this release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.5 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-5-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-5-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>Another patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available. This release contains interesting improvements as well as a number of bug fixes. In this article, we’ll lean into them because there’s plenty to write about!
PrestaShop 8.1.5 is available. This release fixes some bugs but also brings a lot of improvements.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to backup before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.4 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-4-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-4-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been decided to release a security patch for version 8.1 of PrestaShop.
The security patch for version 8.1 of PrestaShop is now available. This is the first release where it&amp;rsquo;s been decided to separate the security fixes from other bug fixes and improvements, allowing for a quick release of the security patch.
It is recommended that you upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to create a backup before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.3 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-3-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-3-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>We are entering the new year with the release of PrestaShop 8.1.3. The latest update for PrestaShop 8.1 is now available. This version brings two security updates, addresses close to 30 known issues, and introduces various enhancements.
To welcome the new year well, we are releasing a new version of PrestaShop! Version 8.1.3 is available with a slight delay, but this is due to the time it took to complete work on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.11 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-1-7-8-11-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-1-7-8-11-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A security patch for PrestaShop 1.7 is now available.
As part of the extended support policy for PrestaShop 1.7, which involves taking care of critical and security fixes for the 1.7.8.x branch, we are releasing today a new patch for this version. This release fixes one high severity security issue found by security researchers.
For more details regarding security fixes, you can check the security advisories section below.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The second patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available! This release contains 2 security fixes, over 30 bugs have been fixed and some minor improvements have been integrated.
Version 8.1.2 fixes a few security issues found by security researchers and solves a great number of bugs reported by the community and project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance team. It also includes some minor improvements, especially for the new product page and new multi-format image generation system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.1 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available. This release contains a few security fixes, so we highly recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
Version 8.1.1 fixes a few security issues found by security researchers and solves a great number of bugs reported by the community and project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance team.
You can go to the release page to see a full changelog, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning a few notable bug fixes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.5 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-5-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-5-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The fifth patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download! This release contains a few security fixes, so we highly recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
PrestaShop 8.0.x branch is no longer supported since the release of PrestaShop 8.1, but due to the high severity of the security issues fixed in this release, we decided to release a patch version for this branch.
Apart from the security fixes, this release also contains a few bug fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.10 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-10-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-10-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A security patch for PrestaShop 1.7 is now available.
As part of the extended support policy for PrestaShop 1.7, which involves taking care of critical and security fixes for the 1.7.8.x branch, we are releasing today a new patch for this version. This release fixes a few security issues found by security researchers.
For more details regarding security fixes, you can check the security advisories section below.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
