<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>version on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/version/</link>
    <description>Recent content in version on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/version/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 Release Candidate Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-rc1-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-rc1-release/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce the first release candidate of PrestaShop 8.1.
We&amp;rsquo;re on the brink of releasing the final 8.1 version. This time, the release candidate version is being shared simultaneously with the community and the project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance (QA) team. The idea is for everyone to collectively confirm that all issues identified in the beta version have been resolved, ensuring their suitability for production use. If no major problems are reported by June 26th, we&amp;rsquo;ll move ahead and launch the final version of 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.4 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-4-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-4-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The fourth patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download! This release contains a few security fixes, so we recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
PrestaShop 8.0.4 is now available. This time there are three security fixes thanks to reports from community researchers. This release also contains a few bug fixes besides security fixes. The incorrect translation of pagination labels in products and combinations lists has been fixed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.9 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-9-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 16:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-9-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>Security patch for PrestaShop 1.7 is now available.
As part of the extended support policy for PrestaShop 1.7, which involves taking care of critical and security fixes for 1.7.8.x branch, we are releasing today a new patch for this version. This release fixes a few security issues reported by community researchers and upgrades some third-party libraries to their latest versions to ensure the stability and security of your shop.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.3 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-3-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-3-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The third patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download!
It was a rather bumpy road at the end because of issues we found during the release process, but here it is! In the newest patch version for PrestaShop 8 you can find a security improvement, and three fixes: one related to inaccurate wording in web services configuration, one which fixes the link to the user documentation in the installer, and one significant fix which improves how clearing the cache behaves in the software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The second patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download!
Version 8.0.2 is available! In this patch, you can find over 20 bug fixes. As a patch version, 8.0.2 brings further goodness and stability to the 8.0 branch.
There were several noteworthy issues addressed in PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s 8.0.2 milestone. The upgrade mechanism had a problem where it couldn&amp;rsquo;t check if the PHP session had started on some webservers, which was reported by many community members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 beta is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The beta version of PrestaShop 8.1 is now ready for you to test!
We’re delighted to announce that PrestaShop 8.1 has reached the beta stage. PrestaShop 8.1 is still in development, but we hope you will help us test this release so we can have the best quality release possible, available for everyone, as soon as possible!
Test PrestaShop 8.1.0 beta 1 now! Version 8.1 fixes over 30 bugs found in the previous release and introduces many improvements and new features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 is now in feature freeze</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-feature-freeze/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-feature-freeze/</guid>
      <description>As of February 1, 2023, PrestaShop version 8.1 has entered the feature freeze phase. This article provides more information about the feature freeze, what the next steps will be, and what to expect from PrestaShop 8.1.
Feature freeze for PrestaShop 8.1 As of today, PrestaShop version 8.1 has entered a feature freeze. What is a feature freeze? Feature freeze refers to a specific stage in the software development process after which no new features can be added to a version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.1 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download!
After a few weeks of intensive work from all project members, the first maintenance release for version 8 is now available.
In this patch, you can find more than 30 bug fixes and one performance improvement that prevents clearing the system&amp;rsquo;s cache for bulk actions performed from the modules list. You will also get changes from the recent PrestaShop patch release 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8 is now in the extended support phase</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/178-in-extended-support-phase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/178-in-extended-support-phase/</guid>
      <description>Now that PrestaShop 8.0 is out, here is a focus on maintained branches of the PrestaShop project and what to expect.
Reminder: PrestaShop branching strategy In August 2015 PrestaShop adopted a new branching model for the project.
The model was refined over the years, for example with this page on the developer documentation about what bugs do qualify for a patch version or the Backward Compatibility Promise that defines what changes can be introduced in a version, but we can say the model has lived quite well as the project is still following it in 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.8 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-1-7-8-8-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-1-7-8-8-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>It has been decided to deliver a new maintenance release for 1.7.8.x branch. Please note that this will be the last regular 1.7.8.x patch version, as the branch now enters security-only maintenance phase. Next regular patches will now target 8.0.x branch.
This release fixes some bugs and regressions as well as a security fix.
We suggest upgrading your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to backup before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-0-available/</guid>
      <description>The maintainers team is pleased to announce that PrestaShop 8.0 is officially available.
PrestaShop 8, the first major version since the original release of PrestaShop 1.7.0 back in 2016, is an important milestone for the project.
A significant cleanup has been performed in the codebase, with several internal components updated, modified or removed. PrestaShop 8 is also the project’s first company-neutral release, meaning that it no longer includes commercial products and services built-in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0 Release Candidate Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-rc1-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-rc1-release/</guid>
      <description>The maintainers team is pleased to announce the first release candidate of PrestaShop 8.0.
This is the last step before releasing the final 8.0 version. This release candidate is intended to allow the community to verify that all regressions found during the beta have been fixed and that the software is ready for production. If no major or critical regression is reported before October 20th, then the final version of 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0 beta is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 15:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The public beta version of PrestaShop 8.0 is now ready for you to test!
The maintainers team is very happy to announce today the release of the public beta version of PrestaShop 8.0. This version includes many new features, improvements and over 130 bug fixes.
The main new features for this version include an update to Symfony 4.4, compatibility with PHP 8 and 8.1, an enhanced experimental product page, and a new security page which allows shop administrators to manage user sessions and configure their password policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release of PrestaShop 1.7.8.7</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-1-7-8-7-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-1-7-8-7-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop version 1.7.8.7 is now available. This release fixes one important security issue, read this article for more information.
The maintainer team has been made aware that malicious actors are exploiting a combination of known and unknown security vulnerabilities to inject malicious code in PrestaShop websites, allowing them to execute arbitrary instructions, and potentially steal customer’s payment information. You can read our dedicated article to find out what’s happening, how the attack works and what to do to keep your shop safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Version 8.0 Feature Freeze: Important Features</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-feature-freeze-v8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-feature-freeze-v8/</guid>
      <description>Dear developers and contributors,
We are very pleased to be announcing the feature freeze of PrestaShop version 8.0. In this post, we will be looking at the most important features of this feature freeze, letting you know why we have frozen new features and explain what this means for the next few months.
Feature freeze is now effective Therefore, as of today, the feature freeze is now effective and no new features will be added to version 8.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
