<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>documentation on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/documentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in documentation on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 06:09:47 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/documentation/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to contribute to the User Guide and help translate it</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/how-to-contribute-and-translate-the-user-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 06:09:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/how-to-contribute-and-translate-the-user-documentation/</guid>
      <description>Some of you contacted us to help translate the PrestaShop User Guide into their language. To make things easier for anyone who wants to help write some user documentation, here is a quick guide on how to use Confluence, on which our user documentation is hosted.
Anatomy of a documentation page These elements are important and/or recurring in the PrestaShop documentation and here&amp;rsquo;s what you should know about it.
Page title It will define the page URL (most of the time), and is repeated each time at the beginning of the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New developer documentation for PrestaShop 1.7</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/developer-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/developer-documentation/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7 is a major release: a lot of code has been refactored, new features have been added, and a new way of building themes has been introduced. So, very early in the development release cycle, we decided to write more doc in order to support the designers and developers intending to switch to 1.7.
The documentation&amp;rsquo;s very first draft is now online: http://developers.prestashop.com/
New website Historically, PrestaShop hosted its documentation on http://doc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module development changes in PrestaShop 1.7.0.0</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/module-development-changes-in-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/module-development-changes-in-17/</guid>
      <description>Existing modules should mostly work as-is with version 1.7. In this article, we dive into that “mostly”!
As you certainly know, all well-written 1.6 modules should work with little to no changes in version 1.7, except:
Those which target the theme/front office – because we rewrote the way themes are written. Those which target the Product page – because the DOM of this page has changed. Those which target the Modules page – again, because the DOM of this page has changed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
