<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1.7.1.x on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/1.7.1.x/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1.7.1.x on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 05:10:11 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/1.7.1.x/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Release of PrestaShop 1.7.2.1</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-2-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 05:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-2-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.2.1 is now available. This maintenance release fixes 25 issues reported on version 1.7.2.
Version 1.7.2.0, released in July, brought a lot of goodies, none the less being the new Stock Management feature. That new minor version was well received, and this patch version simply fixes a few kinks that were discovered, bringing further goodness and stability to the 1.7.2 branch.
Some of the most notable fixes are:
Enhanced search performance on front office (and back office) Improved performance and search bar for stock management Better display of back office main menu and submenus Updated design for the modules page and other layouts improvements Improved translation page (yes, again ^^) Download PrestaShop 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 months of PrestaShop</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/the-six-first-months-of-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/the-six-first-months-of-2017/</guid>
      <description>July is almost over and more than 6 months have come and gone since the beginning of the year. Time to gather some numbers and make sense of them. Infographic included!
High-level numbers Between January 1st and June 31st of 2017, we&amp;rsquo;ve released 13 updates to PrestaShop:
1 minor release for 1.7: 1.7.1.0. Version 1.7.2.0 was released in July! Download it today! 5 patch releases for 1.7: from 1.7.0.4, 1.5.0.5, 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release of PrestaShop 1.7.1.2 </title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-1-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 05:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-1-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.1.2 is now available. This maintenance release fixes 28 issues reported on version 1.7.1.
Version 1.7.1.1, released in April, brought a lot of needed updates to v1.7.1.0, two weeks after the release of that new minor version. As a patch version, 1.7.1.2 brings further goodness and stability to the 1.7.1 branch.
Some of the most notable fixes are:
Add a scrollbar for editor Fix for CMS tree on sitemap Refresh product line on quantity change in cart &amp;amp; Show discount to cart summary Use composer cacert file by default Upgrade theme modules &amp;amp; disabling them in the same time that the theme Download PrestaShop 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release of PrestaShop 1.7.1.1 </title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-1-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 05:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-1-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.1.1 is now available. This maintenance release closes more than 20 of the most pressing issues reported since v1.7.1.0.
Version 1.7.1.0, released two weeks ago, was a step forward for PrestaShop 1.7, bringing more performance and stability to the whole codebase, as well as some new features and several native modules, among which the long-awaited PayPal module.
We received a lot of feedback from the community as soon as PrestaShop 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new regarding translations in PrestaShop 1.7.1.0</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/2017-03-15-translation-news-171/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/2017-03-15-translation-news-171/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 1.7.1.0 has been shipped with several new features to improve internationalization and localization. Here is a short tour of what&amp;rsquo;s new and how it makes things better for you, both as a merchant and a translator!
Daily language packs update Previously translation packs were updated manually on our side, and at this frequency:
1.6 - every two weeks 1.7 - every Monday This wasn&amp;rsquo;t convenient for translators who wanted to quickly see their contribution into production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.1.0 is available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-1-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-1-7-1-0-available/</guid>
      <description>Many of you have been waiting for it: PrestaShop 1.7.1.0 is now available, and it is all you&amp;rsquo;ve ever wanted v1.7 to be!
The feedback we received from the beta version of v1.7.1.0 was very conclusive, and we are happy to release this new minor version of PrestaShop (in the SemVer sense of the word) this April &amp;ndash; a few days later than we initially expected.
Download 1.7.1.0 now! Let’s dive in, shall we?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test the updated 1-Click Upgrade module!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/updated-1-click-upgrade-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/updated-1-click-upgrade-module/</guid>
      <description>After much work and hair-pulling, we finally did it: the 1-Click Upgrade module supports upgrading from 1.6 to 1.7.1.0. Are you ready to test it before the release?
This is your chance to try your hand at the updated 1-Click Upgrade module! We’ve tested it in many configurations, but there’s nothing like community feedback!
Download the update 1-Click upgrade module now! The story so far Those of you who follow our Git history know this: the ‘autoupgrade’ project had not received serious attention for a long time when the team started cleaning up the code in November 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
