<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LouiseBonnard on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/LouiseBonnard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in LouiseBonnard on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 09:10:11 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/LouiseBonnard/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contributor interview: Pululu Kinanga André</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/contributor-interview-pululu-kinanga-andre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/contributor-interview-pululu-kinanga-andre/</guid>
      <description>An open source community is more than just pull requests made by faceless strangers. In order to better understand the people who contribute time and skills to the PrestaShop project, we&amp;rsquo;re writing a series of interviews with contributors of all ranges. This week, meet Pululu Kinanga André, one of our great developers on GitHub!
Hi Pululu! First, could you tell us a bit about yourself?
I am Pululu and I come from Angola.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest 2020 is coming</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/hacktoberfest-2020-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/hacktoberfest-2020-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>Open source has its own tradition when fall starts cooling the atmosphere around, Hacktoberfest! Beer is not flowing like water but code is, and it creates more value than any bunch of slightly tipsy people. ;-)
Curated by the American cloud hosting company DigitalOcean, with Intel and DEV, Hacktoberfest happens online every year in October to celebrate open source. It’s pretty simple: for one month, people are encouraged to engage and create at least 4 pull requests for open source projects on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help us write product specifications</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/write-product-specifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/write-product-specifications/</guid>
      <description>Contribution is not only about code. As an open source project, everyone is encouraged to participate in the construction of PrestaShop: you can translate the software in your native language, suggest a new feature, sign up to the User Club and share your experience with the product teams, become an ambassador&amp;hellip; and also write specifications!
Hosted on a dedicated GitHub repository, product specifications are meant to formally describe how features should work on a given page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A definition of the &#39;good first issue&#39; label</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/a-definition-of-the-good-first-issue-label/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 16:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/a-definition-of-the-good-first-issue-label/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, the PrestaShop product team decided to use new leverage to help new contributors participate in the PrestaShop project on GitHub: the &amp;lsquo;good first issue&amp;rsquo; label.
But what is it exactly? And how does it work? Below are some questions raised to give it a proper definition and specify its use:
🤔 What does this label mean? People participating in the PrestaShop project do not have the same purpose, they also do not share the same skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – March 2020 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-march-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-march-2020/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report tells you how the translations of the software evolved in March.
Project news 📆 PrestaShop Day Paris is postponed In the current context related to the coronavirus (COVID-19) outbreak and its spread in Europe, the decision has been made to postpone PrestaShop Day Paris to a later date. It is a preventive measure aimed at preserving the health of all participants and all those involved in the organization of the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – February 2020 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-february-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-february-2020/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report tells you how the translations of the software evolved in February.
Project news 📆 PrestaShop Day Madrid is postponed In the current context related to the coronavirus Covid-19 outbreak and its spread in Europe, we have decided to postpone the PrestaShop Day Madrid to a later date. This decision is a preventive measure aimed at preserving the health of all participants and all those involved in the organization of the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop keeps growing internationally</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-keeps-growing-internationally/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-keeps-growing-internationally/</guid>
      <description>No need to repeat it: PrestaShop is an international solution. We aim at providing highly global features for worldwide users, and it means providing many useful localization packs containing correct and up-to-date information.
A localization pack is a file providing, for a given country, basic local information such as currencies, states, taxes, languages, measure units, etc. Since the first 1.7.0 release in 2016, those packs have never been cleaned nor updated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – January 2020 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-january-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-january-2020/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report tells you how the translations of the software evolved in January.
Project news 📅 PrestaShop Days are coming back Save the date(s) and plan your visit! Our famous PrestaShop Days are coming back in 2020 and the first announced are Paris and Madrid. Book either your June 4th at the Palais Brongniart in Paris right here or your April 16th at La Nave in Madrid there to meet the PrestaShop teams and the whole ecosystem around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the fuzzy search</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/introduction-to-the-fuzzy-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/introduction-to-the-fuzzy-search/</guid>
      <description>It is always great to see contributions from our community merged, it reminds the power of working on an open-source project. Especially when there are great features at stake, like the fuzzy search.
In this case, we are talking about the Levenshtein algorithm. It should be available in version 1.7.7 thanks to Lathanao and it will definitely improve both the user experience and the conversion rate on your site! Wow, but what is it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – December 2019 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-december-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/do-you-speak-prestashop-december-2019/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report tells you how the translations of the software evolved in December.
Project news ✨ Best wishes for 2020 It is that time of the year, so let us send you our best wishes for 2020! We know it is not celebrated everywhere yet but it is never too early to do so: have a happy new year, with love from family and friends, challenging and fulfilling professional opportunities and great vibes in your everyday life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributor interview: Tantely Rabevohitra</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/contributor-interview-tantely-rabevohitra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/contributor-interview-tantely-rabevohitra/</guid>
      <description>An open source community is more than just PR made by faceless strangers. In order to better understand the people who contribute time and skills to the PrestaShop project, we&amp;rsquo;re writing a series of interviews with contributors of all ranges. This week, meet Tantely Rabevohitra, one of our great translators!
Hi Tantely! First, could you tell us a bit about yourself?
I come from Madagascar, I arrived in France in 2003 to continue my studies, a master of research in Human-Computer Interaction and a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Network and Information Systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – November 2019 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/do-you-speak-prestashop-november-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/do-you-speak-prestashop-november-2019/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report tells you how the translations of the software evolved in November.
Project news 🚀 Further international Since we want to keep PrestaShop as a growing international software, a rework has been driven this summer on all 1.7 localization packs; first to gather all the information they contain and then to optimize it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – October 2019 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2019/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report tells you how the translations of the software evolved in October.
Project news 👋 New bunch of goodies Here it goes again: the last goodies session of 2019 has happened, well done everybody! Our Crowdin’s best translators for those past three months have all been reached to be sent a few goodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – September 2019 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/do-you-speak-prestashop-september-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/do-you-speak-prestashop-september-2019/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report tells you how the translations of the software evolved in September.
Project news 💪 Go full 1.7! Since version 1.6 is not maintained by PrestaShop anymore (read this post to learn more about it if you missed the information), we feel that it will be more relevant to only mention the 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – August 2019 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/do-you-speak-prestashop-august-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/do-you-speak-prestashop-august-2019/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report tells you how the translations of the software evolved in August.
Project news Emails are now available for translation Hello all, I hope summertime was fine for each of you. A lot happened on Crowdin lately: exceptionally, the 1.7.6 catalog has been pushed again to be finally completed. Indeed, a bug prevented email translation&amp;hellip; which was quite annoying, sorry for this quick inconvenience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
