<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JulieVarisellaz on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/JulieVarisellaz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JulieVarisellaz on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/JulieVarisellaz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – October 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about coding, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in October 2023.
Project news Developer Conference in Paris We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the translation project at the Developer Conference on November 30, 2023 in Paris, France. If you’re attending the event, meet us at 3 pm in the Tech room. See you there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – September 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-september-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-september-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about coding, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in September 2023.
Project news New strings are ready for translation As you may have noticed, new strings were added to Crowdin on September 28. It&amp;rsquo;s usually not possible to add new strings outside the release of a minor or major version of PrestaShop but we had to do it to fix a bug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – July 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-july-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-july-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in July!
Project news 💕 Many thanks to newcomers Many people subscribe to the project(s) of their choice each month, but not so many start translating straight away. For that reason, we would like to thank Francisco GP who rushed into the efforts immediately!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – June 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-june-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-june-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in June!
Project news 💕 Many thanks to newcomers Many people subscribe to the project(s) of their choice each month, but not so many start translating straight away. For that reason, we would like to thank Michał Boruta and joeurassa , who rushed into the efforts immediately!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – May 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-may-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-may-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in May!
Project news 💕 Many thanks to newcomers Many people subscribe to the project(s) of their choice each month, but not so many start translating straight away. For that reason, we would like to thank teratux, who rushed into the efforts immediately!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jonathan Danse: module developer and one of the first contributors</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-jonathan-danse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-jonathan-danse/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. This month, meet Jonathan Danse, aka PrestaEdit.
Jonathan is a module developer. He’s also one of the first contributors to the PrestaShop project. It all started, somewhat by chance, during a job interview 12 years ago. In this article, Jonathan talks about his experience with PrestaShop, his work as a module developer, and his dedication to the open source project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – April 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-april-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-april-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in April!
Project news ➕ New strings were added to Crowdin to fix a bug As you may have noticed, 42 new strings were added to Crowdin on May 6. It is usually not possible to add new strings outside the release of a minor or major version of PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julius Zukauskas: Partner Agency Employee and Top Contributor</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-julius-zukauskas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-julius-zukauskas/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. This month, meet Julius Zukauskas, aka zuk3975.
Julius comes from Lithuania. He works at Invertus, an ecommerce agency with a Platinum partner status in the PrestaShop Agency Partner program. Half of his time is dedicated to the open source project, and more specifically to the Symfony migration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – March 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-march-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-march-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in March!
Project news 💬 Contributor interviews Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub or a Crowdin username? Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merchant, freelance developer, and top contributor: Daniel Hlaváček’s experience with the PrestaShop project</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-daniel-hlavacek/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-daniel-hlavacek/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. This month, meet Daniel Hlaváček, aka Hlavtox.
Daniel spends most of his time managing his family business’ online stores. The rest of the time, he works as a freelance developer for 10 clients, whose stores are all based on PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jean-François Viguier: a top contributor and a friend of PrestaShop</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-jean-francois-viguier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-jean-francois-viguier/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. This month, meet Jean-François Viguier, aka jf-viguier.
Co-founder of an ecommerce and coding agency in Toulouse (France), Jean-François is also the vice-president of Friends of Presta, an association that gathers a community of developers and integrators around the open-source ecommerce solution PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – February 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-february-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-february-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in February!
Project news Your pictures of the reward program Between September and December 2021, Mahmoud Parvazi has translated 3,306 words. This allowed him to level up, from the Traveller to the Backpacker level, and enter the reward program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lorenz Meyer: a dedicated contributor supported by his employer</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-lorenz-meyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-lorenz-meyer/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. This month, meet Lorenz Meyer, aka @lmeyer1.
Lorenz answered my questions from Romanel-sur-Lausanne, Switzerland. With 46 contributions, he ranks 119th in the top contributor list. In addition to participating in his personal enrichment, his contribution to the open source project is also encouraged and supported by his employer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – January 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-january-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-january-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in January!
Project news Top contributors, watch your mailbox! 📫 On January 18, the packages were sent to our top translators, as part of the translator reward program. So if you are concerned, watch your mailbox and remember to send a picture to translation@prestashop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From contributor to maintainer: Krystian Podemski&#39;s experience with the PrestaShop project</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-krystian-podemski/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-krystian-podemski/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, a series of contributor interviews was published on the blog. It was a nice way of putting faces to names and getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. And this year, we wanted to do it again. So here we go: this section is back on the blog!
For the first interview of the year 2022, let’s meet Krystian Podemski.
Krystian is 31.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
