<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>news on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in news on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris: Program and Registration</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-agenda-registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-agenda-registration/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re a PrestaShop developer or enthusiast looking to broaden your knowledge and connect with fellow community members, the PrestaShop Developer Conference is the event for you.
Scheduled for November 30, 2023, in Paris, France, the conference promises an in-depth exploration of technical topics, innovative solutions, and ample opportunities to network and engage with peers who share your passion for PrestaShop. We&amp;rsquo;re also very happy to go over the recent unveiling of the agenda, packed with compelling sessions and engaging activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PrestaShop Developer Conference is coming to Paris!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-coming-to-paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-coming-to-paris/</guid>
      <description>Are you a passionate PrestaShop developer or enthusiast, wanting to expand your knowledge and network within the community? The PrestaShop team is happy to let you know the call for presentations is open for the PrestaShop Developer Conference, taking place in Paris, France on November 30, 2023. This event promises to be an opportunity to engage in technical discussions, discover solutions, and connect with like-minded peers in the community.
So, what is the PrestaShop Developer Conference?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 9 minimum PHP version will be PHP8.1</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-9-min-php-version-will-be-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-9-min-php-version-will-be-81/</guid>
      <description>The develop branch contains the source code that will give birth to PrestaShop 9. This is the future of PrestaShop: it will be released either at the end of the year 2023 or at the beginning of the year 2024 and must carry on the ambition of the project for 2024. This major version must also embrace the change in the PHP ecosystem, and consequently, it must drop the support of obsolete PHP versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Organization For The Open Source Project</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/a-new-organization-for-the-open-source-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/a-new-organization-for-the-open-source-project/</guid>
      <description>Today, I want to share the new organization for decision-making that will be set up for the PrestaShop project. We believe this organization will help our community grow, get even more involved, and work together in building a better PrestaShop, faster.
Why do we need a new organization? During the last years, we have been observing a steady growth in the number of community pull requests being merged every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 is now in feature freeze</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-feature-freeze/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-feature-freeze/</guid>
      <description>As of February 1, 2023, PrestaShop version 8.1 has entered the feature freeze phase. This article provides more information about the feature freeze, what the next steps will be, and what to expect from PrestaShop 8.1.
Feature freeze for PrestaShop 8.1 As of today, PrestaShop version 8.1 has entered a feature freeze. What is a feature freeze? Feature freeze refers to a specific stage in the software development process after which no new features can be added to a version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Discussions are now enabled in the PrestaShop Project!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/github-discussions-are-now-enabled-in-the-prestashop-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/github-discussions-are-now-enabled-in-the-prestashop-project/</guid>
      <description>Today, GitHub Discussions are being enabled for the PrestaShop Project. This feature will provide a more organized and easily accessible way for community members to collaborate, ask questions, and share ideas.
What are GitHub Discussions? GitHub Discussions is a new feature in GitHub that provides a space for community members to discuss directly on the project’s GitHub page, similarly to traditional forum boards. This feature is a great way to ask questions, share ideas, and collaborate with other community members, and it has proven its value in other open-source communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An update on the Symfony migration</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/introducing-horizontal-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/introducing-horizontal-migration/</guid>
      <description>In December 2015, a groundbreaking change in PrestaShop was announced: the introduction of the Symfony framework into the CMS. The goal was to gradually replace PrestaShop’s custom framework with Symfony, and switch its templating system from Smarty to Twig. This project was known as “The Symfony migration”. Looking back, we realize that referring to this project as a &amp;ldquo;migration&amp;rdquo; wasn&amp;rsquo;t really accurate at all.
Currently, migrating one page to Symfony involves several steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Version 8.0 Feature Freeze: Important Features</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-feature-freeze-v8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-feature-freeze-v8/</guid>
      <description>Dear developers and contributors,
We are very pleased to be announcing the feature freeze of PrestaShop version 8.0. In this post, we will be looking at the most important features of this feature freeze, letting you know why we have frozen new features and explain what this means for the next few months.
Feature freeze is now effective Therefore, as of today, the feature freeze is now effective and no new features will be added to version 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello 2022, meet our new Front office theme</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/new-theme-announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/new-theme-announce/</guid>
      <description>July 2023: Hummingbird is coming to PrestaShop 9! It has been decided that Hummingbird will be the default theme for PrestaShop 9. You can take an active part in developing this new theme by joining the discussion on Slack, testing the theme, and submitting improvements. Make sure to check out the theme&amp;rsquo;s repository on GitHub. For a long time, many community members have been pushing for a rework of the Classic front-office theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop beyond 1.7</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-beyond-1-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-beyond-1-7/</guid>
      <description>Five years ago, PrestaShop 1.7 was released to the world, introducing Symfony, the Classic theme and child theme features, interface improvements, and so much more. With each one of the eight minor versions that followed, 1.7 kept on growing both in features and stability. Its maturity is recognized by its success: with over 170,000 live shops detected at the time of writing, it’s the most popular PrestaShop version used in production shops on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing TypeScript</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/introducing-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/introducing-typescript/</guid>
      <description>Following a recent Architecture Decision Records (ADR) submission and a Proof of Concept (POC), the Core Maintainers team has decided to introduce TypeScript (TS) on the project.
Why TypeScript? During the last few years, the PrestaShop Project has been increasingly raising the code quality bar. To help maintainers ensure that quality keeps increasing, a number of automatic quality verification tools have been added to the CI pipeline:
ESLint analyzes the whole JavaScript codebase to ensure it follows our code style and find problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heads up: old development branches are going away</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/old-branches-are-going-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/old-branches-are-going-away/</guid>
      <description>The month of June is fast approaching, so it&amp;rsquo;s time for a late Spring clean!
On June 1st, 2021 we will delete all branches from our main repository that are no longer subject to new releases.
The affected branches are:
1.7.0.x 1.7.1.x 1.7.2.x 1.7.3.x 1.7.4.x 1.7.5.x 1.7.6.x Future branches will be deleted as well once they will become stale (e.g. 1.7.7.x will be deleted shortly after 1.7.8 is out).
Important note: Please be aware that this is a routine cleanup and has absolutely no impact on source code availability for previous versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop is now available on Composer</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-available-composer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-available-composer/</guid>
      <description>Released almost 10 years ago, Composer is the most popular package manager for the PHP ecosystem. PrestaShop has been using it since 1.7.0 to manage its dependencies, including all the native modules.
Today we are announcing the general availability of PrestaShop itself through Composer. Thanks to this, it is now possible to easily create a new PrestaShop project from the command line, like this:
composer create-project prestashop/prestashop Or, if you want to download a specific version instead of the latest release:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focusing on essential modules</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/focusing-on-essential-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/focusing-on-essential-modules/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, the PrestaShop project became host and maintainer for a very large number of open source modules. Last year, over 160 of them were present in our GitHub organization. As you probably know already, maintaining them requires a lot of work, and the maintainer team&amp;rsquo;s resources are limited. Proof of this is that some of these modules have not been updated in years.
For this reason, the product team recently did a survey of almost 600 PrestaShop users to find out which modules were essential for their business and which ones they used the least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new place to contribute to the PrestaShop project and share your feedback on the next features</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/productboard-portal-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/productboard-portal-launch/</guid>
      <description>As announced here, the Core product team recently adopted a new working tool to gather feedback and prioritize features: Productboard. No more teasing, it is now time to have a look at how it will look and how we will all be able to handle it!
Productboard makes two things possible for the team:
On the one hand, having a dedicated internal interface to centralize all feedback, group them into topics, define features, and prioritize them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
