<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>news on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in news on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Call for Speakers: PrestaShop Developer Conference Returns in November 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-speakers-prestashop-developer-conference-november-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/call-for-speakers-prestashop-developer-conference-november-2025/</guid>
      <description>We are very excited to announce that the call for presentations is now open for the third edition of the PrestaShop Developer Conference, happening on November 19, 2025 in Paris, France and virtually.
This event is your chance to engage with the tech community, participate in discussions, explore more practical solutions, and connect with other professionals from the community.
What is the PrestaShop Developer Conference? The PrestaShop Developer Conference is an event that brings together developers, product teams, and agency leaders to share insights, collaborate, and grow within the PrestaShop ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSDevCon2024: Cybersecurity – What No One Dares to Say</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/PSDevCon2024-Cybersecurity-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/PSDevCon2024-Cybersecurity-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Application security is often a forgotten aspect of the digital world. Everyone agrees that it is essential, but no one really wants to face its consequences. Today, in this guest blog post, it&amp;rsquo;s time to share the truths that no one wants to say.
This PrestaShop Developer Conference 2024 guest blog post is authored by Vincent Guesnard from TouchWeb and summarizes the presentation given during the event.
1. Why does no one want to publish vulnerabilities?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOP Days 2025 - a wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/fop-days-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/fop-days-2025/</guid>
      <description>The 2025 edition of Friends of Presta (FOP) Days has come to an end, leaving behind two days of discussions, technical insights, and networking. Held on March 26-27 at Le Nida in Issy-les-Moulineaux, the event brought together developers, agencies, and ecommerce professionals from the PrestaShop community.
Collaboration and improving expertise Organized by Friends of Presta, a French non-profit association in the PrestaShop ecosystem, this event was all about collaboration and innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSDevCon 2024 - testing and analyzing your PrestaShop modules automatically</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/testing-and-analyzing-your-prestashop-modules-automatically/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/testing-and-analyzing-your-prestashop-modules-automatically/</guid>
      <description>During the PrestaShop Developer Conference 2024, Jonathan Danse presented methods for automatically testing and analyzing modules, ensuring their quality and reliability. In this guest article, Jonathan shares the key points from his conference and offers practical advice. Learn how to ensure high-performing modules with every deployment.
You can find the sources for the module created in this article on the following GitHub repository: PrestaEdit/modulenine. Jonathan, the floor is now yours!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSDevCon 2024 - PUIK (PrestaShop UI Kit) - The new UI kit from PrestaShop</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/puik-the-new-ui-kit-from-prestashop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/puik-the-new-ui-kit-from-prestashop/</guid>
      <description>During the second PrestaShop Developer Conference on November 6, 2024, I was able to introduce PUIK (PrestaShop UI Kit) to participants. This blog post provides a written summary of the presentation. During the talk, the audience gained a clearer understanding of PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s UI Kit, based on the new PrestaShop Design System. Learn how this library aims to provide a complete set of reusable components for the entire PrestaShop ecosystem. The GitHub repository is available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Synopsis - PrestaShop Developer Conference 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-developer-conference-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-developer-conference-2024/</guid>
      <description>On November 6, 2024, the PrestaShop developer community gathered in Paris for a day of learning and networking at the second PrestaShop Developer Conference. The agenda was filled with insightful sessions and demonstrations. The event provided a platform to grow and learn more about PrestaShop’s ecosystem, get project information as well as explore advancements usable in daily professional activities.
Insightful sessions during the day Throughout the day, the main stage hosted presentations by experts in the PrestaShop community, who shared insights on optimizing performance, leveraging advanced new Admin APIs, implementing continuous integration and workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Register Now for the PrestaShop Developer Conference 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/register-for-the-prestashop-developer-conference-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/register-for-the-prestashop-developer-conference-2024/</guid>
      <description>The world of ecommerce is constantly evolving, and staying on top of the latest trends and innovations is essential for developers and businesses. That’s why we are thrilled to invite you to the second edition of the PrestaShop Developer Conference, taking place on November 6, 2024, in Paris.
Why Attend the Conference? The PrestaShop Developer Conference is more than just a series of presentations - it’s a space where passionate developers come together to exchange ideas, learn from one another, and engage with some of the leading voices in the PrestaShop community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OW2 Webinar - PrestaShop Presentation on September 26</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/OW2WebinarPrestaShopPresentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 09:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/OW2WebinarPrestaShopPresentation/</guid>
      <description>On September 26, the OW2 organization will hold a webinar, presented in part by Clément Désiles from PrestaShop.
During this event, PrestaShop will be presenting alongside ALLMA, a project based on the /e/OS fork of Android and integrating the best of open source modern LLMs. The project is sponsored by a European fund, NGI Search. Pierre-Yves Gibello, OW2’s CEO, will be introducing the webinar at the beginning of the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second PrestaShop Developer Conference - Participate as a Speaker</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/Second-PrestaShop-Developer-Conference-Participate-as-Speaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 09:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/Second-PrestaShop-Developer-Conference-Participate-as-Speaker/</guid>
      <description>Are you a passionate PrestaShop developer or enthusiast? We are happy to announce that the call for presentations is now open for the second edition of the PrestaShop Developer Conference, happening on November 6, 2024 in Paris, France. This event offers a prime opportunity to engage in developer discussions, better understand solutions, and connect with fellow community members.
What is this event about? The PrestaShop Developer Conference empowers the developer community within the PrestaShop ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying releases with a single Zip</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/new-zip-distribution-channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/new-zip-distribution-channel/</guid>
      <description>As we continue to evolve and adapt to the global e-commerce landscape, we are implementing changes to streamline our operations and enhance our project’s trajectory. In 2022, we aimed to make PrestaShop a company-neutral open source project. Today, while keeping the project neutral, we are changing how we distribute the PrestaShop solution, starting with the upcoming 9.0 release.
One release, one Zip As you know, versions are distributed as two separate Zips, one on GitHub and a later one on prestashop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSDevCon 2023: Do you speak PrestaShop?</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/do-you-speak-prestashop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/do-you-speak-prestashop/</guid>
      <description>Do you speak PrestaShop? On November 30, Nicolas Lœuillet and Julie Varisellaz gave a presentation about the project’s translations at the first-ever PrestaShop Developer Conference.
Their presentation aimed to explain the path of a translation string, from the code to the merchant’s back office. The presentation was in French, but we’re happy to share a summary in English on the blog. Let’s get started!
Crowdin: Localization management platform There are 2 ways of translating your PrestaShop store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSDevCon 2023: PrestaShop News - Where We Are And Where We’re Going</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-news-where-we-are-and-where-we-are-going/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-news-where-we-are-and-where-we-are-going/</guid>
      <description>The PrestaShop Developer Conference happened on the 30th of November 2023. During the day, I was able to present a conference, titled “PrestaShop news - Where we are and where we&amp;rsquo;re going”. This blog post is a written version of the presentation that I also partially presented at the December Live Update on December 20th.
This post does not cover the first part of the presentation titled “PrestaShop 8.1 &amp;amp; 2023 - What’s new” because PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris: Synopsis Of The Day</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-developer-conference-2023/</guid>
      <description>The European community of PrestaShop developers gathered to talk code, commerce and also open source in Paris, on November 30, 2023, at the PrestaShop Developer Conference. It was so exciting to see approximately 150 people come to follow conferences and other technical presentations, as well as network during the day.
PrestaShop Developer Conference 2023 The event opened its doors at 9AM and very quickly the venue filled up. Attendees were able to enjoy breakfast before diving into the day&amp;rsquo;s introduction in the main room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Branding For The Project</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/new-project-branding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/new-project-branding/</guid>
      <description>This week will see some changes with the Project. PrestaShop SA, the company, is making the open source Project consistent with the new PrestaShop branding.
New PrestaShop Project branding Unveiled earlier this year, PrestaShop launched its new brand identity to affirm PrestaShop’s strengths, showing more credibility and trust.
Therefore, in the next few days, to align with this new identity, all materials related to the Project will change. You’ll see the rebranded Project’s website, developer documentation, this blog, and other Project-related content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hooks in the Hummingbird theme</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/hummingbird-theme-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/hummingbird-theme-hooks/</guid>
      <description>Hummingbird is the new theme set to be introduced in PrestaShop 9. This theme represents a complete overhaul of the Classic theme, featuring a fresh design and new functionalities. The Product Design team at PrestaShop has developed a visual guide to the hooks available in this theme, aimed at simplifying customization for front-end developers who want to work with it.
What is a hook? As described in the developer documentation:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
