<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GericFosse on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/GericFosse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GericFosse on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/GericFosse/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hummingbird v2.0.0 Beta</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/hummingbird-v2-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/hummingbird-v2-beta/</guid>
      <description>We are thrilled to announce the release of Hummingbird v2.0.0 Beta. This milestone is the result of a monumental effort, representing more than 320 commits, 500 file changes, 50,000 additions, and 30,000 deletions. The goal is to deliver a developer-first, lightweight, and modular theme that establishes a new standard for the PrestaShop ecosystem.
Hummingbird will become the new default theme in PrestaShop starting from version 9.1, while the Classic theme will remain available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update Assistant module v7.0.0 is available (Autoupgrade)</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/autoupgrade-v7.0-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/autoupgrade-v7.0-release/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to introduce the latest major release of the Update Assistant module (formerly known as 1-Click Upgrade).
First launched in 2012, this module takes a significant leap forward with this new version, which is the result of several months of development and over 350 merged Pull Requests. As announced at the PrestaShop Developer Conference and on the Live Update in November 2024, this release pushes the boundaries of PrestaShop store updates even further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autoupgrade module v6.1.0 and 6.2.0 are Available (1-Click Upgrade)</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/autoupgrade-v6.1-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/autoupgrade-v6.1-release/</guid>
      <description>In the footsteps of the latest module releases (see version 6.0.0 release blogpost), these versions bring a number of improvements to streamline PrestaShop updates. Explore the changelog below to find out what version 6.1.0 and 6.2.0 bring to the upgrade module.
What’s inside Global improvements: Version comparison - Fix an issue on the PHP version check before starting an upgrade, which was reporting some valid versions as incompatible. Version comparison - Fix an issue where the number of altered or deleted core files is always zero.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autoupgrade module v6.0.0 is Available (1-Click Upgrade)</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/autoupgrade-v6-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/autoupgrade-v6-release/</guid>
      <description>In the footsteps of the latest module releases (see versions 5.0.2 and 5.0.3 live presentation), this version brings a number of improvements to streamline PrestaShop updates. Explore the changelog below to find out what version 6.0.0 brings to the Autoupgrade module.
What’s inside Global improvements: Ensure update path - Optimization of the upgrade path to the latest version of PrestaShop 8 when using the minor channel. Enable usage &amp;amp; error analytics - Introduce anonymous analytics with Segment and voluntary error reporting based on Sentry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
