<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>i18n on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/i18n/</link>
    <description>Recent content in i18n on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/i18n/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – October 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about coding, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in October 2023.
Project news Developer Conference in Paris We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the translation project at the Developer Conference on November 30, 2023 in Paris, France. If you’re attending the event, meet us at 3 pm in the Tech room. See you there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – September 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-september-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-september-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about coding, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in September 2023.
Project news New strings are ready for translation As you may have noticed, new strings were added to Crowdin on September 28. It&amp;rsquo;s usually not possible to add new strings outside the release of a minor or major version of PrestaShop but we had to do it to fix a bug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – August 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-august-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-august-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in August 2023.
Project news Some updates on the translation project Starting September 18th 2023, the PrestaShop translation project will be managed by both @Julievrz and @axel.viersac. As such, they will be the ones taking care of everything related to the project, including this newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – July 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-july-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-july-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in July.
Project news 🇯🇵/ 🇧🇦Looking for Japanese/Bosnian translators and proofreaders 🇯🇵The Japanese translation project is looking for translators and proofreaders! If you wish to join efforts and help contributor momo-i translate PrestaShop into Japanese — or if you simply want to ask a question, send me a message on Crowdin or on Slack!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – June 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-june-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-june-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in June.
Project news 🌍 Translating the PrestaShop documentation If you didn’t know, you can help translate the PrestaShop 8 documentation into your own language! For now, the PrestaShop 8 docs are only available in English and French, but if you wish to help translate it, let me know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – May 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-may-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-may-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it&amp;rsquo;s also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in May.
Project news 🧰 The QA checker is up and running! The Quality Assurance checker is now enabled on the translation project.
It doesn’t change anything to the current translation process, but it does add a final check to make sure translation strings don’t contain any typos or missing variables, among other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 is ready for translation</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-81-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-81-translations/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop’s 8.1 beta release was announced a few months ago. The stable release is now just around the corner. While it brings new features, a new version also means new strings. A file containing all 8.1 strings has been pushed to Crowdin, and is ready for translation!
8.1 strings are available for translation Translators, proofreaders… your project needs you! Feel free to take a look at those new strings and help your language reach 100% translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – April 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-april-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-april-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in April.
Project news 📖 Coming soon: PrestaShop 8.1 translation catalog!
The PrestaShop 8.1 translation catalog will be uploaded to Crowdin soon, meaning that you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to translate PrestaShop 8.1 into your language. And, as usual, an article will be released to list all particularities of these new strings and add a bit of context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – March 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-march-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-march-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in March.
Project news 🎤 Contributor interviews are back! You’ve read that right – contributor interviews are back! The first interview sheds light on PrestaShop ambassador, merchant and contributor AmirRzd, who’s been contributing to the translation project for nearly 8 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – February 2023 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/2023-03-02-do-you-speak-prestashop-february-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/2023-03-02-do-you-speak-prestashop-february-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in February!
Project news 🌐 The top translators page is back up After a short interruption due to a bug, the top translators page is now back up and running! This is where you&amp;rsquo;ll find the top contributors of the translation project, sorted by translated words as well as the progress of every language and fully translated languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – January 2023 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-january-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-january-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in January!
Project news ➕ A new language is available for translation! Thanks to Ali Zhumagaliev, the Karakalpak language is now available for translation on the Crowdin project!
💕 Many thanks to January’s newcomers Many people subscribe to the project(s) of their choice each month, but not so many start translating straight away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – December 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-december-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-december-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in December!
Project news ➕ The PrestaShop project 2022 retrospective 🎉 2023 is here, happy new year! Thank you all for your contributions. With the help of every single one of you, PrestaShop 8.0 was released on October 26, 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – November 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-november-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-november-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in November!
Project news ➕ Our translation guide is now available 🎉 Christmas draws near. We teased our little gift last month and it is finally here (drumrolls): the translation guide to PrestaShop software is now available. The guide has everything you need to get started or dig deeper into the Crowdin project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – October 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in October!
Project news ➕ PrestaShop 8 is now available to the world 🎉 PrestaShop 8 is here! While it’s been translated into multiple languages already (thank you all for your contributions!), new translation strings are added regularly, so keep an eye out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – September 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-september-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-september-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in September!
Project news ➕ PrestaShop 8 strings are ready for translation PrestaShop 8 is just around the corner! The new strings are still available for translation. You are more than welcome to help contribute to the project and bring PrestaShop 8 to the world!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
