<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>live-update on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/live-update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in live-update on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/live-update/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - October 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-october-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-october-2024/</guid>
      <description>On October 30th, 2024, we hosted another Live Update for the PrestaShop Project with the latest news, announcements, and some insights into the project&amp;rsquo;s future.
PrestaShop Live Update - October 2024 During this Live Update, I presented the latest news about the project, including the release of PrestaShop 8.2, progress on PrestaShop 9, and changes in the PrestaShop developer documentation.
I also talked about the PrestaShop Developer Conference agenda and introduced you to the PrestaShop Project Newsletter, a new initiative we launched recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update October 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-october-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-october-2024/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while but the next Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2024 will be back on Wednesday, October 30th, 2024 at 4pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
In the upcoming Live Update, we will provide updates on the latest developments in the PrestaShop Project, including PrestaShop 8.2, version 9 and more. It will also be a great occasion to discuss the PrestaShop Developer Conference 2024 in detail and tell you more about our plans for the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - June 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-june-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-june-2024/</guid>
      <description>On June 19th, 2024, we hosted the fifth Live Update of the year. We had the opportunity to talk about PrestaShop 9 and get to know the team working on, among other things, the PrestaShop autoupgrade module.
PrestaShop Live Update - June 2024 During this Live Update, we had the opportunity to meet the Seamless Upgrade &amp;amp; Extensibility team, who are actively involved in various projects within the PrestaShop ecosystem. One of their key focuses is the development of the PrestaShop autoupgrade module, which plays a crucial role in system upgrades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update June 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-june-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-june-2024/</guid>
      <description>The next Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2024 will happen on Wednesday, June 19th, 2024 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
We will present an overview of the recently released PrestaShop 9 Alpha. This session will cover some of the new features and improvements introduced in this latest version.
Additionally, the Seamless Upgrade &amp;amp; Extensibility team from PrestaShop SA will join us to share their latest projects, with a focus on the recent improvements to the autoupgrade module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - April 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-april-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-april-2024/</guid>
      <description>Participants were able to know about the PrestaShop Performance project, which aims to enhance loading times and reliability of the PrestaShop solution by discovering and tackling key performance issues.
PrestaShop Live Update - April 2024 In our fourth Live Update, our special guest, Elyes Naouar, QA Performance Specialist at PrestaShop, introduced the community to the PrestaShop Performance project. This initiative is focused on identifying, measuring, and addressing performance issues to improve the loading times and reliability of the PrestaShop solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update April 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-april-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-april-2024/</guid>
      <description>The next Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2024 will happen on Wednesday, April 17th, 2024 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
In the upcoming Live Update, we will be providing updates on the latest developments in the PrestaShop Project, including PrestaShop 8.1.5 and the upcoming version 9. Additionally, we are excited to announce a presentation introducing the Performance Project by QA Performance Specialist from PrestaShop SA, @elyesnaouar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - March 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-march-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-march-2024/</guid>
      <description>In our third Live Update this year, we reviewed the already implemented compatibility of PrestaShop with Symfony Framework 6.4, focusing on its impact and the backward incompatible changes it introduces.
PrestaShop Live Update - March 2024 In this Live Update, Morgan Pichat, one of the core developers at PrestaShop SA, delivered a presentation showing some of the details and challenges regarding the integration of Symfony 6.4 into PrestaShop 9.
Morgan highlighted some of the significant changes for solution authors in the PrestaShop ecosystem following the upgrade and the challenges overcome during this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update March 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-march-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-march-2024/</guid>
      <description>The third Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2024 will happen on Wednesday, March 13th, 2024 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
In the upcoming Live Update, we turn our attention to PrestaShop 9, a version yet to be released. We&amp;rsquo;ll explore the significant breaking changes introduced in this new version. @M0rgan01 will specifically address the backward incompatible changes due to the new Symfony Framework version, changes that are especially relevant for module developers using the Symfony Framework in their solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - February 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-february-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-february-2024/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the second time in 2024. Read on for a recap of the session.
PrestaShop Live Update - February 2024 The second live update in 2024 was held on February 7th, 2024. During the session, we had two presentations.
Fabien Vallon, Lead Product Manager at PrestaShop, provided an exciting glimpse into the upcoming Core Upgrade application. This tool, set to be released later this year, promises to streamline the PrestaShop upgrade process, and we can&amp;rsquo;t wait to share more details with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update February 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-february-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-february-2024/</guid>
      <description>The second Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2024 will happen on Wednesday, February 7th, 2024 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
The upcoming Live Update in February 2024 will feature the presentation of two very interesting subjects!
Fabien Vallon who is Lead Product Manager at PrestaShop will present an overview of the new Core Upgrade tool that is planned to be released this year.
We will also have a special guest, Tomas Ilginis, a developer from Invertus, one of the leading agencies specializing in PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - January 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-january-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-january-2024/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held the first time in 2024 and streamed live on January 17th, 2024.
PrestaShop Live Update - January 2024 The first Live Update in 2024 was a chance to show the community yet another presentation from PrestaShop Developer Conference, present new patch versions, and answer some questions about the project organization, branding, and the future.
For those who are interested in slides from Łukasz Janik&amp;rsquo;s presentation, he will write a blog post about it soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing PrestaShop Project Live Update January 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-january-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/upcoming-live-update-january-2024/</guid>
      <description>The first Live Update for the PrestaShop Project in 2024 will happen on Wednesday, January 17th, 2024 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
In the first Live Update of the year, we have some news to share, and we will have a special guest. Łukasz Janik from the e-commerce agency Waynet will join us to talk about CI/CD processes for PrestaShop, they use in their projects. This presentation was originally presented during the PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - December 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-10-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/live-update-10-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the tenth time this year and streamed live on December 20th, 2023.
PrestaShop Live Update - December 2023 The first Live Update after a month-long break, due to the PrestaShop Developer Conference, was the occasion for an important announcement, which probably comes as no surprise now that you&amp;rsquo;re reading this blog. The project now has the same branding PrestaShop SA has been using for several months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing December PrestaShop Project Live Update</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-10-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/upcoming-live-update-10-2023/</guid>
      <description>The tenth Live Update for the PrestaShop Project will happen on Wednesday, December 20th, 2023 at 4 pm (Paris time) on YouTube!
This time, we will announce project updates and follow two presentations originally given at the PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris:
PrestaShop news - where we are and where we&amp;rsquo;re going by @matks API OAuth/CQRS in PrestaShop 9 by @jolelievre Join us on YouTube! Remember that at the end of every meeting, there is a Q&amp;amp;A session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Live Update - October 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-9-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/live-update-9-2023/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s live update was held for the ninth time this year and streamed live on October 11th, 2023.
PrestaShop Live Update - October 2023 It was a special Live Update where we said goodbye to the project leader, Pablo Borowicz, who, after over six years, is leaving the PrestaShop company. On behalf of everyone in the project, I would like to thank him for all the work he has done for the project and wish him all the best in his future endeavors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
