<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NeOMakinG on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/NeOMakinG/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NeOMakinG on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/NeOMakinG/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hello 2022, meet our new Front office theme</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/new-theme-announce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/new-theme-announce/</guid>
      <description>July 2023: Hummingbird is coming to PrestaShop 9! It has been decided that Hummingbird will be the default theme for PrestaShop 9. You can take an active part in developing this new theme by joining the discussion on Slack, testing the theme, and submitting improvements. Make sure to check out the theme&amp;rsquo;s repository on GitHub. For a long time, many community members have been pushing for a rework of the Classic front-office theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing TypeScript</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/introducing-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/introducing-typescript/</guid>
      <description>Following a recent Architecture Decision Records (ADR) submission and a Proof of Concept (POC), the Core Maintainers team has decided to introduce TypeScript (TS) on the project.
Why TypeScript? During the last few years, the PrestaShop Project has been increasingly raising the code quality bar. To help maintainers ensure that quality keeps increasing, a number of automatic quality verification tools have been added to the CI pipeline:
ESLint analyzes the whole JavaScript codebase to ensure it follows our code style and find problems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
