<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>core-monthly on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/core-monthly/</link>
    <description>Recent content in core-monthly on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/core-monthly/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - July 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-07-01-2025-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-07-01-2025-07-31/</guid>
      <description>We are back with the July edition of the PrestaShop Core Monthly! 🌞
Dear community,
July has been an exciting month for the PrestaShop project, filled with significant releases, upcoming feature announcements, and continued community engagement. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into what made this summer month particularly productive for our project.
PrestaShop 8.2.2 maintenance release We released PrestaShop 8.2.2 on July 28th, bringing a comprehensive set of bug fixes and improvements to the 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - June 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-06-01-2025-06-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-06-01-2025-06-30/</guid>
      <description>We are back with yet another edition of the PrestaShop Core Monthly, your monthly digest of the PrestaShop codebase&amp;rsquo;s latest changes and news from the PrestaShop project.
PrestaShop 9.0.0 is out! 🎉 June marks the completion of one month since the PrestaShop 9.0.0 release, which is now available for download!
This release is a major milestone for the PrestaShop project, as it brings a lot of new features and improvements. We hope you will enjoy it as much as we do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - March 2025</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-03-01-2025-03-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-03-01-2025-03-31/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s new in the project? We&amp;rsquo;re ending the quarter strong! Project members with the help of the community have been working hard to prepare the next major release of PrestaShop. Release of the completely new version of the Auto Upgrade Update Assistant module, and that&amp;rsquo;s only a glimpse of the work done in March. Read on to learn more about the latest changes in the PrestaShop project.
Stay up to date with the latest developments in the PrestaShop project by reading the Core Monthly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - January</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-01-01-2025-01-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/core-monthly-2025-01-01-2025-01-31/</guid>
      <description>We are back with the first Core Monthly of 2025! 🎉 Discover the latest updates in the PrestaShop project, including new releases, project highlights, community contributions, and more.
Want to stay up to date with the latest developments in the PrestaShop project? Core Monthly is your go-to source for the most important news, updates, and changes in the project. In this edition, we will show you what happened in January 2025.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - February 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/core-monthly-2024-02-01-2024-02-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/core-monthly-2024-02-01-2024-02-29/</guid>
      <description>With over 250 pull requests merged in the project repositories, February was a busy month for the PrestaShop open source project. We released the security patch, PrestaShop 8.1.4, and made significant progress on the new API. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the most important changes in the codebase.
Release of PrestaShop 8.1.4 The 8.1.4 maintenance release of PrestaShop was a dedicated security release. This was the first instance where the decision was made to separate security fixes from other bug fixes and improvements, allowing for a quicker release of the security patch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - January 2024</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/core-monthly-2024-01-01-2024-01-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/core-monthly-2024-01-01-2024-01-31/</guid>
      <description>The first Core Monthly of 2024 is here! 🎉 Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the progress we&amp;rsquo;ve made together in the first month of this promising year.
Release of PrestaShop 8.1.3 and 1.7.8.11 In January we released security updates for PrestaShop 8.1 and 1.7.8. The updates fixed security vulnerabilities discovered by community researchers. We recommend that you update your store to the latest version of PrestaShop to ensure that your store is secure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - November</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-11-01-2023-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-11-01-2023-11-30/</guid>
      <description>November was marked by the first PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris.
PrestaShop Developer Conference On November 30th, PrestaShop organized its first developer conference in Paris. The event was a great success, with around 150 attendees, over 25 speakers, and almost 20 talks. It was a great opportunity to discuss best practices for working with PrestaShop software, exchange experiences between developers and discuss PrestaShop development.
The great turnout proved to everyone we need more events of that type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - October</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-10-01-2023-10-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-10-01-2023-10-31/</guid>
      <description>In this Core Monthly, check out what we&amp;rsquo;ve been up to in October with PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s core and modules. Also, get a sneak peek at the agenda and speakers for the upcoming PrestaShop Developer Conference.
PrestaShop Developer Conference A few weeks ago we closed the call for papers for the conference, and it&amp;rsquo;s time to share with you the agenda as well as speakers for the event. We received a lot of great submissions, and we&amp;rsquo;re excited to share the agenda with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - September</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-09-01-2023-09-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-09-01-2023-09-30/</guid>
      <description>In this article, delve into September&amp;rsquo;s updates and news from the project. As well as Hacktoberfest 2023&amp;rsquo;s kick off, offering a month-long celebration of open-source contributions. Keep reading for more information.
PrestaShop 8.1.2 In September, the project saw the release of PrestaShop 8.1.2. This second patch for the 8.1 series brings two security fixes and addresses over 30 bugs. The release also includes minor enhancements, particularly to the new product page and the multi-format image generation system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - August</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-08-01-2023-08-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-08-01-2023-08-31/</guid>
      <description>A little later than usual, discover the latest happenings in the PrestaShop Project for August 2023. We had a productive month, successfully merging more than 240 pull requests and releasing PrestaShop 8.1.1 and some security patches. Read on to find out more!
PrestaShop 8.1.1, 8.0.5, 1.7.8.10 The first patch for PrestaShop 8.1 and security patches for 8.0.5 and 1.7.8.10 are all available to download. You can read the details about these versions in the release notes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - July 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-07-01-2023-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-07-01-2023-07-31/</guid>
      <description>Read about what has been going on in the PrestaShop Project in July 2023. It was a good month with over 340 merged pull requests! 🎉
Even during the Summer we see a lot of great progress in the PrestaShop Project. In July, we merged over 340 pull requests.
We welcomed three new committers:
Guyomar Alexis (@ga-devfront) Clément Désiles (@jokesterfr) Morgan Pichat (@M0rgan01) You can see all current project members on the updated People and Roles page on the project&amp;rsquo;s website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - June</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-06-01-2023-06-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-06-01-2023-06-30/</guid>
      <description>The new PrestaShop 8.1, ongoing work on PrestaShop 9.0, new content in the developer documentation and more! Read about all this news in the Core Monthly report for June.
PrestaShop 8.1 is out! You read that right! The new PrestaShop 8.1 is out! 🎉 Congratulations to the whole PrestaShop project team, contributors and community members who made this release possible. Version 8.1 is a minor upgrade, with major improvements. The all-new product management page, full support for WebP and Avif and lots of other improvements are waiting for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - May 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-05-01-2023-05-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-05-01-2023-05-31/</guid>
      <description>In May, we released PrestaShop 8.1 RC1, shared some exciting news about PrestaShop 9, and continued improving the core and the modules. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at recent developments in the project in May.
Live Update The last Live Update took place on May 17th. You can read all the details in the summary. We didn&amp;rsquo;t share the date of the next Live Update back then, but we agreed now that we will host the next session on June 21st.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - April 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-04-01-2023-04-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-04-01-2023-04-30/</guid>
      <description>As we enter May, let&amp;rsquo;s recap the key accomplishments within the PrestaShop project during April. We focused on vital security upgrades, namely PrestaShop 8.0.4 and 1.7.8.9, as well as putting the final touches on PrestaShop 8.1. A new project organization was also introduced, and the developer documentation received several updates. Read on to learn more about the latest developments in the PrestaShop project.
New project organization On April 19th, 2023, @eternoendless unveiled &amp;ldquo;a clearer, more transparent, more collaborative organization&amp;rdquo; for the project, that has been under development for the past few months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - March 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-03-01-2023-03-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-03-01-2023-03-31/</guid>
      <description>In this Core Monthly, most important topics include new patch releases for PrestaShop 8, improvements in the developer documentation, data transparency policy, and more. Discover the latest updates on our ongoing projects and catch up on what our project members have been working on throughout the month of March.
Patch releases for PrestaShop 8 Two new versions for PrestaShop 8 are now available. 8.0.2 and 8.0.3 versions were both released a few weeks ago.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
