<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>core-monthly on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/core-monthly/</link>
    <description>Recent content in core-monthly on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/core-monthly/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - November</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-11-01-2023-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-11-01-2023-11-30/</guid>
      <description>November was marked by the first PrestaShop Developer Conference in Paris.
PrestaShop Developer Conference On November 30th, PrestaShop organized its first developer conference in Paris. The event was a great success, with around 150 attendees, over 25 speakers, and almost 20 talks. It was a great opportunity to discuss best practices for working with PrestaShop software, exchange experiences between developers and discuss PrestaShop development.
The great turnout proved to everyone we need more events of that type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - October</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-10-01-2023-10-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-10-01-2023-10-31/</guid>
      <description>In this Core Monthly, check out what we&amp;rsquo;ve been up to in October with PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s core and modules. Also, get a sneak peek at the agenda and speakers for the upcoming PrestaShop Developer Conference.
PrestaShop Developer Conference A few weeks ago we closed the call for papers for the conference, and it&amp;rsquo;s time to share with you the agenda as well as speakers for the event. We received a lot of great submissions, and we&amp;rsquo;re excited to share the agenda with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - September</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-09-01-2023-09-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-09-01-2023-09-30/</guid>
      <description>In this article, delve into September&amp;rsquo;s updates and news from the project. As well as Hacktoberfest 2023&amp;rsquo;s kick off, offering a month-long celebration of open-source contributions. Keep reading for more information.
PrestaShop 8.1.2 In September, the project saw the release of PrestaShop 8.1.2. This second patch for the 8.1 series brings two security fixes and addresses over 30 bugs. The release also includes minor enhancements, particularly to the new product page and the multi-format image generation system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - August</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-08-01-2023-08-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-08-01-2023-08-31/</guid>
      <description>A little later than usual, discover the latest happenings in the PrestaShop Project for August 2023. We had a productive month, successfully merging more than 240 pull requests and releasing PrestaShop 8.1.1 and some security patches. Read on to find out more!
PrestaShop 8.1.1, 8.0.5, 1.7.8.10 The first patch for PrestaShop 8.1 and security patches for 8.0.5 and 1.7.8.10 are all available to download. You can read the details about these versions in the release notes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - July 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-07-01-2023-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-07-01-2023-07-31/</guid>
      <description>Read about what has been going on in the PrestaShop Project in July 2023. It was a good month with over 340 merged pull requests! 🎉
Even during the Summer we see a lot of great progress in the PrestaShop Project. In July, we merged over 340 pull requests.
We welcomed three new committers:
Guyomar Alexis (@ga-devfront) Clément Désiles (@jokesterfr) Morgan Pichat (@M0rgan01) You can see all current project members on the updated People and Roles page on the project&amp;rsquo;s website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - June</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-06-01-2023-06-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-06-01-2023-06-30/</guid>
      <description>The new PrestaShop 8.1, ongoing work on PrestaShop 9.0, new content in the developer documentation and more! Read about all this news in the Core Monthly report for June.
PrestaShop 8.1 is out! You read that right! The new PrestaShop 8.1 is out! 🎉 Congratulations to the whole PrestaShop project team, contributors and community members who made this release possible. Version 8.1 is a minor upgrade, with major improvements. The all-new product management page, full support for WebP and Avif and lots of other improvements are waiting for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - May 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-05-01-2023-05-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-05-01-2023-05-31/</guid>
      <description>In May, we released PrestaShop 8.1 RC1, shared some exciting news about PrestaShop 9, and continued improving the core and the modules. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at recent developments in the project in May.
Live Update The last Live Update took place on May 17th. You can read all the details in the summary. We didn&amp;rsquo;t share the date of the next Live Update back then, but we agreed now that we will host the next session on June 21st.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - April 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-04-01-2023-04-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-04-01-2023-04-30/</guid>
      <description>As we enter May, let&amp;rsquo;s recap the key accomplishments within the PrestaShop project during April. We focused on vital security upgrades, namely PrestaShop 8.0.4 and 1.7.8.9, as well as putting the final touches on PrestaShop 8.1. A new project organization was also introduced, and the developer documentation received several updates. Read on to learn more about the latest developments in the PrestaShop project.
New project organization On April 19th, 2023, @eternoendless unveiled &amp;ldquo;a clearer, more transparent, more collaborative organization&amp;rdquo; for the project, that has been under development for the past few months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - March 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-03-01-2023-03-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-03-01-2023-03-31/</guid>
      <description>In this Core Monthly, most important topics include new patch releases for PrestaShop 8, improvements in the developer documentation, data transparency policy, and more. Discover the latest updates on our ongoing projects and catch up on what our project members have been working on throughout the month of March.
Patch releases for PrestaShop 8 Two new versions for PrestaShop 8 are now available. 8.0.2 and 8.0.3 versions were both released a few weeks ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - February 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-02-01-2023-02-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-02-01-2023-02-28/</guid>
      <description>As we move into March, let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to review the progress made in February across the project. While PrestaShop 8.0.2 and 8.1 are certainly two key priorities, a lot of work has also been put in on other aspects of the project. Nonetheless, the final touches for PrestaShop 8.0.2 are currently underway, and progress on PrestaShop 8.1 continues to move forward steadily. Additionally, several exciting new features have been merged that will be incorporated into PrestaShop 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - January 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-01-01-2023-01-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2023-01-01-2023-01-31/</guid>
      <description>The PrestaShop project had a busy January with a focus on releasing PrestaShop 8.0.1 and final touches for PrestaShop 8.1 before the feature-freeze. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at what happened in the project last month.
Yes, that really was a very busy January! The current dynamic in the project is at the top level. What happened last month?
PrestaShop 8.0.1 PrestaShop 8.0.1 was released on January 6th, and it is the first patch version for PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - December 2022</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2022-12-01-2022-12-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/core-monthly-2022-12-01-2022-12-31/</guid>
      <description>Release of PrestaShop 1.7.8.8 and the autoupgrade module, what&amp;rsquo;s next for PrestaShop 8, an overview of ongoing work, and much more. This Core Monthly summarizes what happened in the project during the month of December.
Dear community,
Welcome to the first Core Monthly of 2023! 2022 was a fantastic year for the PrestaShop project, with a new major release, announcement of the upcoming new theme for PrestaShop, and significant changes to the project&amp;rsquo;s structure, which made it more open than it has ever been.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Monthly - November 2022</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/core-monthly-2022-11-01-2022-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/core-monthly-2022-11-01-2022-11-30/</guid>
      <description>In this Core Monthly, I will focus on a few important topics that are being worked on inside the project, the new product page, initiatives, new releases, and some great contributions from the community.
Dear developers,
Here it is! The first edition of the Core Monthly. I know through community feedback about the impact weekly summaries recently had, this is why it was decided to summarize the entire month in one article to make them more useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Weekly - Week 43 of 2022</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/coreweekly-43-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/coreweekly-43-2022/</guid>
      <description>This edition of the Core Weekly report highlights changes in PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s core codebase from Monday 24th to Sunday 30th of October 2022.
General messages Dear developers,
PrestaShop 8 is available! This is an important moment for everyone involved in the project. All project members would like to thank the community for their involvement in this new version.
The Hummingbird theme maintainers team decided to release its early version. If you are working with PrestaShop themes, this is a great chance to get your hands on this new version to see what the future holds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop Core Weekly - Week 41 of 2022</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/coreweekly-41-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/coreweekly-41-2022/</guid>
      <description>This edition of the Core Weekly report highlights changes in PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s core codebase from Monday 10th to Sunday 16th of October 2022.
General messages Dear developers,
Last week, the maintainers team released PrestaShop 8.0 release candidate 1. You can read more in a dedicated article. If no major or critical regression is reported before October 20th, the final version of 8.0 will be made available later this month.
Releases welcome: v6.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
