<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theme on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/theme/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theme on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
  <language>en-us</language>
      <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/theme/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Hummingbird v2.0.0 Beta Is Available</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/hummingbird-v2-beta/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/hummingbird-v2-beta/</guid>
          <description>We are thrilled to announce the release of Hummingbird v2.0.0 Beta. This milestone is the result of a monumental effort, representing more than 320 commits, 500 file changes, 50,000 additions, and 30,000 deletions. The goal is to deliver a developer-first, lightweight, and modular theme that establishes a new standard for the PrestaShop ecosystem.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Hooks in the Hummingbird theme</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/hummingbird-theme-hooks/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/hummingbird-theme-hooks/</guid>
          <description>Hummingbird is the new theme set to be introduced in PrestaShop 9. This theme represents a complete overhaul of the Classic theme, featuring a fresh design and new functionalities. The Product Design team at PrestaShop has developed a visual guide to the hooks available in this theme, aimed at simplifying customization for front-end developers who want to work with it.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Hello 2022, meet our new Front office theme</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/new-theme-announce/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/new-theme-announce/</guid>
          <description> April 2024: Hummingbird situation In 2023, it was decided that Hummingbird should be implemented in PrestaShop 9. While we would love to see Hummingbird in PrestaShop 9, integrating it as a default theme comes at a price. It impacts the entire ecosystem, and we are currently evaluating the feasibility of this move. We will keep you updated on the progress.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>How to solve the search bar issue after upgrading to PrestaShop 1.7.8</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/misc/178-and-searchbar/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/misc/178-and-searchbar/</guid>
          <description>We have recently been informed that many of you have encountered a display problem with the search bar in Front office, right after upgrading to PrestaShop 1.7.8. This problem also affected shops using the built-in “classic” theme.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>A journey to improve the Time To Interactive metric in Classic Theme</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/journey-to-improve-the-time-to-interactive-metric/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/journey-to-improve-the-time-to-interactive-metric/</guid>
          <description>The project Core Web Vitals from Google has announced that loading time and performance will have an impact on the website ranking in search results. Google mentions lazy loading in their suggestions. Lazy loading will be available on Classic Theme in version 1.7.8 thanks to Progi1984 and it will definitely improve both user experience and loading time on your site!</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Update your store for GDPR</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/update-your-prestashop-store/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/update-your-prestashop-store/</guid>
          <description>Almost all of our merchants have to comply with the law. That’s why we have released the GDPR official module by PrestaShop (1.6 and 1.7 live, 1.5 to be released very soon), helping merchants and contributors to comply with the law.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Parent/Child theme feature in PrestaShop 1.7</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/child-themes-feature/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/child-themes-feature/</guid>
          <description> There is a feature introduced in PrestaShop 1.7.0 that we would like to dive back in: the child theme feature!</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>How to translate your theme in PrestaShop 1.7</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/how-to-translate-your-theme/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/how-to-translate-your-theme/</guid>
          <description> By now you’re probably aware that the 1.7 version comes with a new translation system and that the theme you are building can benefit from it. However, we didn’t give much details on how it works yet, so here is what you should know if you want to translate your theme for PrestaShop 1.7.</description>
        </item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Designing the new PrestaShop default theme</title>
          <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/designing-the-new-prestashop-default-theme/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
            
          <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/designing-the-new-prestashop-default-theme/</guid>
          <description>When merchants use PrestaShop for the first time, they’re offered a basic shop with demo products and a default theme. This basic theme is essential for the merchants to have a clear insight of what their new shop will look like. For the 1.7 version of the software, we’ve decided to revamp this default theme which we called “Classic”.</description>
        </item>
      
  </channel>
</rss>
