<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>addons on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/addons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in addons on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 09:10:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/addons/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Integration Fund is still alive</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/integration-fund-is-still-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/integration-fund-is-still-alive/</guid>
      <description>Dear contributors, remember when, about two years ago, we presented you the Integration Fund? We even made an amazing video where we talk about this no less amazing Integration Fund. Well, we are still here and running, and for all this we would like to thank you.
Now, some of you may be wondering: “Integration Fund? Never heard of it!”. So if you&amp;rsquo;ve missed the previous articles, here is where you should go:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Integration Fund explained by the team and its contributors</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/integration_fund_explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/integration_fund_explained/</guid>
      <description>Still not sure what the Integration Fund is? Take a look at this video:
It is still time to get involved We are very proud of all the contributors we have funded until now. Together, we are building the ecommerce of tomorrow, in the spirit of WeCommerce.
But you know the old saying, the more the merrier :) We still have funds to allocate to many local modules.
Do you want to develop a local module in one of the spots below where you see a target?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A year of our $1M Fund: Already $200,000 granted, and you too can be a part of it!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/a-year-of-our-integration-fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/a-year-of-our-integration-fund/</guid>
      <description>Last year PrestaShop launched its 1$ Million Integration Fund, conceived as a way to support a selection of developers by granting them funds to develop local modules. At the Paris PrestaShop Day 2016, we celebrated the first anniversary of the program.
Here are the figures that we achieved together with contributors from all over the world: $200,000 were granted to fund 130 modules that improve PrestaShop stores in more than 100 countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefit from the $1M Integration Fund to build your own PrestaShop modules</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/prestashop-integration-fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 14:29:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/prestashop-integration-fund/</guid>
      <description>One of the strengths of PrestaShop is how it reaches merchants all around the world through a highly customizable code, a high number of available languages and a rich catalog of local modules. We’re going a step further by making a big effort to offer local modules on PrestaShop Addons marketplace, thanks to the $1 million Integration Fund, launched in June, 2015.
The PrestaShop community is at the heart of this program, with two main goals:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
