<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wording on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/wording/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wording on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 16:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/wording/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Content style guide: a reference for better harmonization</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/content-style-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/content-style-guide/</guid>
      <description>It all started with an observation: contributors brought many new wordings to the PrestaShop open source project but couldn&amp;rsquo;t access clear content guidelines. This led to a lot of inconsistencies. Wording is such an essential element of a good user experience, it was time for a change.
A reference document for writing content When designing a new feature, contributors to the PrestaShop project have to think about the wording: feature labels, help texts, error messages, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we reorganized the main menu in PrestaShop 1.7</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/how-we-reorganized-main-menu-prestashop-1.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 04:29:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/how-we-reorganized-main-menu-prestashop-1.7/</guid>
      <description>Did you think everything had been said about PrestaShop 1.7 version? In our quest towards a simpler interface, the main menu was reorganized, mostly to make it easier for you to navigate in PrestaShop. So here are a few things you should be aware of.
In short:
New sections were created A new wording has been introduced The location of some pages was changed Other pages were gathered as tabs of a main page The method behind the new menu Here’s our recipe to come up with this updated menu:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
