<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>starter-theme on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/starter-theme/</link>
    <description>Recent content in starter-theme on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 09:10:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/starter-theme/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Our plans for the Starter Theme</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/starter-theme-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/starter-theme-plans/</guid>
      <description>With PrestaShop 1.7, theme designers have the choice to either start their work from scratch, rework the Classic theme, or build upon the foundations laid by the Starter Theme. Based on feedback from our community, we want to improve the Starter Theme into something that fits them best.
The idea behind the Starter Theme was pretty simple: make life easier for theme designers, and give them more freedom. Their work process is usually thus: because recreate all the necessary files is complex, they tend to work with the default theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starter Theme: fresh news from the front #3</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/starter-theme-news-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/starter-theme-news-3/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since we gave you any news about the StarterTheme. So, let&amp;rsquo;s sum up what happened since Starter Theme: Fresh News From The Front #2.
Page layout We don&amp;rsquo;t want to impose a 3 columns layout for template developers anymore. We want to make something more flexible. As a theme developer, you will be able to ship your theme with as many layouts as you want. For example you can have a full width layout, 2 columns split in 2 halves or one third/two third.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starter Theme: fresh news from the front #2</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/starter-theme-news-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/starter-theme-news-2/</guid>
      <description>We already have more exciting news about the StarterTheme.
Last week, @djfm came up with a photo to summarize what we aim to do with the StarterTheme:
The StarterTheme is now part of PrestaShop/PrestaShop When we started this project, we wanted to start from scratch so bad that we even wanted to have a standalone Git repository. After few days, we realized it wasn&amp;rsquo;t so easy, because we constantly needed to have the Core repository in sync with the StarterTheme repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starter Theme: fresh news from the front</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/starter-theme-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/starter-theme-news/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a month since PrestaShop announced a new Starter Theme project.
It&amp;rsquo;s an important project, both because it touches on something that&amp;rsquo;s been tricky for many years, namely being able to quickly build a quality and standard-respecting theme from scratch, and because it&amp;rsquo;s truly a project built for and with the community, with a dedicated branch, its own Gitter channel for discussions, and even its own Trello board (yes, outside of the Forge!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re building a Starter Theme for PrestaShop 1.7.0.0</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/starter-theme-kickoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/starter-theme-kickoff/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever tried to create a PrestaShop theme from scratch, you might have noticed it requires quite a large skillset: not only must you know HTML, CSS and Smarty, but you also need to be very familiar with the inner workings of PrestaShop itself. There is a lot of business logic going on in the templates, it is hard to tell apart classes that are used for styling from classes that are used by JavaScript-powered features, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
