<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>contribution on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/contribution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in contribution on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/contribution/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/hacktoberfest-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/hacktoberfest-2023/</guid>
      <description>The month of October is coming quickly! So be prepared for Hacktoberfest, a month-long celebration of open source software.
Hacktoberfest 2023 The online event has been happening every October since 2013 and is sponsored by DigitalOcean. This year marks the 10th anniversary of the event, with changes to help ensure its sustainability for the next decade. You’ll learn about these right below. How can you participate? Very simple: people are encouraged to create at least 4 pull requests for open source projects on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freelance Developer and Translator: Meet SNor42</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-snor42/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-snor42/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who’s hiding behind a Crowdin username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project.
For the second interview of 2023, we interview Norbert, aka SNor42.
Ranked 29th on the top translator page, Norbert is a translator and proofreader on the Hungarian project.
Hello SNor! :-) 👋 Can you tell me more about yourself?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louis Authie: Freelancer, Contributor and Author</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-louis-authie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-louis-authie/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who’s hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project.
This month, meet Louis Authie, aka LouisAUTHIE.
Louis is a freelance full stack developer at Web Helpers, with over 120 contributions on GitHub. He’s also a member of Friends of Presta, an association that gathers a community of developers and integrators around the open source ecommerce solution PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop ambassador, merchant and contributor: meet Amirhossein Rezazadeh</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-amirhossein/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/contributor-interview-amirhossein/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who’s hiding behind a Crowdin username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project.
For the first interview of 2023, I interviewed Amirhossein Rezazadeh, aka AmirRzd.
Ranked 31st on the top translator page, Amirhossein is a translator and proofreader on the Persian project.
Hello AmirRzd! :-) Can you tell us more about yourself?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest and PrestaShop: how you can participate in this 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/hacktoberfest-2022-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/hacktoberfest-2022-started/</guid>
      <description>October is now here and Hacktoberfest, a month-long celebration of open source software, has started. We have recently written an article about the event, how you can get involved and all the different rules. You can know more in our Hacktoberfest 2022 article.
In a few words, participation is very simple: people are encouraged to create at least 4 pull requests for open source projects on GitHub.
How to get started If you are wondering how to get started, we are listing in this blog post issues that could be a good starting point for new contributors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest 2022</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/hacktoberfest-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/hacktoberfest-2022/</guid>
      <description>With the month of October coming in a few days, be prepared for Hacktoberfest, a month-long celebration of open source software. The online event has been happening every October for the last 9 years and is sponsored by the American cloud hosting company DigitalOcean. How can you participate? Very simple: people are encouraged to create at least 4 pull requests for open source projects on GitHub.
If you are not sure how to get involved in open source projects and where to start, Hacktoberfest might be the perfect opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jonathan Danse: module developer and one of the first contributors</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-jonathan-danse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-jonathan-danse/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. This month, meet Jonathan Danse, aka PrestaEdit.
Jonathan is a module developer. He’s also one of the first contributors to the PrestaShop project. It all started, somewhat by chance, during a job interview 12 years ago. In this article, Jonathan talks about his experience with PrestaShop, his work as a module developer, and his dedication to the open source project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julius Zukauskas: Partner Agency Employee and Top Contributor</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-julius-zukauskas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-julius-zukauskas/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. This month, meet Julius Zukauskas, aka zuk3975.
Julius comes from Lithuania. He works at Invertus, an ecommerce agency with a Platinum partner status in the PrestaShop Agency Partner program. Half of his time is dedicated to the open source project, and more specifically to the Symfony migration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merchant, freelance developer, and top contributor: Daniel Hlaváček’s experience with the PrestaShop project</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-daniel-hlavacek/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-daniel-hlavacek/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. This month, meet Daniel Hlaváček, aka Hlavtox.
Daniel spends most of his time managing his family business’ online stores. The rest of the time, he works as a freelance developer for 10 clients, whose stores are all based on PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jean-François Viguier: a top contributor and a friend of PrestaShop</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-jean-francois-viguier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-jean-francois-viguier/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. This month, meet Jean-François Viguier, aka jf-viguier.
Co-founder of an ecommerce and coding agency in Toulouse (France), Jean-François is also the vice-president of Friends of Presta, an association that gathers a community of developers and integrators around the open-source ecommerce solution PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lorenz Meyer: a dedicated contributor supported by his employer</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-lorenz-meyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-lorenz-meyer/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub username? It’s time to find out! Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. This month, meet Lorenz Meyer, aka @lmeyer1.
Lorenz answered my questions from Romanel-sur-Lausanne, Switzerland. With 46 contributions, he ranks 119th in the top contributor list. In addition to participating in his personal enrichment, his contribution to the open source project is also encouraged and supported by his employer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From contributor to maintainer: Krystian Podemski&#39;s experience with the PrestaShop project</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-krystian-podemski/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/contributor-interview-krystian-podemski/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, a series of contributor interviews was published on the blog. It was a nice way of putting faces to names and getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project. And this year, we wanted to do it again. So here we go: this section is back on the blog!
For the first interview of the year 2022, let’s meet Krystian Podemski.
Krystian is 31.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest 2021</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/hacktoberfest-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/hacktoberfest-2021/</guid>
      <description>Hacktoberfest is a month-long celebration of open-source software that happens online every October, sponsored by the American cloud hosting company DigitalOcean. People are encouraged to engage and create at least 4 pull requests for open-source projects on GitHub.
If you want to contribute to open-source projects but don’t know where to start, Hacktoberfest might be the perfect opportunity for you.
How does that work? Your goal is to contribute with at least 4 quality pull requests to the open-source project you like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated UI tests tutorial</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/how-to-write-a-new-ui-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/how-to-write-a-new-ui-test/</guid>
      <description>One year ago, the QA team started to develop a new test framework, based on Puppeteer, Mocha, and Chai. You can read more about the framework in this previous article: The (new) PrestaShop Test Framework. Since then, the tests coverage has been continually increasing, and we recently improved our framework by switching to Playwright.
In this article, we will explain how to create a new UI (User Interface) test for the PrestaShop core project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributor interview: Pululu Kinanga André</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/contributor-interview-pululu-kinanga-andre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/contributor-interview-pululu-kinanga-andre/</guid>
      <description>An open source community is more than just pull requests made by faceless strangers. In order to better understand the people who contribute time and skills to the PrestaShop project, we&amp;rsquo;re writing a series of interviews with contributors of all ranges. This week, meet Pululu Kinanga André, one of our great developers on GitHub!
Hi Pululu! First, could you tell us a bit about yourself?
I am Pululu and I come from Angola.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
