<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>llandry on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/llandry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in llandry on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 06:09:47 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/llandry/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? - August 2016 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/do-you-speak-prestashop-august-2016-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/do-you-speak-prestashop-august-2016-edition/</guid>
      <description>Here is the latest report to inform you of what happened on the PrestaShop translation project on Crowdin in August.
Project news Thanks for pursuing the effort &amp;lt;3 This month was quite a good month for PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s project in Crowdin.The quantity of words translated and validated is huge compared to the same period last year. Thanks to all of you, old and new members, for this This month we would like to say a special thank to an amazing member of our community, Jesús Ruiz García, for the huge quantity of work done in translating the documentation since he joined the community and especially for his precious help and tips on terminology and glossary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Translator Guide Available Now!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/new-translator-guide-available-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/new-translator-guide-available-now/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to 2,870 Crowdin contributors, PrestaShop has been translated in over 65 languages, helping merchants to create shops in over 200 countries! Translating PrestaShop allows us to aim at millions of potential users and merchants from all around the world. We’re very proud of the work done and hope to bring e-commerce to a growing number of people, no matter what their country or language is. In order to keep reaching new people, we are today releasing our translator guide, so that anyone can start contributing to the translation project!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
