<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>patch on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/patch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in patch on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/patch/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 8.2.2 is here! This latest patch version brings a range of updates, addressing reported issues and introducing enhancements to improve the platform for merchants and developers alike.
We are happy to announce the release of PrestaShop 8.2.2, a patch version that not only resolves numerous bugs reported by our dedicated community and Quality Assurance team but also introduces some improvements.
As part of the Call for Contributions challenge, PrestaShop 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.2.1 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/prestashop-8-2-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch for PrestaShop 8.2 is available. This release contains many bug fixes and improvements, including a new way to handle module filtering in the front office.
We are excited to announce the release of PrestaShop 8.2.1, a new patch that not only addresses a significant number of bugs reported by our dedicated community and Quality Assurance team but also introduces a valuable new feature. This feature allows module developers to filter the display of other modules in PrestaShop, helping them avoid the use of overrides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.7 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-7-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-7-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A new patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is now available! This release includes several significant improvements and numerous bug fixes. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore these updates in detail.
PrestaShop 8.1.7 is now available. This release addresses several bugs and brings various improvements.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to backup before. Upgrade is possible using the latest version of the 1-Click Upgrade module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.6 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-6-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-6-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A new patch version for PrestaShop 8.1 is now available. This maintenance release fixes 2 security issues.
The security patch for version 8.1 of PrestaShop is now available. It is recommended that you upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to create a backup before. You can upgrade to the latest version using the 1-Click Upgrade module. There are no database changes in this release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.5 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-5-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-5-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>Another patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available. This release contains interesting improvements as well as a number of bug fixes. In this article, we’ll lean into them because there’s plenty to write about!
PrestaShop 8.1.5 is available. This release fixes some bugs but also brings a lot of improvements.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to backup before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.4 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-4-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-4-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been decided to release a security patch for version 8.1 of PrestaShop.
The security patch for version 8.1 of PrestaShop is now available. This is the first release where it&amp;rsquo;s been decided to separate the security fixes from other bug fixes and improvements, allowing for a quick release of the security patch.
It is recommended that you upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes. Of course, don’t forget to create a backup before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.3 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-3-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-8-1-3-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>We are entering the new year with the release of PrestaShop 8.1.3. The latest update for PrestaShop 8.1 is now available. This version brings two security updates, addresses close to 30 known issues, and introduces various enhancements.
To welcome the new year well, we are releasing a new version of PrestaShop! Version 8.1.3 is available with a slight delay, but this is due to the time it took to complete work on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.11 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-1-7-8-11-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2024/prestashop-1-7-8-11-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A security patch for PrestaShop 1.7 is now available.
As part of the extended support policy for PrestaShop 1.7, which involves taking care of critical and security fixes for the 1.7.8.x branch, we are releasing today a new patch for this version. This release fixes one high severity security issue found by security researchers.
For more details regarding security fixes, you can check the security advisories section below.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The second patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available! This release contains 2 security fixes, over 30 bugs have been fixed and some minor improvements have been integrated.
Version 8.1.2 fixes a few security issues found by security researchers and solves a great number of bugs reported by the community and project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance team. It also includes some minor improvements, especially for the new product page and new multi-format image generation system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.1 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available. This release contains a few security fixes, so we highly recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
Version 8.1.1 fixes a few security issues found by security researchers and solves a great number of bugs reported by the community and project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance team.
You can go to the release page to see a full changelog, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning a few notable bug fixes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.5 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-5-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-5-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The fifth patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download! This release contains a few security fixes, so we highly recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
PrestaShop 8.0.x branch is no longer supported since the release of PrestaShop 8.1, but due to the high severity of the security issues fixed in this release, we decided to release a patch version for this branch.
Apart from the security fixes, this release also contains a few bug fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.10 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-10-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-10-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>A security patch for PrestaShop 1.7 is now available.
As part of the extended support policy for PrestaShop 1.7, which involves taking care of critical and security fixes for the 1.7.8.x branch, we are releasing today a new patch for this version. This release fixes a few security issues found by security researchers.
For more details regarding security fixes, you can check the security advisories section below.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.4 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-4-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-4-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The fourth patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download! This release contains a few security fixes, so we recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
PrestaShop 8.0.4 is now available. This time there are three security fixes thanks to reports from community researchers. This release also contains a few bug fixes besides security fixes. The incorrect translation of pagination labels in products and combinations lists has been fixed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.9 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-9-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 16:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-1-7-8-9-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>Security patch for PrestaShop 1.7 is now available.
As part of the extended support policy for PrestaShop 1.7, which involves taking care of critical and security fixes for 1.7.8.x branch, we are releasing today a new patch for this version. This release fixes a few security issues reported by community researchers and upgrades some third-party libraries to their latest versions to ensure the stability and security of your shop.
It is recommended to upgrade your shop quickly in order to benefit from these fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.3 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-3-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-3-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The third patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download!
It was a rather bumpy road at the end because of issues we found during the release process, but here it is! In the newest patch version for PrestaShop 8 you can find a security improvement, and three fixes: one related to inaccurate wording in web services configuration, one which fixes the link to the user documentation in the installer, and one significant fix which improves how clearing the cache behaves in the software.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
