<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>module on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/module/</link>
    <description>Recent content in module on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/module/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to solve the search bar issue after upgrading to PrestaShop 1.7.8</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/misc/178-and-searchbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/misc/178-and-searchbar/</guid>
      <description>We have recently been informed that many of you have encountered a display problem with the search bar in Front office, right after upgrading to PrestaShop 1.7.8. This problem also affected shops using the built-in &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; theme.
What is the problem? After having updated your shop to 1.7.8, if you are using the default theme or a theme that overrides the default look of the search bar from the &amp;ldquo;ps_searchbar&amp;rdquo; module, you might have seen it displaying like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Of Module ProductComments 4.2.1</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/productcomments-4-2-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/productcomments-4-2-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>We have identified and fixed a new security issue on module Product Comments.
This issue is fixed in latest version 4.2.1.
Security fix One security fix has been included in this minor version:
Blind SQL injection during the CommentGrade process (security advisory) More information about why it is important to update:
SQL Injection (CWE-89) Other changes The version v4.2.1 of the module also brings some new improvements, you can read the full Changelog here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Of Module ProductComments 4.2.0</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/productcomments-4-2-0-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/productcomments-4-2-0-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The ongoing work on security for PrestaShop software continues. We have identified and fixed a new security issue on module Product Comments.
This issue is fixed in latest version 4.2.0.
Security fix One security fix has been included in this minor version:
Reflected XSS with parameters in PostComment (security advisory) More information about why it is important to update:
Cross-site Scripting (CWE-79) Other changes The version v4.2.0 of the module also brings some new improvements, you can read the full Changelog here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything you always wanted to know about PrestaTrust</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/everything-you-always-wanted-to-know-about-prestatrust/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/everything-you-always-wanted-to-know-about-prestatrust/</guid>
      <description>It allows to authenticate the code of modules and to safely keep track of the sales data in the blockchain.
In the upcoming 1.7.3 version, we will release a new option for PrestaShop modules called PrestaTrust. This is one of the most innovative projects, based on a technology which is still to discover for a lot of people, a kind of mystery that makes great promises for the future of our world: the blockchain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Module development changes in PrestaShop 1.7.0.0</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/module-development-changes-in-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/module-development-changes-in-17/</guid>
      <description>Existing modules should mostly work as-is with version 1.7. In this article, we dive into that “mostly”!
As you certainly know, all well-written 1.6 modules should work with little to no changes in version 1.7, except:
Those which target the theme/front office – because we rewrote the way themes are written. Those which target the Product page – because the DOM of this page has changed. Those which target the Modules page – again, because the DOM of this page has changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting the Advanced EU Compliance module</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/advanced-eu-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/advanced-eu-compliance/</guid>
      <description>As good news never come alone, let us introduce you to the new module that is included natively in PrestaShop from 1.6.1.0 version: Advanced EU Compliance.
Why did we create this module? E-commerce evolves at a very fast pace, and the more it evolves the more new legislations are appearing to frame it. These legislations can - over time - become a real headache for e-shop owners, who have to adapt their website themselves, or to hire someone to do it for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to override modules in PrestaShop</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/module/how-to-override-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 12:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/module/how-to-override-modules/</guid>
      <description>This article may be outdated Please note that this article refers to very old versions of PrestaShop. Check out the documentation to learn how to override modules. Since version 1.6.0.11 of PrestaShop, there is a new feature that allows developers to override a module&amp;rsquo;s instance classes (ie. its main module files, see the PR by @axometeam).
Since PrestaShop uses lots of modules for both core and custom features, module overrides are a welcome addition to an already great override system in PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
