<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>8.1 on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/8.1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 8.1 on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/8.1/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 is ready for translation</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-81-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-81-translations/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop’s 8.1 beta release was announced a few months ago. The stable release is now just around the corner. While it brings new features, a new version also means new strings. A file containing all 8.1 strings has been pushed to Crowdin, and is ready for translation!
8.1 strings are available for translation Translators, proofreaders… your project needs you! Feel free to take a look at those new strings and help your language reach 100% translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 beta is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The beta version of PrestaShop 8.1 is now ready for you to test!
We’re delighted to announce that PrestaShop 8.1 has reached the beta stage. PrestaShop 8.1 is still in development, but we hope you will help us test this release so we can have the best quality release possible, available for everyone, as soon as possible!
Test PrestaShop 8.1.0 beta 1 now! Version 8.1 fixes over 30 bugs found in the previous release and introduces many improvements and new features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 is now in feature freeze</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-feature-freeze/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-feature-freeze/</guid>
      <description>As of February 1, 2023, PrestaShop version 8.1 has entered the feature freeze phase. This article provides more information about the feature freeze, what the next steps will be, and what to expect from PrestaShop 8.1.
Feature freeze for PrestaShop 8.1 As of today, PrestaShop version 8.1 has entered a feature freeze. What is a feature freeze? Feature freeze refers to a specific stage in the software development process after which no new features can be added to a version.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
