<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>8.1 on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/8.1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 8.1 on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/8.1/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The second patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available! This release contains 2 security fixes, over 30 bugs have been fixed and some minor improvements have been integrated.
Version 8.1.2 fixes a few security issues found by security researchers and solves a great number of bugs reported by the community and project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance team. It also includes some minor improvements, especially for the new product page and new multi-format image generation system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1.1 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch for PrestaShop 8.1 is available. This release contains a few security fixes, so we highly recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
Version 8.1.1 fixes a few security issues found by security researchers and solves a great number of bugs reported by the community and project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance team.
You can go to the release page to see a full changelog, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning a few notable bug fixes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-0-available/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to announce that PrestaShop 8.1 is officially available.
PrestaShop 8.1 is a minor upgrade with major improvements. It&amp;rsquo;s focused on making things faster and easier for you, transforming the way you use PrestaShop.
The entirely reworked product management page delivers a more efficient and user-friendly experience. This new page makes managing product combinations, prices, taxes, stock, and images quicker and easier. Multistore product management has also been drastically improved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 Release Candidate Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-rc1-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-rc1-release/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce the first release candidate of PrestaShop 8.1.
We&amp;rsquo;re on the brink of releasing the final 8.1 version. This time, the release candidate version is being shared simultaneously with the community and the project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance (QA) team. The idea is for everyone to collectively confirm that all issues identified in the beta version have been resolved, ensuring their suitability for production use. If no major problems are reported by June 26th, we&amp;rsquo;ll move ahead and launch the final version of 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 is ready for translation</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-81-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-81-translations/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop’s 8.1 beta release was announced a few months ago. The stable release is now just around the corner. While it brings new features, a new version also means new strings. A file containing all 8.1 strings has been pushed to Crowdin, and is ready for translation!
8.1 strings are available for translation Translators, proofreaders… your project needs you! Feel free to take a look at those new strings and help your language reach 100% translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 beta is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The beta version of PrestaShop 8.1 is now ready for you to test!
We’re delighted to announce that PrestaShop 8.1 has reached the beta stage. PrestaShop 8.1 is still in development, but we hope you will help us test this release so we can have the best quality release possible, available for everyone, as soon as possible!
Test PrestaShop 8.1.0 beta 1 now! Version 8.1 fixes over 30 bugs found in the previous release and introduces many improvements and new features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 is now in feature freeze</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-feature-freeze/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-feature-freeze/</guid>
      <description>As of February 1, 2023, PrestaShop version 8.1 has entered the feature freeze phase. This article provides more information about the feature freeze, what the next steps will be, and what to expect from PrestaShop 8.1.
Feature freeze for PrestaShop 8.1 As of today, PrestaShop version 8.1 has entered a feature freeze. What is a feature freeze? Feature freeze refers to a specific stage in the software development process after which no new features can be added to a version.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
