<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>8.0.x on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/8.0.x/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 8.0.x on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/8.0.x/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.1 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download!
After a few weeks of intensive work from all project members, the first maintenance release for version 8 is now available.
In this patch, you can find more than 30 bug fixes and one performance improvement that prevents clearing the system&amp;rsquo;s cache for bulk actions performed from the modules list. You will also get changes from the recent PrestaShop patch release 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8 is now a LTS</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/178-lts-80/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/178-lts-80/</guid>
      <description>Now that PrestaShop 8.0 is out, here is a focus on maintained branches of the PrestaShop project and what to expect.
Reminder: PrestaShop branching strategy In August 2015 PrestaShop adopted a new branching model for the project.
The model was refined over the years, for example with this page on the developer documentation about what bugs do qualify for a patch version or the Backward Compatibility Promise that defines what changes can be introduced in a version, but we can say the model has lived quite well as the project is still following it in 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-0-available/</guid>
      <description>The maintainers team is pleased to announce that PrestaShop 8.0 is officially available.
PrestaShop 8, the first major version since the original release of PrestaShop 1.7.0 back in 2016, is an important milestone for the project.
A significant cleanup has been performed in the codebase, with several internal components updated, modified or removed. PrestaShop 8 is also the project’s first company-neutral release, meaning that it no longer includes commercial products and services built-in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
