<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>8.0.x on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/8.0.x/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 8.0.x on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 09:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/8.0.x/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.5 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-5-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-5-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The fifth patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download! This release contains a few security fixes, so we highly recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
PrestaShop 8.0.x branch is no longer supported since the release of PrestaShop 8.1, but due to the high severity of the security issues fixed in this release, we decided to release a patch version for this branch.
Apart from the security fixes, this release also contains a few bug fixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.4 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-4-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-4-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The fourth patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download! This release contains a few security fixes, so we recommend you to upgrade your shop as soon as possible.
PrestaShop 8.0.4 is now available. This time there are three security fixes thanks to reports from community researchers. This release also contains a few bug fixes besides security fixes. The incorrect translation of pagination labels in products and combinations lists has been fixed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.3 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-3-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-3-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The third patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download!
It was a rather bumpy road at the end because of issues we found during the release process, but here it is! In the newest patch version for PrestaShop 8 you can find a security improvement, and three fixes: one related to inaccurate wording in web services configuration, one which fixes the link to the user documentation in the installer, and one significant fix which improves how clearing the cache behaves in the software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.2 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-2-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-2-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The second patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download!
Version 8.0.2 is available! In this patch, you can find over 20 bug fixes. As a patch version, 8.0.2 brings further goodness and stability to the 8.0 branch.
There were several noteworthy issues addressed in PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s 8.0.2 milestone. The upgrade mechanism had a problem where it couldn&amp;rsquo;t check if the PHP session had started on some webservers, which was reported by many community members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0.1 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-1-maintenance-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-0-1-maintenance-release/</guid>
      <description>The first patch version for PrestaShop 8 is now available to download!
After a few weeks of intensive work from all project members, the first maintenance release for version 8 is now available.
In this patch, you can find more than 30 bug fixes and one performance improvement that prevents clearing the system&amp;rsquo;s cache for bulk actions performed from the modules list. You will also get changes from the recent PrestaShop patch release 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8 is now in the extended support phase</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/178-in-extended-support-phase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/178-in-extended-support-phase/</guid>
      <description>Now that PrestaShop 8.0 is out, here is a focus on maintained branches of the PrestaShop project and what to expect.
Reminder: PrestaShop branching strategy In August 2015 PrestaShop adopted a new branching model for the project.
The model was refined over the years, for example with this page on the developer documentation about what bugs do qualify for a patch version or the Backward Compatibility Promise that defines what changes can be introduced in a version, but we can say the model has lived quite well as the project is still following it in 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-0-available/</guid>
      <description>The maintainers team is pleased to announce that PrestaShop 8.0 is officially available.
PrestaShop 8, the first major version since the original release of PrestaShop 1.7.0 back in 2016, is an important milestone for the project.
A significant cleanup has been performed in the codebase, with several internal components updated, modified or removed. PrestaShop 8 is also the project’s first company-neutral release, meaning that it no longer includes commercial products and services built-in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
