<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>minor on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/minor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in minor on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/minor/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-0-available/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to announce that PrestaShop 8.1 is officially available.
PrestaShop 8.1 is a minor upgrade with major improvements. It&amp;rsquo;s focused on making things faster and easier for you, transforming the way you use PrestaShop.
The entirely reworked product management page delivers a more efficient and user-friendly experience. This new page makes managing product combinations, prices, taxes, stock, and images quicker and easier. Multistore product management has also been drastically improved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 Release Candidate Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-rc1-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-rc1-release/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce the first release candidate of PrestaShop 8.1.
We&amp;rsquo;re on the brink of releasing the final 8.1 version. This time, the release candidate version is being shared simultaneously with the community and the project&amp;rsquo;s Quality Assurance (QA) team. The idea is for everyone to collectively confirm that all issues identified in the beta version have been resolved, ensuring their suitability for production use. If no major problems are reported by June 26th, we&amp;rsquo;ll move ahead and launch the final version of 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.1 beta is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/prestashop-8-1-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The beta version of PrestaShop 8.1 is now ready for you to test!
We’re delighted to announce that PrestaShop 8.1 has reached the beta stage. PrestaShop 8.1 is still in development, but we hope you will help us test this release so we can have the best quality release possible, available for everyone, as soon as possible!
Test PrestaShop 8.1.0 beta 1 now! Version 8.1 fixes over 30 bugs found in the previous release and introduces many improvements and new features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.0 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-1-7-8-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-1-7-8-0-available/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce PrestaShop 1.7.8.0 is officially available!
Each version of PrestaShop is getting bigger and bigger, with more and more regular contributors. We are very proud of having such a strong community working with us on a daily basis.
This new version brings many features that should please both merchants and developers.
New in 1.7.8.0 Support for PHP 7.4 PrestaShop 1.7.8 introduces compatibility with PHP 7.4, which allows you to benefit from bug fixes and security patches from PHP until December 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.0 RC1 Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-1-7-8-0-rc-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-1-7-8-0-rc-release/</guid>
      <description>A few months after the beta, the first release candidate for PrestaShop 1.7.8.0 is now ready for you to test!
This is the last step before releasing the final 1.7.8.0. This version aims to verify that all regressions found during the beta have been fixed and that the software is ready for production. If no major or critical regression is reported by October 5, then the final version of 1.7.8.0 will be made available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a more mobile-friendly back office</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/responsive-back-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 16:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/responsive-back-office/</guid>
      <description>Until now, PrestaShop always relied on a desktop-first responsive design strategy. Indeed, there are few use cases on mobile. But you can&amp;rsquo;t prevent users from checking their store&amp;rsquo;s back office on their mobile!
Why work on responsive design? They were some issues that affected the user experience on mobile:
Difficulties in accessing important store information Hidden content because of overlapping components Text readability issues Bugs and lack of consistency on display (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multistore feature in PrestaShop 1.7.8: What&#39;s new?</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/multistore-news-in-1.7.8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/multistore-news-in-1.7.8/</guid>
      <description>With the release of the new version 1.7.8 which is in progress, this article details one of the main features revamps of this version: the multistore.
The multistore feature allows merchants to manage several front offices through a single back office. It’s frequently used by merchants who sell in different countries and therefore have different languages and/or currencies. It is also used by merchants who do both B2B and B2C. And it is more rarely used by merchants who have several brands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.8.0 beta is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-1-7-8-0-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/prestashop-1-7-8-0-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The first Beta version of PrestaShop 1.7.8.0 is now ready for you to test!
We are very happy to announce today the release of the beta version of 1.7.8. This version includes many features and bug fixes, we count on you to test the Beta and report any bugs you encounter.
Main new features are: the redesign of the translation system that facilitates the export and the translation of your modules and themes, a new header for multistore allowing to configure the different stores more easily and quickly, and many other improvements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 is available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-7-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-7-0-available/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 is officially available!
This release is our biggest yet. More than 1300 merged Pull Requests in 600 days, almost 120 contributors, two betas, one release candidate. Was it worth it? We absolutely think so and hope that you will enjoy using it. By the way, we know this release was expected in early 2020, there will be a build article explaining what happened this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 RC1 Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-7-0-rc-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-7-0-rc-release/</guid>
      <description>We are really happy to announce that we are very close to finishing the 1.7.7.0 release, the release candidate is the last step before the final version is out.
This release candidate aims at making sure that all major regressions found during the beta have been fixed, and that no new ones have been spotted. If no new critical or major regression is reported by November 17th, we will make the final version of 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 Beta 2 Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-7-0-beta2-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-7-0-beta2-release/</guid>
      <description>The second Beta version for PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 is now ready for you to test!
Over 130 Pull Requests have been merged since the first Beta of 1.7.7.0 was released about three months ago. A great number of regressions have been detected and fixed thanks to extensive testing by the community and the PrestaShop team, mainly in the new order pages. However, as new regressions keep being reported, the maintainer team has decided to issue a second Beta release before a Release Candidate is built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 Beta Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-7-0-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/prestashop-1-7-7-0-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The first Beta version for PrestaShop 1.7.7.0 is now ready for you to test!
After more than one year in the making, we are really thrilled to announce that we are releasing the 1.7.7.0 beta. This version is even bigger than the previous one with 957 merged pull requests, compared to 748 for 1.7.6.0 (our previous record) – and we are still at least a month away from the final version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new order pages in PrestaShop 1.7.7</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/the-new-order-pages-in-prestaShop-1-7-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/the-new-order-pages-in-prestaShop-1-7-7/</guid>
      <description>With the release of the new version 1.7.7, this article has the ambition to detail one of the major features of the version. Our work was focused on one of the most used pages by our merchants: the orders&amp;rsquo; management page.
We are thrilled to introduce to you the new features around the order process. But before jumping into the features awaiting the merchants in the new version, we would like to share our thinking process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.6.0 is available!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-6-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-6-0-available/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce PrestaShop 1.7.6.0 is officially available!
It has been quite a journey to deliver this huge release, our biggest yet since 1.7.1.0. Six months of development, a six week-long Beta, two Release Candidates&amp;hellip; Was it worth it? We absolutely think so, and hope that you will enjoy using it.
In this version we focused on improving and bringing back important 1.6 features to merchants, and kept working on code quality and performance improvements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release note 1.7.6 RC2</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-6-0-rc2-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/prestashop-1-7-6-0-rc2-release/</guid>
      <description>Once again the PrestaShop community actively participated in the testing of the PrestaShop 1.7.6 Release Candidate. Thanks to your involvement, 3 regressions were identified and fixed.
Our team is glad to announce PrestaShop 1.7.6.0 Release Candidate 2. If no new regression is reported in the next days, we will make the final version of 1.7.6.0 available by the end of next week (28).
Fixed in this Release Candidate 2 Front Office:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
