<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>product on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/product/</link>
    <description>Recent content in product on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 16:25:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/product/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Towards a more mobile-friendly back office</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/responsive-back-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 16:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/responsive-back-office/</guid>
      <description>Until now, PrestaShop always relied on a desktop-first responsive design strategy. Indeed, there are few use cases on mobile. But you can&amp;rsquo;t prevent users from checking their store&amp;rsquo;s back office on their mobile!
Why work on responsive design? They were some issues that affected the user experience on mobile:
Difficulties in accessing important store information Hidden content because of overlapping components Text readability issues Bugs and lack of consistency on display (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multistore feature in PrestaShop 1.7.8: What&#39;s new?</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/multistore-news-in-1.7.8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/multistore-news-in-1.7.8/</guid>
      <description>With the release of the new version 1.7.8 which is in progress, this article details one of the main features revamps of this version: the multistore.
The multistore feature allows merchants to manage several front offices through a single back office. It’s frequently used by merchants who sell in different countries and therefore have different languages and/or currencies. It is also used by merchants who do both B2B and B2C. And it is more rarely used by merchants who have several brands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new place to contribute to the PrestaShop project and share your feedback on the next features</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/productboard-portal-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/productboard-portal-launch/</guid>
      <description>As announced here, the Core product team recently adopted a new working tool to gather feedback and prioritize features: Productboard. No more teasing, it is now time to have a look at how it will look and how we will all be able to handle it!
Productboard makes two things possible for the team:
On the one hand, having a dedicated internal interface to centralize all feedback, group them into topics, define features, and prioritize them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product development at PrestaShop</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/product-features-methodology-at-prestashop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/product-features-methodology-at-prestashop/</guid>
      <description>In March 2020, the Core product team at PrestaShop, in charge of building and prioritizing new features, decided to work with a new tool: Productboard.
The team thought it was the right occasion to talk more about the product development at PrestaShop, the steps, the roles and responsibilities and what happens behind the scenes before a new feature is added to PrestaShop.
PrestaShop’s product development cycle Core product team In the PrestaShop company, a cross-functional team is dedicated to maintaining the PrestaShop open source project: the Core team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new order pages in PrestaShop 1.7.7</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/the-new-order-pages-in-prestaShop-1-7-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/the-new-order-pages-in-prestaShop-1-7-7/</guid>
      <description>With the release of the new version 1.7.7, this article has the ambition to detail one of the major features of the version. Our work was focused on one of the most used pages by our merchants: the orders&amp;rsquo; management page.
We are thrilled to introduce to you the new features around the order process. But before jumping into the features awaiting the merchants in the new version, we would like to share our thinking process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User tests are not enough</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/user-tests-are-not-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/user-tests-are-not-enough/</guid>
      <description>As a designer, product manager or entrepreneur you’ve probably been told countless times that user feedback is gold (and that’s true!). There’s no shortage of books and articles that describe the benefits of testing your product with your users. While these documents provide good advice on how the test is done, they often lack explanations on how to make sense of this feedback and how this process fits inside a team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we reorganized the main menu in PrestaShop 1.7</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/how-we-reorganized-main-menu-prestashop-1.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 04:29:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/how-we-reorganized-main-menu-prestashop-1.7/</guid>
      <description>Did you think everything had been said about PrestaShop 1.7 version? In our quest towards a simpler interface, the main menu was reorganized, mostly to make it easier for you to navigate in PrestaShop. So here are a few things you should be aware of.
In short:
New sections were created A new wording has been introduced The location of some pages was changed Other pages were gathered as tabs of a main page The method behind the new menu Here’s our recipe to come up with this updated menu:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Product Page - Evolution Revolution</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/product-page-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 14:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/product-page-evolution/</guid>
      <description>A long time ago, in a galaxy not so far away, we packed PrestaShop with much needed functionalities in its core. The aim was to propose the best ecommerce solution, with the biggest functional scope, answering to almost all of the merchants’ needs — all that while still being free.
And we can say it&amp;rsquo;s been a success! Features are one of the reasons why merchants choose PrestaShop when they want to create their online shop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
