<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>github on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in github on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/github/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest 2023</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/hacktoberfest-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/hacktoberfest-2023/</guid>
      <description>The month of October is coming quickly! So be prepared for Hacktoberfest, a month-long celebration of open source software.
Hacktoberfest 2023 The online event has been happening every October since 2013 and is sponsored by DigitalOcean. This year marks the 10th anniversary of the event, with changes to help ensure its sustainability for the next decade. You’ll learn about these right below. How can you participate? Very simple: people are encouraged to create at least 4 pull requests for open source projects on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest and PrestaShop: how you can participate in this 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/hacktoberfest-2022-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/hacktoberfest-2022-started/</guid>
      <description>October is now here and Hacktoberfest, a month-long celebration of open source software, has started. We have recently written an article about the event, how you can get involved and all the different rules. You can know more in our Hacktoberfest 2022 article.
In a few words, participation is very simple: people are encouraged to create at least 4 pull requests for open source projects on GitHub.
How to get started If you are wondering how to get started, we are listing in this blog post issues that could be a good starting point for new contributors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest 2022</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/hacktoberfest-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/hacktoberfest-2022/</guid>
      <description>With the month of October coming in a few days, be prepared for Hacktoberfest, a month-long celebration of open source software. The online event has been happening every October for the last 9 years and is sponsored by the American cloud hosting company DigitalOcean. How can you participate? Very simple: people are encouraged to create at least 4 pull requests for open source projects on GitHub.
If you are not sure how to get involved in open source projects and where to start, Hacktoberfest might be the perfect opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest 2021</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/hacktoberfest-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/hacktoberfest-2021/</guid>
      <description>Hacktoberfest is a month-long celebration of open-source software that happens online every October, sponsored by the American cloud hosting company DigitalOcean. People are encouraged to engage and create at least 4 pull requests for open-source projects on GitHub.
If you want to contribute to open-source projects but don’t know where to start, Hacktoberfest might be the perfect opportunity for you.
How does that work? Your goal is to contribute with at least 4 quality pull requests to the open-source project you like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest 2020 is coming</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/hacktoberfest-2020-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/hacktoberfest-2020-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>Open source has its own tradition when fall starts cooling the atmosphere around, Hacktoberfest! Beer is not flowing like water but code is, and it creates more value than any bunch of slightly tipsy people. ;-)
Curated by the American cloud hosting company DigitalOcean, with Intel and DEV, Hacktoberfest happens online every year in October to celebrate open source. It’s pretty simple: for one month, people are encouraged to engage and create at least 4 pull requests for open source projects on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help us write product specifications</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/write-product-specifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/write-product-specifications/</guid>
      <description>Contribution is not only about code. As an open source project, everyone is encouraged to participate in the construction of PrestaShop: you can translate the software in your native language, suggest a new feature, sign up to the User Club and share your experience with the product teams, become an ambassador&amp;hellip; and also write specifications!
Hosted on a dedicated GitHub repository, product specifications are meant to formally describe how features should work on a given page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How bug reports are handled</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/how-bug-reports-are-handled/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 10:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/how-bug-reports-are-handled/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop is a successful Open Source project – with more than 300 000 shops worldwide, merchants trust us to help them build their ecommerce shop.
However this success has a cost: every day our users discover new bugs and inconsistencies in the project, and they come to GitHub to report them. On average, 10 new issues are created every day on GitHub (counting bug reports and feedback about features), and 2 out of 3 issues are either invalid or duplicates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A definition of the &#39;good first issue&#39; label</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/a-definition-of-the-good-first-issue-label/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 16:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/a-definition-of-the-good-first-issue-label/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, the PrestaShop product team decided to use new leverage to help new contributors participate in the PrestaShop project on GitHub: the &amp;lsquo;good first issue&amp;rsquo; label.
But what is it exactly? And how does it work? Below are some questions raised to give it a proper definition and specify its use:
🤔 What does this label mean? People participating in the PrestaShop project do not have the same purpose, they also do not share the same skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s review pull requests!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/review-your-pull-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 12:00:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/review-your-pull-requests/</guid>
      <description>Have you submitted code to PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s Core codebase or any of its native module through a pull request on GitHub? Then read on!
The PrestaShop team has four main ways to get feedback from the Community:
The Support Forums, where we try to answer the most pressing matters (and there&amp;rsquo;s never enough hours in the day). The Forge, our bugtracker, where users (both developers and merchants) report issues or suggest improvements, and the team handles them one by one, according to their complexity and impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up your Git for contributing</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/misc/set-up-your-git-for-contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 11:21:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/misc/set-up-your-git-for-contributing/</guid>
      <description>Any open source project comes with its own set of rules to harmonize everybody&amp;rsquo;s contributions. Usually the guidelines are described in a CONTRIBUTING.md file inside the project root directory.
To follow these guidelines, you often need to adapt your development environment. You will find here all you need to know to set up your development environment! This will help your contribution get validated more quickly and without further modifications.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about working with the PrestaShop project, but what you&amp;rsquo;ll read here applies to most PHP open source projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
