<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Translations on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Translations on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 06:09:47 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to translate your theme in PrestaShop 1.7</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/how-to-translate-your-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/how-to-translate-your-theme/</guid>
      <description>This article is outdated PrestaShop&amp;rsquo;s translation system has evolved since this article was originally published in 2017. Make sure to read the latest documentation on how to use translations in PrestaShop for modules, and for themes. By now you’re probably aware that the 1.7 version comes with a new translation system and that the theme you are building can benefit from it. However, we didn’t give much details on how it works yet, so here is what you should know if you want to translate your theme for PrestaShop 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to contribute to the User Guide and help translate it</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/how-to-contribute-and-translate-the-user-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 06:09:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/how-to-contribute-and-translate-the-user-documentation/</guid>
      <description>Some of you contacted us to help translate the PrestaShop User Guide into their language. To make things easier for anyone who wants to help write some user documentation, here is a quick guide on how to use Confluence, on which our user documentation is hosted.
Anatomy of a documentation page These elements are important and/or recurring in the PrestaShop documentation and here&amp;rsquo;s what you should know about it.
Page title It will define the page URL (most of the time), and is repeated each time at the beginning of the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Translator Guide Available Now!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/new-translator-guide-available-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 06:09:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/new-translator-guide-available-now/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to 2,870 Crowdin contributors, PrestaShop has been translated in over 65 languages, helping merchants to create shops in over 200 countries! Translating PrestaShop allows us to aim at millions of potential users and merchants from all around the world. We’re very proud of the work done and hope to bring e-commerce to a growing number of people, no matter what their country or language is. In order to keep reaching new people, we are today releasing our translator guide, so that anyone can start contributing to the translation project!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos: How to help translating PrestaShop into Spanish (ES)</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/how-to-help-translating-PrestaShop-into-Spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 10:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/how-to-help-translating-PrestaShop-into-Spanish/</guid>
      <description>This article, in Spanish, has been written by Jesús Ruiz Garcia, an active contributor to the Spanish documentation and software translation. Jesús has started a project to improve and harmonize the Spanish translation of PrestaShop. If you want to join him and contribute to the Spanish translation, watch these short videos to know how it works!
¿Cómo ayudar a traducir el software de PrestaShop en español? El equipo de PrestaShop está trabajando continuamente en mejoras del software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 rules to follow when translating PrestaShop</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/how-to-help-with-prestashop-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 17:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/translation/how-to-help-with-prestashop-translations/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s not always easy to begin translating PrestaShop when the project has already been started by other contributors. To help you get on board, and to guide you with your first translations, here are 10 quick rules to follow if you want to make sure your contributions will be validated!
Make sure you know the context. Is it for the merchant? the customer? on which page is it? When will it show?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
