<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ux on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/ux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ux on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 16:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/ux/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Content style guide: a reference for better harmonization</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/content-style-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/content-style-guide/</guid>
      <description>It all started with an observation: contributors brought many new wordings to the PrestaShop open source project but couldn&amp;rsquo;t access clear content guidelines. This led to a lot of inconsistencies. Wording is such an essential element of a good user experience, it was time for a change.
A reference document for writing content When designing a new feature, contributors to the PrestaShop project have to think about the wording: feature labels, help texts, error messages, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a more mobile-friendly back office</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/responsive-back-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 16:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/responsive-back-office/</guid>
      <description>Until now, PrestaShop always relied on a desktop-first responsive design strategy. Indeed, there are few use cases on mobile. But you can&amp;rsquo;t prevent users from checking their store&amp;rsquo;s back office on their mobile!
Why work on responsive design? They were some issues that affected the user experience on mobile:
Difficulties in accessing important store information Hidden content because of overlapping components Text readability issues Bugs and lack of consistency on display (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multistore feature in PrestaShop 1.7.8: What&#39;s new?</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/multistore-news-in-1.7.8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/multistore-news-in-1.7.8/</guid>
      <description>With the release of the new version 1.7.8 which is in progress, this article details one of the main features revamps of this version: the multistore.
The multistore feature allows merchants to manage several front offices through a single back office. It’s frequently used by merchants who sell in different countries and therefore have different languages and/or currencies. It is also used by merchants who do both B2B and B2C. And it is more rarely used by merchants who have several brands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A journey to improve the Time To Interactive metric in Classic Theme</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/journey-to-improve-the-time-to-interactive-metric/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/journey-to-improve-the-time-to-interactive-metric/</guid>
      <description>The project Core Web Vitals from Google has announced that loading time and performance will have an impact on the website ranking in search results. Google mentions lazy loading in their suggestions. Lazy loading will be available on Classic Theme in version 1.7.8 thanks to Progi1984 and it will definitely improve both user experience and loading time on your site!
What is lazy loading ? Lazy loading is a technique that defers loading of non-critical resources at page load time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new order pages in PrestaShop 1.7.7</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/the-new-order-pages-in-prestaShop-1-7-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2020/the-new-order-pages-in-prestaShop-1-7-7/</guid>
      <description>With the release of the new version 1.7.7, this article has the ambition to detail one of the major features of the version. Our work was focused on one of the most used pages by our merchants: the orders&amp;rsquo; management page.
We are thrilled to introduce to you the new features around the order process. But before jumping into the features awaiting the merchants in the new version, we would like to share our thinking process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we reorganized the main menu in PrestaShop 1.7</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/how-we-reorganized-main-menu-prestashop-1.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 04:29:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/how-we-reorganized-main-menu-prestashop-1.7/</guid>
      <description>Did you think everything had been said about PrestaShop 1.7 version? In our quest towards a simpler interface, the main menu was reorganized, mostly to make it easier for you to navigate in PrestaShop. So here are a few things you should be aware of.
In short:
New sections were created A new wording has been introduced The location of some pages was changed Other pages were gathered as tabs of a main page The method behind the new menu Here’s our recipe to come up with this updated menu:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling for user-testing volunteers (Paris, France)</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/call-for-user-testing-volunteers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 17:37:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/call-for-user-testing-volunteers/</guid>
      <description>A lot of work has been done on the new back office for PrestaShop 1.7, most notably the reworked Product page and Modules page; as well as the brand new theme. Now, we need you to tell us what you think &amp;ndash; face to face! As a reminder, the PrestaShop 1.7 Project FAQ is available.
A big part of the PrestaShop 1.7 project was making sure that this new version had a design that would help merchants do their daily tasks faster and with less confusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Product Page - Evolution Revolution</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/product-page-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 14:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/product-page-evolution/</guid>
      <description>A long time ago, in a galaxy not so far away, we packed PrestaShop with much needed functionalities in its core. The aim was to propose the best ecommerce solution, with the biggest functional scope, answering to almost all of the merchants’ needs — all that while still being free.
And we can say it&amp;rsquo;s been a success! Features are one of the reasons why merchants choose PrestaShop when they want to create their online shop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop episode 1.7: the module page awakens</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/module-page-awakens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 15:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/module-page-awakens/</guid>
      <description>We’ve been working on this project for a while now, and it is about time we tell you about the new module page we are planning for PrestaShop 1.7.0! Since September, our team (Thibaud, Thomas, Melvin, Guilhem, Léa and myself) has been busy redesigning the outdated module page of version 1.6. Needless to say, it is an important subject for PrestaShop’s business, but most importantly a key step in merchants’ journey to a successful online store.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
