<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>qa on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/qa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in qa on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/qa/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adapting to PrestaShop 9: Guzzle is gone, what&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/breaking-change-guzzle-removal-v9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/breaking-change-guzzle-removal-v9/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 9 is a major release, meaning it introduces breaking changes, including the removal of certain dependencies. One of the most impactful changes for module developers is the removal of Guzzle, a popular HTTP client that many modules relied on.
If your module depends on Guzzle, it will no longer be available by default in PrestaShop 9. In this article, we’ll explain why Guzzle was removed, what this means for your module, and how to migrate to a suitable alternative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reworking the &#34;Update Assistant&#34; Module V7: Our Experience</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/reworking-the-update-assistant-module-v7-our-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2025/reworking-the-update-assistant-module-v7-our-experience/</guid>
      <description>Let’s face it—our Update Assistant module was messy. The front-end was confusing, the user experience was challenging, and even minor adjustments were a little more complex than what we would have liked.
As part of the Seamless Upgrade &amp;amp; Extensibility squad, one of our key missions is to improve the reliability of PrestaShop upgrades. And to do that, we knew the Update Assistant module needed more than just a few patches—it needed a complete reinvention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a new bug severity classification</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/severity-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 11:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/severity-classification/</guid>
      <description>According to the Information Technology Infrastructure Library (ITIL), a bug is an &amp;ldquo;event that is not part of the standard operation of a service and causes an unplanned interruption or decrease the quality of service&amp;rdquo;. And it is everybody’s job to chase them all!
At the PrestaShop Quality Assurance team (aka QA), we browse issues on GitHub all day long. As we go about doing that, we often come across messages from people who are annoyed about a bug taking a long time to be fixed, and saying &amp;ldquo;this is a major issue, why is it still not fixed?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
