<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>team on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/team/</link>
    <description>Recent content in team on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 12:30:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/team/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to make your module compliant with PrestaShop’s Official GDPR Compliance Module</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/module/how-to-make-your-module-compliant-with-prestashop-official-gdpr-compliance-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 12:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/howtos/module/how-to-make-your-module-compliant-with-prestashop-official-gdpr-compliance-module/</guid>
      <description>Everybody must already know, there are a few steps to follow in order to make your module compliant with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)
Add a consent confirmation checkbox if the module collects personal data Allow users to ask for total removal of their personal data Allow users to ask for a comprehensive export of their personal data owned by the site The Official GDPR Compliance Module by PrestaShop will be available soon, and it provides you with 4 new hooks to help you meet these requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop is hiring</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-is-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-is-hiring/</guid>
      <description>You are a developer, you love PrestaShop and are passionate about open source? Maybe you are even already a contributor to our project? Then what are you waiting for, let’s work together!
We are looking for people focused on producing quality code, meaning it should be readable, maintainable, tested and documented.
As Prestashop is an open source project, you will be responsible for:
Reviewing your colleagues or contributors code; Giving advice and providing constructive criticism; Participating in many discussions, whether on GitHub, Slack or Gitter; Fixing bugs without introducing new ones; In order to maintain its technical leadership, PrestaShop makes sure its developers devote time to training and sharing their knowledge with their colleagues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop loves its community</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-loves-its-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2018/prestashop-loves-its-community/</guid>
      <description>And here comes the nice surprise&amp;hellip; 2018 is here, following the gregorian calendar, let us wish you a successful and happy new year again!
So thank you all for this huge year we spent together, on Crowdin or on GitHub, making PrestaShop so proud of its community. We have prepared this nice infographic to have a look at 2017, to see how PrestaShop moved forward and feel fine about it. You deserve to do so, enjoy it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncle Build makes an assessment</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/uncle-build-makes-an-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/uncle-build-makes-an-assessment/</guid>
      <description>Dear readers, followers, developers, translators, PrestaShopers from all sides, we call for your opinion about the devblog, you answered, thank you so much!
We must admit that we were quite eager for the results, as we know Build needs to evolved and be improved. Since we are convinced this change must come with you, as you are all the first involved in it, it seems important to us to ask for your opinion about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncle Build wants you!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/uncle-build-wants-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/uncle-build-wants-you/</guid>
      <description>Dear readers, followers, developers, translators, PrestaShopers from all sides, it is time to lean over what will be next for Build!
Chatting about Build’s future Launched in March 2015, we are now sprinting towards a third year of activity. As we write for you, through our communication on upcoming code updates, ongoing projects and developments, we would like to hear from you to keep the devblog alive altogether.
That&amp;rsquo;s why we have prepared a survey in order to have a more accurate idea of what we could turn Build into.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PrestaCrew is always hiring!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-always-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/prestashop-always-hiring/</guid>
      <description>Looking to have an impact on +270.000 users all at once? Look no further! PrestaShop is always willing to hire new talents, and this special post will point to some specific roles we are looking to add to our current roster.
Always hiring?! First and foremost: we are always looking to add members to the team, most particularly PHP developers &amp;ndash; but not limited to that!
So if you find yourself wandering around aimlessly in Paris, come visit us!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to best contact us</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/how-to-best-contact-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 09:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2017/how-to-best-contact-us/</guid>
      <description>There are many ways to connect with the PrestaShop team. From support requests to development contributions, we’re here to work with you!
Since we’re an open source company, there are a number of places where we collaborate with the PrestaShop community. For new and old community members alike, it’s helpful to have this information in one place.
Without further ado, this is how we can work together!
The quick links Getting support Contacting our teams Reporting issues to the Core team Talking to the Addons team about bought modules/themes Helping the i18n improve the translation Contributing to the User documentation Contributing to the 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The PrestaCrew is hiring more sailors</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/prestacrew-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 12:00:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/prestacrew-hiring/</guid>
      <description>The team at PrestaShop is busy preparing what&amp;rsquo;s ahead for our e-commerce boat and community. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot coming and we&amp;rsquo;re looking for some extra hands to come aboard. So, what&amp;rsquo;s this all about?
Core team and Addons team hiring! Developers at PrestaShop can thrive in two departments: the Core team and the Addons team.
The Core developers work on the future of the PrestaShop software. Addons developers focus on building additional modules sold on our marketplace, and improving the Addons platform.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
