<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>l10n on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/l10n/</link>
    <description>Recent content in l10n on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 09:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/l10n/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do You Speak PrestaShop? – March 2023 Edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-march-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-march-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in March.
Project news 🎤 Contributor interviews are back! You’ve read that right – contributor interviews are back! The first interview sheds light on PrestaShop ambassador, merchant and contributor AmirRzd, who’s been contributing to the translation project for nearly 8 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – February 2023 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/2023-03-02-do-you-speak-prestashop-february-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/2023-03-02-do-you-speak-prestashop-february-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in February!
Project news 🌐 The top translators page is back up After a short interruption due to a bug, the top translators page is now back up and running! This is where you&amp;rsquo;ll find the top contributors of the translation project, sorted by translated words as well as the progress of every language and fully translated languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – January 2023 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-january-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-january-2023/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in January!
Project news ➕ A new language is available for translation! Thanks to Ali Zhumagaliev, the Karakalpak language is now available for translation on the Crowdin project!
💕 Many thanks to January’s newcomers Many people subscribe to the project(s) of their choice each month, but not so many start translating straight away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – December 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-december-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2023/do-you-speak-prestashop-december-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in December!
Project news ➕ The PrestaShop project 2022 retrospective 🎉 2023 is here, happy new year! Thank you all for your contributions. With the help of every single one of you, PrestaShop 8.0 was released on October 26, 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – November 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-november-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-november-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the software translations evolved in November!
Project news ➕ Our translation guide is now available 🎉 Christmas draws near. We teased our little gift last month and it is finally here (drumrolls): the translation guide to PrestaShop software is now available. The guide has everything you need to get started or dig deeper into the Crowdin project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – October 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-october-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in October!
Project news ➕ PrestaShop 8 is now available to the world 🎉 PrestaShop 8 is here! While it’s been translated into multiple languages already (thank you all for your contributions!), new translation strings are added regularly, so keep an eye out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – September 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-september-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-september-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in September!
Project news ➕ PrestaShop 8 strings are ready for translation PrestaShop 8 is just around the corner! The new strings are still available for translation. You are more than welcome to help contribute to the project and bring PrestaShop 8 to the world!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – August 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-august-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-august-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in August!
Project news ➕ PrestaShop 8 is ready for translation PrestaShop 8 is on its way! While it brings new features, this new version also means new strings. A file containing all PrestaShop 8 strings has been pushed to Crowdin, and is ready for translation!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – July 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-july-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-july-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in July!
Project news 💕 Many thanks to newcomers Many people subscribe to the project(s) of their choice each month, but not so many start translating straight away. For that reason, we would like to thank Francisco GP who rushed into the efforts immediately!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – June 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-june-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-june-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in June!
Project news 💕 Many thanks to newcomers Many people subscribe to the project(s) of their choice each month, but not so many start translating straight away. For that reason, we would like to thank Michał Boruta and joeurassa , who rushed into the efforts immediately!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – May 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-may-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-may-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in May!
Project news 💕 Many thanks to newcomers Many people subscribe to the project(s) of their choice each month, but not so many start translating straight away. For that reason, we would like to thank teratux, who rushed into the efforts immediately!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – April 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-april-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-april-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in April!
Project news ➕ New strings were added to Crowdin to fix a bug As you may have noticed, 42 new strings were added to Crowdin on May 6. It is usually not possible to add new strings outside the release of a minor or major version of PrestaShop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – March 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-march-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-march-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in March!
Project news 💬 Contributor interviews Have you ever wondered who was hiding behind a GitHub or a Crowdin username? Contributor interviews are a great way of getting to know the people who participate in the PrestaShop project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – February 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-february-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-february-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in February!
Project news Your pictures of the reward program Between September and December 2021, Mahmoud Parvazi has translated 3,306 words. This allowed him to level up, from the Traveller to the Backpacker level, and enter the reward program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you speak PrestaShop? – January 2022 edition</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-january-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/do-you-speak-prestashop-january-2022/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to PrestaShop is not only about the code, it is also about taking part in the PrestaShop translation project! This report will tell you how the translations of the software evolved in January!
Project news Top contributors, watch your mailbox! 📫 On January 18, the packages were sent to our top translators, as part of the translator reward program. So if you are concerned, watch your mailbox and remember to send a picture to translation@prestashop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
