<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>major on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/major/</link>
    <description>Recent content in major on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/tag/major/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0 Is Available</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-0-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-0-available/</guid>
      <description>The maintainers team is pleased to announce that PrestaShop 8.0 is officially available.
PrestaShop 8, the first major version since the original release of PrestaShop 1.7.0 back in 2016, is an important milestone for the project.
A significant cleanup has been performed in the codebase, with several internal components updated, modified or removed. PrestaShop 8 is also the project’s first company-neutral release, meaning that it no longer includes commercial products and services built-in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0 Release Candidate Is Ready To Be Tested!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-rc1-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-rc1-release/</guid>
      <description>The maintainers team is pleased to announce the first release candidate of PrestaShop 8.0.
This is the last step before releasing the final 8.0 version. This release candidate is intended to allow the community to verify that all regressions found during the beta have been fixed and that the software is ready for production. If no major or critical regression is reported before October 20th, then the final version of 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate your solutions from PrestaShop 1.7 to 8.0</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/migrate-your-solutions-from-17-to-80/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/migrate-your-solutions-from-17-to-80/</guid>
      <description>PrestaShop 8 beta version was released last week. If you are a developer in our ecosystem, create modules or themes, and have clients working with PrestaShop, this is an excellent opportunity to spend some time with this version and test your solutions.
In this article, I will focus on things that might affect your work. You will read here about changes that are not backward compatible, and could require you to make changes in the code of your solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 8.0 beta is open for feedback!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-beta-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 15:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2022/prestashop-8-0-beta-release/</guid>
      <description>The public beta version of PrestaShop 8.0 is now ready for you to test!
The maintainers team is very happy to announce today the release of the public beta version of PrestaShop 8.0. This version includes many new features, improvements and over 130 bug fixes.
The main new features for this version include an update to Symfony 4.4, compatibility with PHP 8 and 8.1, an enhanced experimental product page, and a new security page which allows shop administrators to manage user sessions and configure their password policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 released!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-0-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 09:10:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-0-0-released/</guid>
      <description>Here it is! All singin&amp;rsquo; all dancin&amp;rsquo;: Prestashop 1.7.0.0 is ready for you to explore!
It&amp;rsquo;s been 495 days since the release of 1.6.1.0, the last major version of PrestaShop. And boy have we kept ourselves busy since then!
We are happy to finally release the start of a now path for PrestaShop: version 1.7.0.0 opens the way to a new way of selling, creating and developing with your favorite Open Source e-commerce platform!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here comes PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 alpha 4!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/here-comes-prestashop-1-7-alpha-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 02:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/here-comes-prestashop-1-7-alpha-4/</guid>
      <description>Three weeks ago we released PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 alpha 3. Since then, and with the help of the community, we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on it to fix the bugs you&amp;rsquo;ve reported and to keep improving this new version. We&amp;rsquo;re now releasing PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 alpha 4 version, so we can keep gathering feedback and make sure that the final and stable version will be the best it can be!
While this alpha version is not ready for production stores, it is a great basis for us to get your feedbacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 alpha 3 now!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-alpha-3-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 02:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2016/prestashop-1-7-alpha-3-is-here/</guid>
      <description>Here it is. After two internal alpha versions, we’re happy to present to you this public alpha release of PrestaShop 1.7.0.0 &amp;ndash; the first in a series of public alpha/beta/RC versions that we intend to release over several weeks, in order to gather feedback and make sure that the final and stable version is the best it can be!
Here is your chance to dive into what’s coming in 1.7:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PrestaShop 1.6.1.0 released!</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/1-6-1-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 18:54:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2015/1-6-1-0-released/</guid>
      <description>Here it is!
119 days after the release of PrestaShop 1.6.0.14, and with 1,247 files changed, 57,118 lines of code added and 26,083 deleted, we are happy to release version 1.6.1.0 of PrestaShop.
This version is the first step of many new cool things for the PrestaShop project, of which you will start seeing the results in the coming versions: the adoption of a SemVer-like versioning scheme, the switch to PSR-2 and the move to PHP 5.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
