<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MarionFrancois on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</title>
    <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/MarionFrancois/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MarionFrancois on PrestaShop Developers&#39; blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://build.prestashop-project.org/authors/MarionFrancois/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Multistore feature in PrestaShop 1.7.8: What&#39;s new?</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/multistore-news-in-1.7.8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/multistore-news-in-1.7.8/</guid>
      <description>With the release of the new version 1.7.8 which is in progress, this article details one of the main features revamps of this version: the multistore.
The multistore feature allows merchants to manage several front offices through a single back office. It’s frequently used by merchants who sell in different countries and therefore have different languages and/or currencies. It is also used by merchants who do both B2B and B2C. And it is more rarely used by merchants who have several brands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results of community survey – April 2021</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/community-survey-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/community-survey-results/</guid>
      <description>The core product team carried out a survey in April, concerning the open source project and the community. The goal of this survey was to better know and understand the pains and the wishes of the community about the open source project.
💕 Special thanks to the respondents We received 98 responses, which makes a completion rate of 28.6%, and wanted to thank everyone who participated in this survey. Your opinions are very important for us and we care a lot about your satisfaction!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community survey – April 2021</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/community-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2021/community-survey/</guid>
      <description>The core product team is currently carrying out a survey oriented around the open-source project for the community.
You are many to express yourself on Slack, on the forum, or on Github about your pains and your wishes about the open-source project.
A lot of issues and suggestions are reported to the project every week. The maintainer’s team&amp;rsquo;s resources are limited, and it’s not possible to integrate all feedbacks experienced by all users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a new bug severity classification</title>
      <link>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/severity-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 11:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://build.prestashop-project.org/news/2019/severity-classification/</guid>
      <description>According to the Information Technology Infrastructure Library (ITIL), a bug is an &amp;ldquo;event that is not part of the standard operation of a service and causes an unplanned interruption or decrease the quality of service&amp;rdquo;. And it is everybody’s job to chase them all!
At the PrestaShop Quality Assurance team (aka QA), we browse issues on GitHub all day long. As we go about doing that, we often come across messages from people who are annoyed about a bug taking a long time to be fixed, and saying &amp;ldquo;this is a major issue, why is it still not fixed?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
